[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
戴维·马兰：好的，这是CS50，这是第四周。
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50, and this is week four.
在过去的几周中，我们已经
And for the past several weeks, we've had
使用这种称为C的语言时，各种训练轮都会启动。
training wheels of sorts on, while using this language known as C.
那些训练轮已采用CS50库的形式。
And those training wheels have been in the form of the CS50 library.
当然，您可以通过选择并包含cs50.h来使用该库。
And you use this library, of course, by selecting and including cs50.h
在您的代码之上。
atop your code.
然后，如果您考虑[音频不清晰]的工作原理，
And then if you think about how [INAUDIBLE] works,
您已经通过破折号L CS50链接了代码。
you've been linking your code via dash L CS50.
到目前为止，所有这些操作都已经使用make自动化了。
But all of that has been automated for you up until now, using make.
今天，我们将从上周的重点过渡
Today, we'll transition from last week's focus
在算法上更多地关注机器
on algorithms to a little more focus on machines
在我们现在用来实现这些算法的机器上
and on the machines we now use to implement these algorithms all the more
当我们开始起飞这些训练轮时，功能强大
powerfully, as we begin to take off these training wheels
并查看计算机机箱内部到底发生了什么。
and look at what's really going on underneath the hood of your computer.
和C的某些方面一样复杂，
And as complicated as some aspects of C have been,
因为编程是新手，很可能适合您，
as new is programming may very well be to you,
意识到引擎盖下没有太多事情要做
realize that there's not all that much going on underneath the hood
我们需要了解的才能继续前进
that we need to understand to now move onward
并开始解决更有趣，更复杂，更多的问题
and start solving far more interesting and more sophisticated and more
好玩的问题。
fun problems.
我们只需要一些其他的构建基块。
We just need a few additional building blocks.
因此，今天，我们将首先通过重新学习计数方法来做到这一点。
And so today, we'll do this, first, by relearning how to count.
例如，在这里，我们将其称为计算机的内存。
Here, for instance, is what we'll call the computer's memory.
而且我们之前已经看过这个网格。
And we've seen this grid before.
而且我们可以对计算机内存中的所有字节进行编号。
And we can number recall all of the bytes in your computer's memory.
我们可以将此字节号称为0、1、2、3、4，一直到字节15。
We might call this byte number 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, all the way up to byte 15,
等等。
and so forth.
但是事实证明，当谈论计算机的记忆时，
But it turns out, when talking about computers' memories,
计算机以及计算机科学家和程序员
computers and computer scientists and programmers
实际上并不倾向于使用十进制。
actually don't tend to use decimal.
他们绝对不会在这样低的级别上使用二进制文件。
They definitely don't tend to use binary at that low level.
取而代之的是，他们倾向于出于常规目的而使用，
Instead, they tend to use, just for conventional sake,
称为十六进制的东西。
something called hexadecimal.
十六进制是一个不同的基本系统，
Hexadecimal is a different base system that,
而不是使用10位数或2位数，而是使用16。
instead of using 10 digits or 2 digits, uses 16 instead.
因此，计算机科学家在对事物进行编号时
And so a computer scientist, when numbering things
像计算机内存中的字节一样，仍会执行0、1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8、9。
like bytes in a computer memory, would still do 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
但是在那之后，与其继续使用小数点到10，
But after that, instead of going onward with decimal to, say, 10,
通常是11、12、13、14、15，
11, 12, 13, 14, 15, they instead, conventionally,
将开始使用几个字母。
would start using a few letters of the alphabet.
因此，以十六进制表示，这个不同的基本系统基础16
And so, in hexadecimal, this different base system base 16,
您仍然从0开始计数。
you start counting at 0 still.
您最多可以算到9。
You count up to and through 9.
但是当你想继续计数时，
But when you want to keep counting higher,
然后转到A，B，C，D，E和F。
you then go to A, B, C, D, E, and F.
这样做的好处是，在十六进制内（十六进制表示16）
And the upside of this is that, within hexadecimal-- and that hex implies 16--
您总共有16个个人数字，即0到9，以及现在的A到F。
you have 16 total individual digits, 0 through 9, and also now, A through F.
因此，我们不必引入第二位数字就可以计算出最高为16的数字。
So we don't have to introduce second digits just to count up as high as 16.
我们可以使用0到F的单个数字。
We can use individual digits 0 through F.
而且我们可以通过使用多个十六进制数字来进一步计数。
And we can keep counting up further by using multiple hexadecimal digits.
但是要到达那里，让我们介绍一下这个词汇。
But to get there, let's introduce this vocabulary.
因此，在二进制中，我们当然使用0和1。
So in binary, of course, we use 0's and 1's.
当然，在十进制中，我们使用0到9。
In decimal, of course, we use 0 through 9's.
而且要明确一点，在十六进制中，我们将使用0到F之间的值，否则
And in hexadecimal, to be clear, we're going to use 0 through F's, otherwise
被称为基础16。
known as base-16.
这只是我们使用A到F的约定。
And it's just a convention that we use A through F. We
本可以使用其他六个符号。
could have used any other six symbols.
但是，这些都是人类选择的。
But these are what humans have chosen.
因此，十六进制的工作原理与我们熟悉的十进制非常相似。
So hexadecimal works quite similarly to our familiar decimal system.
现在，您对二进制系统的了解甚至还很熟悉，如下所示。
And it's even familiar to, now, what you know as the binary system, as follows.
让我们考虑使用十六进制而不是十进制的两位数值
Let's consider a two-digit value using hexadecimal instead of decimal
而不是二进制。
and instead of binary.
好吧，就像在十进制世界中一样，我们以10为底，
Well, just like in the world of decimal, we used base-10,
或在二进制世界中，我们使用了base-2。
or in the world of binary, we used base-2.
现在，我们将使用base-16，ergo，十六进制。
We're just going to use, now, base-16, ergo, hexadecimal.
因此，这是第16个。
So this is 16 to the first.
这是16-
This is 16 to the--
对不起16到0。
sorry 16 to the 0.
这是16到第一个。
This is 16 to the first.
当然，如果我们将其相乘，那只是一列
And of course, if we multiply that out, it's just the ones column
现在是16列。
and now the 16's column.
因此，如果您想以十六进制进行计数，
And so if you want to count up in hexadecimal,
您仍然照常从0开始，然后是01、02、03、04、05、06、07、08、09。
you still start with 0 as usual, then 01, 02, 03, 04, 05, 06, 07, 08, 09.
然后事情变得有趣了。
And then things get interesting.
现在，您无需转到01，因为那是不正确的。
Now, you don't go to 01, because that would be incorrect.
在这个基本系统中，01等于16乘以1加1乘以0。
01, in this base system, would be like 16 times 1 plus 1 times 0.
那不是我们想要的。
That's not what we want.
在我们知道的数字是9之后，我们现在可以算出A，B，C，D，E，F。
After the number we know is 9, we now count up to A, B, C, D, E, F.
现在，事情又变得有趣了。
And now, things get interesting again.
但是就像在十进制系统中一样，当您计数到99时，
But just like in the decimal system, when you count up to, like, 99,
您必须在这里开始携带1，同样的东西。
you have to start carrying the 1, same thing here.
如果要计数过去的F，请携带1。
If you want to count past F, you carry the 1.
现在，为了表示一个大于F的值，我们使用01，
And so now, to represent one value greater than F, we use 01,
看起来像10，但不是10。
which looks like 10, but is not 10.
十六进制为01。
In hexadecimal, it is 01.
16乘以1给我们16。
16 times 1 gives us 16.
1乘以0得出0。
1 times 0 gives us 0.
当然，这使我们现在知道的十进制数为16。
And of course, that gives us the decimal number we now know is 16.
因此，我们将不再引入越来越多的基本系统。
So we will no longer introduce more and more base systems.
但是让我规定，仅通过使用这些列即可
But let me stipulate that just by using these columns
你在小学时学到的，大概是
that you learned back in grade school, presumably,
您现在可以实现任何基本系统吗？
can you implement any base system now.
碰巧的是，在计算机世界中，
It just so happens that in the world of computers,
如今在内存世界中，很快还有文件，
and today in the world of memory, and soon, also files,
这将是非常传统的
it's just going to be very conventional to be
能够识别和使用十六进制。
able to recognize and use hexadecimal.
实际上，人类有一个理由喜欢十六进制，
And in fact, there's a reason humans like hexadecimal,
或至少有人。
or at least some humans.
计算机科学家回忆说，在这种情况下，如果我们将FF计数为高，
Computer scientists recall that if we count up as high as FF, in this case,
我们仍然会做同样的数学。
we would still do the same math.
所以16乘15加1乘15将给我们，真的，
So 16 times 15 plus 1 times 15 is going to give us, really, this,
或者是240加15或255。
or of course, 240 plus 15, or 255.
我很快就做了。
And I did that pretty quickly.
但这只是小学数学相乘的一种
But that's just the sort of grade school math of multiplying
列中的值，再一次，
the column by the value that's in it, where again,
这些F中的每一个就是我们现在使用一位数字表示15的方式。
each of these F's is how we now express 15 using a single digit.
但是回想一下，我们之前看过255个。
But recall that we've seen 255 before.
几周前，当我们谈论二进制文件时，
Back when we talked about binary a few weeks ago,
255恰好也是我们在这里看到的模式，使用二进制的8个1位。
255 also happened to be the pattern that we see here, eight 1 bits using binary.
因此，计算机科学家倾向于使用十六进制的原因
And so the reason that computer scientists tend to hexadecimal,
是的，你知道在八位中，实际上
is that, you know what, in eight bits, there's actually
这里有两对，左边是四对，右边是四对。
two pairs here, like four on the left, four on the right.
如果我们把这些东西整理一下，那
If we sort of scooch these things over, it
事实证明，因为十六进制允许
turns out that because hexadecimal allows
您代表16个可能的值，这是
you to represent 16 possible values, it's
一次代表四个位的完美系统。
a perfect system for representing four bits at a time.
毕竟，如果这里有四个位，每个位可以是0或1，
After all, if you've got four bits here, each of which can be a 0 or 1,
分别是2乘2乘2乘2的可能值，
that's 2 times 2 times 2 times 2 possible values for each of those,
或16个总值，也就是说，在计算机世界中，
or 16 total values, which is to say that in the world of computers,
如果您想以四位为单位说话，
if you ever want to talk in units of four bits,
改用十六进制非常方便，
it's wonderfully convenient to use hexadecimal instead,
只是因为方便地，一个十六进制数字恰好是
only because, conveniently, one hexadecimal digit happens to be
等效于四个二进制数字，0和1。
equivalent to four binary digits, 0's and 1's.
所以0，0，0，0一直到1，1，1，1。
So 0, 0, 0, 0, all the way up through 1, 1, 1, 1.
那么为什么人类要这样做呢？
So why do humans do this?
正是由于这种便利，这才是人类的惯例。
It's just now the human convention because of that convenience.
现在，你们中的某些人可能很早以前就看到过十六进制。
Now, some of you may very well have seen hexadecimal before.
实际上，回想一下我们在RGB第0周的讨论，
In fact, recall our discussion in week 0 of RGB,
我们讨论了使用
where we discussed the representation of colors using
一定数量的红色，绿色和蓝色。
some amount of red, green, and blue.
当时，我们使用了这个示例。
And at the time, we used this example.
我们从上下文中拿出了我们的例子。
We took our example out of context.
而不是使用hi作为文本字符串，
And instead of using hi as a string of text,
我们将72、73和33重新解释为一系列颜色。
we reinterpreted 72, 73, and 33 as a sequence of colors.
你要多少红色？
How much red do you want?
您要多少绿色？
How much green do you want?
你想要多少蓝色？
How much blue do you want?
很好。
And that's fine.
用小数表示和表达自己的观点是非常好的。
It's perfectly fine to think and express yourself in terms of decimal.
但是计算机科学家往往不会在色彩环境中那样做
But computer scientists tend not to do it that way in the context of colors
并在记忆的背景下。
and in the context of memory.
取而代之的是，他们倾向于使用一种称为十六进制的东西。
Instead, they tend to use something called hexadecimal.
在这里，十六进制实际上只是
And hexadecimal, here, would actually just
您是否将这些值从72、73、33更改为等效的十六进制
have you change these values from 72, 73, 33, to the equivalent hexadecimal
表示。
representation.
而且我们不会在这里进行数学运算。
And we won't bother doing the math here.
但我只规定十进制为72、73、33
But let me just stipulate that 72, 73, 33 in decimal
与十六进制的48、49、21相同。
is the same thing as 48, 49, 21 in hexadecimal.
现在，很明显，如果您看一下这三个数字，
Now, obviously, if you glance at these three numbers,
如果您要查看十六进制数字，这一点都不明显
it's not at all obvious if you're looking at hexadecimal digits
或十进制数字，因为它们确实使用相同的子集，即0到9。
or decimal digits, because they do use the same subset, 0's through 9's.
因此，在计算机世界中，惯例也是如此
And so a convention, too, in the computing world,
每当您代表十六进制数字时，
is any time you represent hexadecimal digits,
您通常会以0x作为前缀。
you tend to prefix them, just because, with 0x.
而且0或x没有数学意义。
And there's no mathematical meaning to the 0 or the x.
它只是您放置在此处以使观众清楚看到的前缀
It's just a prefix you put there to make clear to the viewer
即使它们可能是十六进制数字
that these are hexadecimal digits, even if they might otherwise
看起来像十进制数字。
look like decimal digits.
那么我们要去哪里呢？
So where are we going with this?
好吧，那些可能已经尝试过的人
Well, those of you who might have experimented
过去制作自己的网页并使它们色彩丰富，
in the past with making your own web pages and making them colorful,
或那些曾经使用过Photoshop等程序的艺术家
or those of you who are artists and have used programs like Photoshop, odds
是，您之前已经看过这些代码。
are, you've seen these codes before.
实际上，这里有一些Photoshop本身的屏幕截图。
In fact, here are a few screenshots of Photoshop itself.
如果您在Photoshop中单击一种颜色，然后打开此窗口，
If you click on a color in Photoshop and you pull up this window,
您可以更改屏幕上绘制的颜色
you can change the color that you're drawing on the screen
成为彩虹的任何颜色。
to be any of the colors of the rainbow.
但更不可思议的是，如果您低头看这里，
But more arcanely, if you look down here,
您实际上可以看到这些十六进制代码，
you can actually see these hexadecimal codes,
因为多年来已经成为人类的惯例
because it's become human convention over the years
使用十六进制表示不同数量的红色，绿色，
to use hexadecimal to represent different amounts of red, green,
和蓝色。
and blue.
因此，如果您没有红色，没有绿色，没有蓝色，否则表示为000000，
So if you have no red, no green, no blue, otherwise represented as 000000,
好吧，这将为您提供我们在这里称为黑色的颜色。
well, that's going to give you the color we know here as black.
那里没有任何波长的光。
It's sort of the absence of any wavelengths of light there.
相比之下，如果您将所有这六位数字都更改了
If by contrast, though, you change all of those six digits
到最大可能的值，再次是F。十六进制的范围0
to the highest possible value, which, again, is F. The range in hexadecimal 0
到F，否则为十进制，从0到15，好吧，
through F, otherwise in decimal, being 0 through 15, well,
FFFFFF就是很多红色，很多绿色，很多蓝色。
with FFFFFF, that's a lot of red, a lot of green, a lot of blue.
当您组合这些波长的光时，
And when you combine those wavelengths of light,
您会看到我们在这里看到的白色。
you get the color we see here as white.
您可以想像，现在，将不同数量的
And you can imagine, now, combining different amounts
红色，绿色或蓝色。
of red or green or blue.
因此，例如，十六进制FF0000是我们称为红色的颜色。
So for instance, in hexadecimal, FF0000, is the color we know as red.
00FF00是我们称为绿色的颜色。
00FF00 is the color we know as green.
最后，0000FF是我们称为蓝色的颜色，因为同样，
And finally, 0000FF is the color we know as blue, because again,
程序员和美工经常但不总是使用的系统确实是，
the system that programmers and artists often but don't always use, is indeed,
此RGB系统用于红色，绿色和蓝色。
this system of RGB for red, green, and blue.
所以我们在这里介绍这个不是因为你
So we introduced this here not because you
必须开始以不同的方式思考，因为再次，
have to start thinking any differently, because again,
数学机制与第0周相同。
the mathematical mechanism is the same as week 0.
但是您将开始在示例，程序中看到数字，
But you're going to start seeing numbers in examples, in programs,
只是按照惯例以十六进制显示，而不是
as just appearing in hexadecimal by convention, as opposed to actually
被解释为十进制。
being interpreted as decimal.
因此，如果现在考虑计算机的内存，
So if we consider, now, our computer's memory,
现在，我们将开始考虑整个内存范围，
we'll now start thinking of this whole canvas of memory,
所有这些字节都在我们计算机的内存中，
all of these bytes inside of our computer's memory,
一直到F都是无数的0、1、2。
as being innumerable as 0, 1, 2, all the way through F.
然后如果继续计数，我们可以转到10、11、12、13、14、15、16、17、18，
And then if we keep counting, we can go to 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18,
19、1A，1B，1C，1D等。
19, 1A, 1B, 1C, 1D, and so forth.
如果不是那么明显就很好，
And it's fine if it's not nearly that obvious,
当您查看这些内容时，十进制等效项是什么。
as you look at these things, what the decimal equivalents are.
那不是问题。
That's not a problem.
在这种情况下，这只是一种不同的思考位置的方式，
It's just a different way of thinking about the locations, in this case,
计算机内存或一种颜色或另一种颜色的表示形式。
of a computer's memory, or the representation of one color or another.
好吧，现在让我们以此为契机，
All right, well, let's now use this as an example of an opportunity,
而是考虑实际存储在我们计算机内存中的内容。
rather, to consider what's actually being stored in our computer's memory.
而且要明确的是，我将开始为所有这些内存地址添加前缀，
And to be clear, I'll start prefixing all of these memory addresses,
可以这么说，使用0x只是为了表明我们现在正在谈论
so to speak, with 0x, just to make clear that we're now talking, indeed,
以0和1表示。
in terms of 0's and 1's.
因此，这是一条简单的代码行。
So here's a simple line of code.
脱离上下文，我们实际上需要把这个
Out of context, we would need to, actually, put this
在主程序或其他程序中实际上可以执行任何操作。
in main or some other program to actually do anything with it.
但是我们现在已经看过很多次了
But we've seen this before many times, now,
在其中声明变量的位置，例如，n代表数字。
where you declare a variable, for instance, n for number.
声明它作为其类型的int。
Declare it as an int for its type.
然后，甚至可以为其分配一个值。
And then, perhaps, even assign it a value.
好吧，当我们在计算机中使用这种代码时，实际发生了什么？
Well, what's actually going on when we use this kind of code in our computer?
好吧，让我们继续前进，并在实际程序中鞭打一下。
Well, let's go ahead and whip this thing up in a actual program.
让我创建一个名为address.c的文件，因为我
Let me create a file called address.c because I
想开始尝试使用计算机内存中的某些地址。
want to start experimenting with some addresses in the computer's memory.
我将继续介绍标准io点h。
I'm going to go ahead and include standard io dot h.
我要给自己诠释主要的虚无。
I'm going to give myself int main void.
在这里，我将继续进行声明
And down here, I'm going to go ahead and declare exactly
该变量int n等于50。
that variable, int n equals 50.
然后我将继续打印并输出百分比i和反斜杠0，
And then I'm going to go ahead and print out, with percent i and a backslash 0,
n的值
the value of n.
因此，那里没有什么有趣的，也没有太复杂的。
So nothing interesting there, nothing too complicated.
我将继续致辞。
I'm going to go ahead and make address.
然后，我将继续执行点斜杠地址。
And then I'm going to go ahead and do dot slash address.
当然，就第一周而言，我们希望
And of course, as per week one, we should hopefully
只能看到数字50。
see just the number 50.
但是今天，我们将为您提供更多工具，使您可以实际使用
But today, we're going to give you some more tools with which you can actually
开始四处查看计算机的内存。
start poking around your computer's memory.
但首先让我们考虑一下这行代码
But let's first consider this line of code
在计算机硬件环境中。
in the context of your computer's hardware.
因此，如果您使用这样的代码编写程序，
So if you're writing a program with a line of code like this,
n必须位于计算机内存中的某个位置。
that n needs to be somewhere in your computer's memory.
那50个需要放在计算机内存中的某个位置。
That 50 needs to be put somewhere in your computer's memory.
因此，如果我们再次认为这只是我们计算机的一部分
So if we, again, consider this to be just part of our computer's
内存，几十个字节，假设那个变量n
memory, a few dozen bytes, well, suppose that that variable, n,
恰好在这里结束。
happens to end up down here.
我故意将n表示为占用四个字节，四个正方形，因为我们
I've deliberately drawn n as taking up four bytes, four squares, because we
至少在CS50 IDE和现代系统上通常都将其称为整数，
call that an integer, typically, at least on CS50 IDE and modern systems,
往往是四个字节。
tends to be four bytes.
因此，我确保将其填满四个完整的框。
So I made sure to have it fill four complete boxes.
然后可能实际存储在其中的值为50。
And then value might be 50 that's actually stored there.
好吧，事实证明，在您的计算机内存中，
Well, it turns out that within your computer's memory, again,
这些地址隐式存在。
there are these addresses that are implicitly there.
因此，即使可以，我们也可以引用此变量n
So even though, yes, we can refer to this variable, n,
根据我在代码中给它的变量名，
based on the variable name I gave it in my code,
当然，此变量存在于内存中的特定位置。
surely this variable exists at a specific location in memory.
我不知道它在哪里。
I don't know offhand where it is.
但让我建议也许是在位置0x12345678上，
But let me just propose that maybe it's at location 0x12345678, just
任意地址。
an arbitrary address.
实际上，我不知道它在哪里。
I have no idea, in actuality, where it is.
但它确实有地址，因为这些方块中的每个方块
But it certainly does have an address, because every one of these squares
计算机内存中有一个地址，一个唯一的标识符，例如0、1
inside of your computer's memory has an address, a unique identifier like 0, 1,
2，依此类推。
2, and so forth.
也许50结束于内存地址0x12345678。
Maybe the 50 ended up at memory address 0x12345678.
好吧，这对C来说很酷，因为我们实际上可以开始看到这一点，
Well, that's kind of cool about C, is that we can actually begin to see this,
无双关语。
no pun intended.
所以让我继续修改该程序
So let me go ahead and modify this program
并介绍一些新的语法
and introduce a little bit of new syntax that
将使我们能够开始在您的计算机内存中四处张望
will allow us to start poking around the inside of your computer's memory
这样我们就可以实际看到其下发生了什么。
so we can actually see what's going on underneath.
因此，我将继续更改该程序以代替执行此操作。
So I'm going to go ahead and change this program to do this instead.
我要说，你知道吗？
I'm going to go ahead and say, you know what?
不要只打印出值n，它当然是50。
Don't just print out the value, n, which, of course, is 50.
出于好奇，让我看看n的实际地址是多少。
Let me see, just out of curiosity, what is the actual address of n.
今天要做的是，我们将介绍一种新的语法，
And to do that today, we're going to introduce one new piece of syntax,
这恰好是这里。
which happens to be this here.
今天，在C中有两个新的运算符。第一个是＆符，
There's two new operators, today, in C. The first is an ampersand, which
不代表逻辑与。
does not represent a logical and.
回想一下几周前，我们确实发现，如果您
Recall a couple of weeks ago, we did see that if you
想要结合布尔表达式，this和that，您使用两个＆符。
want to combine Boolean expressions, this and that, you use two ampersands.
不幸的巧合是，这样的独奏“＆”号，
It's an unfortunate coincidence that an ampersand, solo like this,
今天的意义会有所不同。
will mean something different today.
具体来说，此“＆”号将成为我们操作员的地址。
Specifically, this ampersand is going to be our address of operator.
只要在任何变数名称前加上与号，就可以告诉C，
By simply prefixing any variable name with an ampersand, we can tell C,
请告诉我此变量存储在哪个地址。
please tell me what address this variable is stored in.
这颗星，不要与乘法相混淆，
And this star, not to be confused with multiplication,
在今天的背景下也具有另一种含义。
also has another meaning in today's context.
当您使用此星号时，您实际上可以
When you use this asterisk, you can actually
告诉您的程序在特定的内存地址中查找。
tell your program to look inside of a particular memory address.
因此，“＆”号会告诉您变量位于什么地址。
So the ampersand tells you what address a variable is at.
星号运算符，也称为解引用运算符，
The star operator, otherwise known as the dereference operator,
意思是，转到以下地址。
means, go to the following address.
因此，它们属于反向操作。
So they sort of are reverse operations.
一个人弄清楚地址。
One figures out the address.
一个去地址。
One goes to the address.
因此，让我们在这里真正看到它。
And so let's see this for real here.
让我继续并将此处的程序中的n更改为＆符。
Let me go ahead and change my n in my program here to ampersand n.
所以我想打印出的不是n中的数字，而是n的地址。
So I want to print out, not the number in n, but the address of n.
现在，如何打印地址？
And now, how do I print out an address?
好吧，这只是一个数字。
Well, it is just a number.
但实际上，printf支持地址的不同格式代码。
But actually, printf supports a different format code for addresses.
您可以执行百分比p，出于我们很快就会看到的原因，
You can do percent p, for reasons we'll soon see,
那说打印出这个变量的地址
that says to print out the address of this variable
并再次按照惯例将其解释为十六进制。
and interpret it as hexadecimal, again, by convention.
所以我现在继续做地址
So I'm going to go ahead and make address now
仅对该文件进行两次更改之后。
after only making two changes to this file.
一切似乎都可以编译。
Everything seems to compile OK.
现在，我要继续运行地址。
Now, I'm going to go ahead and run address.
我们将看到，在这个特定程序中，
And we will see that, in this particular program,
address.c，无论出于何种原因，该变量n
address.c, for whatever reason, that variable, n,
最终到达疯狂的位置0x7ffd80792f7c。
ended up at crazy location 0x7ffd80792f7c.
现在，这有用吗？
Now, is that useful?
不一定是实际中的。
Not in practice, necessarily.
我们将通过利用这些地址来使其变得有用。
We're going to make this become useful by leveraging these addresses.
但是具体地址并不有趣。
But the specific address is not interesting.
我瞥了一眼这个数字。
I'm glancing at this number.
我不知道那个数字是十进制。
I have no idea what that number is in decimal.
我得算一下，或者坦率地说，只是谷歌一个转换器
I would have to do the math, or frankly, just Google a converter
为我做
and do it for me.
再说一遍，这不是有趣的部分。
So again, that's not the interesting part.
这是十六进制的事实只是一个实现细节。
The fact that this is in hexadecimal is just an implementation detail.
它恰好代表此变量的位置。
It happens to represent the location of this variable.
再说一次，我们不一定要这样做。
And again, we won't want to do this, necessarily.
但是要明确一点，这些运算符之一
But just to be clear that one of these operators,
“＆”号获取地址。
the ampersand gets the address.
然后星级经营者去一个地址。
And the star operator goes to an address.
实际上，我们可以消除这些影响。
We can actually undo the effects of these things.
举例来说，如果我现在打印出来的不是“＆”号，而是出于好奇，
For instance, if I print out now, not ampersand n, but just out of curiosity,
星号＆符，我可以消除此运算符的影响。
star ampersand n, I can kind of undo the effects of this operator.
“＆”号要说的是，n的地址是什么？
Ampersand n is going to say, what is the address of n?
星号“＆”号要说的是，去那个地址。
Star ampersand n is going to say, go to that address.
所以这是没有意义的练习，因为如果我只想要n中的值，
So this is kind of a pointless exercise, because if I just want what's in n,
很显然，我可以像我们开始那样打印n。
I can just, obviously, print n like we began.
但是同样，作为一项智力练习，
But again, just as an intellectual exercise,
如果我在n前面加上运算符的地址，然后使用星号
if I prefix n with the address of operator, and then use the asterisk
说，去那个地址，是一样的东西
and say, go to that address, it's the same exact thing
就像打印n本身一样。
as just printing n itself.
因此，让我将格式代码改回整数。
So let me change the format code back to an integer.
取而代之的是百分比p，让我继续进行发言，
Instead percent p, let me go ahead and make address now,
似乎编译OK，并运行地址。
seems to compile OK, and run address.
瞧，我们又回到了50岁。
And voila, we're back at the 50.
因此，就像今天的语法可能会令人感到奇怪一样，
So as weird as the syntax today might start to feel,
意识到这些运营商在一天结束时，
realize that these operators, at the end of the day,
他们的工作相对简单。
are relatively simple in what they do.
而且，如果您了解一种只是抵消了另一种的影响，
And if you understand that one just kind of undoes the effects of the other,
我们可以开始与他们建立一些非常有趣的程序吗？
can we start to build up some pretty interesting programs with them.
我们将通过利用一种特殊类型的变量来做到这一点，
And we're going to do so by leveraging a special type of variable,
一个称为指针的变量。
a variable called a pointer.
并且存在以百分比p表示的p。
And there is that p in percent p.
指针是一个包含其他值的地址的变量。
A pointer is a variable that contains the address of some other value.
因此，我们之前已经看过整数。
So we've seen integers before.
我们也见过浮点数，字符，字符串和其他类型。
We've seen floats and chars and strings and other types as well.
现在，指针只是变量的另一种类型
Pointers, now, are just a different type of variable
存储一些值的地址。
that store the address of some value.
您可以使用指向整数的指针，指向chars的指针，指向bool的指针，
And you can have pointers to integers, pointers to chars, pointers to bools,
或任何其他数据类型。
or any other data type.
指针引用值的特定类型
A pointer references the specific type of the value
它实际上指的是。
that it actually is referring to.
因此，让我们更具体地看一下。
So let's see this more concretely.
现在，让我回到这里的程序。
Let me go back, now, to my program here.
让我在这里介绍另一个变量。
And let me introduce another variable here.
让我继续打印，而不是立即打印出类似n的内容
Instead of immediately printing out something like n, let me go ahead
并引入第二个类型为int star的变量。
and introduce a second variable that is of type int star.
我承认，这可能是最令人困惑的C语法
And this, I will admit, is probably the most confusing piece of C syntax
我们通常会看到，只是因为，我的天，星现在
that we'll, in general, see, just because, my god, star is now
用于乘法，去地址，以及现在
used for multiplication, for going to an address, and also, now,
声明一个变量。
declaring a variable.
可以说，这不是最佳的设计决策。
This is, arguably, not the best design decision.
但是它是几十年前制成的。
But it was made decades ago.
这就是我们所拥有的。
So this is what we have.
但是，如果我做int star p等于和号n，那么我现在可以做些什么，
But if I do int star p equals ampersand n, now, what I can do down here,
通过将n的地址临时存储在变量中来打印出n的地址。
is print out the address of n by temporarily storing it in a variable.
所以我现在还没有做任何新的事情。
So I'm not doing anything new just yet.
我仍在第5行声明一个整数
I'm still declaring on line 5, an integer
称为n，分配值为50。
called n, assigning at the value 50.
现在第6行的新功能是，我正在引入一种新型的变量。
What's new now on line 6, is that I'm introducing a new type of variable.
这种类型的变量称为指针。
This type of variable is known as a pointer.
同样，指针只是一个存储某个值的地址的变量。
A pointer, again, is just a variable that stores the address of some value.
而且，语法很奇怪，它声明了一个指向整数的指针，
And the syntax, admittedly weird, for declaring a pointer to an integer,
字面意思是int，因为这就是您要指向的类型，
is literally say int, because that's the type you're pointing to,
星号，然后是您要创建的变量的名称。
star, and then the name of the variable you want to create.
我可以称呼它为任何东西，但为了保持简洁，我将其称为p。
And I could call this anything, but I'll call it p to keep it succinct.
再一次，在等号的右侧
And again, on the right hand side of the equals sign
与以前的运算符相同。
is the same operator as before.
如果要弄清楚n的地址是什么，它就是＆符号。
If you want to figure out what is the address of n, it's just ampersand n.
因此，我们现在可以将该地址长期存储。
And so we can store that address, now, somewhere longer-term.
以前，我只是传入＆符n，而printf就是这样。
Before, I just passed in ampersand n and printf did it's thing.
现在，我暂时在第6行上，将该地址存储在一个新变量中
Now, I'm temporarily, on line 6, storing that address in a new variable
称为p。
called p.
从技术上讲，它的类型是int star，这是程序员可能会说的。
And its type is technically int star, is what a programmer might say.
因此，说int p等于“＆”号是不正确的。
So it would be incorrect to say int p equals ampersand n.
确实，我们的编译器Clang不会那样。
And indeed, our compiler, Clang, won't like that.
它很可能不会让您编译代码。
It won't let you compile the code, most likely.
因此，相反，我做int star p来表明我知道自己在做什么。
And so, instead, I do int star p to make clear that I know what I'm doing.
我说的是存储一个int的地址，而不是一个整数。
I am storing the address of an int, not an integer, per say.
因此，如果我现在继续保存，请使用make地址重新编译。
So if I go ahead, now, and save this, recompile with make address.
请注意，我之前更改了代码2的一行。
And notice, I changed one line of code 2 earlier.
我回到百分比p打印一个指针，该指针是一个地址。
I went back to percent p to print a pointer that is an address.
我指出的是p的值，不再是n的值。
And I'm pointing out the value of p, no longer the value of n.
如果我现在运行点斜杠地址，瞧，那是个隐秘的地址。
If I now run dot slash address, voila, there's that cryptic address.
这些地址很可能会随着时间而改变。
And these addresses may very well change over time.
根据程序内部发生的情况
Depending on what's going on inside of your program
或系统上的其他内容，这些地址每次都可能不同。
or other things on the system, these addresses might be different each time.
这是可以预料的，而不是要依赖的东西。
And that's to be expected and not something to be relied on.
但这显然是一些随机的秘密地址，
But it's clearly some random cryptic address,
类似于我之前的任意0x12345678。
similar to my arbitrary 0x12345678 before.
但是现在，让我们撤消此操作。
But now, let's just undo this operation.
为了让我们可以围成一圈，现在让我提出建议
Just so we can come full circle here, let me now propose
我如何打印n的值。
how I can print out the value of n.
如果可以的话，让我请一个人这样做。
And let me call on someone for this if I can.
如果我现在的目标是在第7行，不再打印n的地址，而是打印
If my goal, now, on line 7, is no longer to print the address of n, but to print
n本身使用p。
n itself using p.
我将继续前进，先发制人，
I'm going to go ahead and change, preemptively,
格式代码为百分比i。
the format code to percent i.
显然，速记符号只是print n。
And a shorthand notation would, obviously, be just print n.
但是假设我不想为此打印n
But suppose I don't want to print n for this
练习中，我现在如何通过使用p引用n中的值来打印它？
exercise, how can I now print the value in n by referring to it by way of p?
我应该从字面上键入什么作为printf的第二个参数
What should I literally type as printf's second argument
通过某种方式使用此新变量p打印n的值。
to print out the value of n by using this new variable, p, in some way.
是的，让我们拜访约书亚。
Yeah, let's call on Joshua.
听众：我相信，如果您在p之前使用＆号，
AUDIENCE: I believe, if you use the ampersand before the p,
它可能会做到。
it will probably do it.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，“＆”号，让我继续尝试。
DAVID MALAN: OK, ampersand p, let me go ahead and try that.
让我们尝试使用＆符号打印出该值。
Let's try ampersand p to print out this value.
所以＆符p，我要保存文件。
So ampersand p, I'm going to save the file.
我要做地址并输入。
I'm going to do make address and enter.
事实并非如此。
And it doesn't seem to be the case.
请注意，我遇到了错误。
Notice that I'm getting an error.
这有点神秘。
It's a little cryptic.
格式指定类型为int，但参数的类型为int star star，
Format specifies type int, but the argument has type int star star,
再来一次。
more on that another time.
因此，事实证明这是不正确的。
So it turns out this was incorrect.
我们再提出一个建议，因为“＆”号，回想号，
Let's take one other suggestion, because the ampersand, recall,
获取某物的地址。
gets the address of something.
但是p已经是一个地址。
But p is already an address.
因此，约书亚，您的技术建议是，
So Joshua, what you technically proposed,
是给我地址的地址。
was get me the address of the address.
那不是我们想要走的方向。
And that's not the direction we want to go.
我们想去那个地址。
We want to go to what is at that address.
索菲娅，你觉得呢？
Sophia, what do you think?
观众：我们想增加一个百分比-
AUDIENCE: We want to add a percent--
或在打印时加上星号p。
or a star p when we print it.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
所以听到你有点麻烦。
So I had a little trouble hearing you.
但是我认为如果我们不使用＆运算符，
But I think if we instead use not the ampersand operator,
但是明星经营者，
but the star operator, that's going to be,
实际上，解引用运算符从本质上讲意味着
indeed, the dereference operator, which essentially means,
转到p中的值。
go to the value in p.
而且，如果p中的值是一个地址，我想，让我们尝试一下，创建地址。
And if the value in p is an address, I think, let's try this, make address.
是的，这次编译还可以。
Yep, that compiled OK this time.
现在，如果我做点斜杠地址，希望我
Now, if I do dot slash address, hopefully, I
现在，的确会看到数字50。
will now see, indeed, the number 50.
再一次，我们似乎没有取得任何根本进展。
So again, we don't seem to have made any fundamental progress.
归根结底，我仍然只打印n的值。
At the end of the day, I'm still just printing out the value of n.
但是我们已经介绍了这个新的原语，这个新的拼图，
But we've introduced this new primitive, this new puzzle piece,
如果可以的话，这允许您以编程方式
if you will, that allows you, programmatically,
找出计算机内存中某物的地址
to figure out the address of something in the computer's memory
并实际去那个地址。
and to actually go to that address.
而且我们很快就会看到对其进行更复杂的控制。
And we'll soon see exercise more sophisticated control over it as well.
但是，让我们回到此的图形表示
But let's come back to a pictorial representation of this
并考虑一下我们现在在这段代码的上下文中所做的事情。
and consider what it is we just did in the context, now, of this code.
因此，在我的主代码中，有两行有趣的代码，
So inside of my main, the two interesting lines of code,
真的，在我们添加Sophia之前，这两行是第一行吗？
really, were these two lines first before we made Sophia's addition
并实际上取消了对p的引用，并使用printf将其打印出来。
and actually dereferenced p and printed it out with printf.
但是，让我们暂时考虑一下这些值是什么
But let's consider, for a moment, what these values now
看起来就像在计算机的内存中。
look like in a computer's memory.
再说一次，语法有点神秘
And again, the syntax is a little cryptic
因为我们现在有了一颗星星和一个“＆”号。
because we now have a star and an ampersand.
但是，这再次意味着，现在，我们开始思考
But again, that just means, now, we get to start thinking
就计算机的内存而言。
in terms of the computer's memory.
例如，这是我计算机内部的内存网格。
So for instance, here's a grid of memory inside of my computer.
也许，例如，50和n最终落在那儿。
And maybe, for instance, the 50 and the n end up down there.
它们可能会出现在任何地方，甚至无法在此处显示在屏幕上。
They could end up anywhere, not even pictured on the screen here.
就目前的目的而言，它们最终位于计算机内存中的某个位置。
They end up somewhere in the computer's memory, for our purposes thus far.
但从技术上讲，它住在一个地址中。
But it technically lives in an address.
让我简化一下地址，以便说得更快。
And let me simplify the address just so it's quicker to say.
现在，这50个存储在变量n中，也许实际上
This 50, now, stored in the variable n, maybe it actually
住在地址0x123。
lives at address 0x123.
我不知道它在哪里，但我们显然
I have no idea where it is, but we've clearly
看到它可以住在这样一个看似随机的地址中。
seen that it can live in a seemingly random address like that.
现在，p呢？
Now, what about p?
从技术上讲，p本身就是一个变量。
p is technically a variable itself.
这是一个存储其他地址的变量。
It's a variable that stores the address of something else.
但这仍然是一个变量，这意味着当您声明p时
But it's still a variable, which means, when you declare p
在前面的代码中，它实际上确实占用了一些字节的内存
with the code earlier, it actually does take up some bytes of memory
屏幕上。
on the screen.
因此，让我继续前进，建议p恰好在这里存储在内存中。
And so let me go ahead and propose that p happens to end up in memory here.
现在，故意将p画得更长一些。
Now, p is deliberately drawn to be longer here.
这次我总共消耗了八个字节，
I'm consuming eight total bytes this time,
因为事实证明，在包括CS50 IDE在内的现代计算机系统上，
because it turns out, on modern computer systems, including CS50 IDE,
指针往往占用八个字节。
pointers tend to take up eight bytes.
因此，不是一个字节，不是四个字节，而是八个字节，所以我只是简单地将其绘制成更大的字节。
So not one, not four, but eight bytes, so I've simply drawn it to be bigger.
那么，实际上存储在变量p中的是什么？
So what is actually stored in the variable p?
好吧，事实证明，它只是存储了一些值的地址。
Well, it turns out that, again, it's just storing the address of some value.
因此，如果本身存储50的整数n位于位置0x123，
So if the integer n, which itself is storing 50, is at location 0x123,
并为指针p分配了该地址，就像在说，
and pointer p is being assigned that address, it's just like saying,
好吧，存储在此变量p中，实际上只是一个数字
well, stored in this variable p, is literally just a number
此处以十六进制表示形式0x123表示。
represented here in hexadecimal notation, 0x123.
这就是计算机内存中所有要做的事情
So that's all that's going on inside the computer's memory
这两行代码。
with those two lines of code.
除了事实，根本没有什么新的
There's nothing fundamentally new, except the fact
我们有新的语法可用来显式地引用这些地址。
that we have new syntax with which to refer to these addresses explicitly.
这里是n。
This is n down here.
这是这里。
This is p up here.
p的值恰好是一个地址。
And the value of p just happens to be an address.
现在，我一直说这些地址有点神秘。
Now, I keep saying that these addresses are a little cryptic.
他们有些武断。
They're a little arbitrary.
他们是。
And they are.
老实说，很少有启发性的了解，
And honestly, it is rarely, if ever, going to be enlightening to know,
作为人类，该整数n实际位于什么地址。
as a human, what address this integer n is actually at.
谁在乎它是0x123还是0x456？
Who cares if it's at 0x123 or 0x456?
通常，我们不这样做。
Generally, we don't.
因此，计算机科学家在谈论计算机的内存时，
And so computer scientists, when talking about computers' memory,
就实际数字而言，倾向于不谈论这些低层次的细节。 ，
tend not to talk at these low level details, in terms of actual numbers. ,
相反，他们倾向于简化图片，
Instead, they tend to simplify the picture,
有点抽象所有其他内存，坦率地说，不是
sort of abstract away all of the other memory, which frankly, is not
与到目前为止的讨论有关，并且只是
relevant to the discussion thus far, and just
说，你知道吗，我知道p正在存储一个地址。
say, you know what, I know that p is storing an address.
该地址恰好是这里的50。
And that address happens to be that of 50 down here.
但是我真的不在乎我的日常编程生活中，
But I really don't care, in my everyday programming life,
这些特定的地址是什么。
what these specific addresses are.
那你知道吗？
So you know what?
让我们将其抽象为箭头。
Let's just abstract it away as an arrow.
同样，抽象就是简化底层细节
And again, abstraction is all about simplifying lower level details
您可能非常需要了解，但不一定
that you may very well need to understand but you don't necessarily
需要继续思考。
need to keep thinking about.
您无需在这个级别上继续思考。
You don't need to keep thinking at this level.
在这个级别上思考就足够了。
It suffices to think at this level.
因此，我们不妨以图形方式绘制一个指针，
So we might as well draw a pointer, pictorially,
指着一些价值，而不管什么
as pointing at some value and irrespective of what
实际地址是。
the actual address is.
因此，在我们人类世界中，情况就是如此。
And so this is very much the case in our human world.
无论是否，我们都有非常相似的约定
We have very similar conventions whether or not
乍一看可能很明显，例如
it might be obvious at first glance, such
我们很可能会在日常生活中使用这些相同的机制。
that we may very well be using these same mechanisms in our everyday lives.
举例来说，如果您家中的街道上碰巧有一个邮箱
So for instance, if you happen to have a mailbox out in the street on your home
或在校园里的哈佛科学中心地下室
or down in the basement of Harvard Science Center when on campus, it
至少在住宅上可能看起来像这样。
may very well look like something like this, at least more residentially.
并假设在此情况下，此邮箱代表p，
And suppose that this mailbox here is representing, in this case, p,
在故事里。
in the story.
它存储一个指针，即其他内容的地址。
It's storing a pointer, that is, the address of something else.
好吧，如果街上还有很多其他邮箱，
Well, if there's a whole bunch of other mailboxes on the street,
好吧，我们可以在这些邮箱中放入所需的任何内容。
well, we can put anything we want in these mailboxes.
我们甚至可以放明信片，信件，包裹。
We can put postcards, letters, packages even.
就像在现实世界中一样，我们可以在虚拟环境中做同样的事情。
And just as in the real world, can we do the same in the virtual.
我可以存储字符或整数或其他东西，包括地址。
I can store chars or integers or other things, including addresses.
例如，布莱恩，我想您在其他地方拥有自己的邮箱。
So for instance, Brian, I think you have your own mailbox somewhere else.
当然，布莱恩（Brian）拥有一个邮箱，该邮箱本身具有唯一的地址。
And Brian, of course, has a mailbox that itself has a unique address.
例如，布莱恩（Brian），恰好是唯一地址
So Brian, for instance, what happens to be the unique address
你那条街上的邮箱的地址？
of the mailbox on your street there?
布莱恩：是的，这是我的邮箱。
BRIAN: Yeah, so here is my mailbox.
标为n。
It's labeled n.
它的地址在这里。
And its address is over here.
我的邮箱地址似乎是0x123。
The address of my mailbox appears to be 0x123.
DAVID MALAN：是的，所以我的邮箱也有一个地址。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so my mailbox, too, has an address.
坦白说，我并不是很在乎。
Frankly, again, I don't really care about it.
所以我什至没有把它放在这里的邮箱里。
So I've not even put it on the mailbox here.
但是如果我的邮箱代表p，一个指针和Brian的邮箱
But if my mailbox represents p, a pointer, and Brian's mailbox
代表n，一个整数，它应该
represents n, an integer, well, it should
表示如果我查看指针的内容
mean that if I look inside the contents of my pointer
我看到了值0x123，这现在是我的提示，
and I see the value 0x123, that is now my clue,
种类繁多的面包屑，现在可以让我看一下Brian的邮箱内。
a breadcrumb of sorts, that can now let me go look inside of Brian's mailbox.
还有布莱恩，如果您不介意为我们这样做，
And Brian, if you wouldn't mind doing that for us,
你在那个地址有什么？
what do you have at that address?
布莱恩：而且，如果我在邮箱中查找地址0x123，
BRIAN: And if I look in my mailbox at address 0x123,
我的邮箱里有50号。
I have the number 50 inside of this mailbox.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, indeed.
因此，在这种情况下，他碰巧正在存储一个int。
So in this case, he happens to be storing an int.
但这可能是其他任何事情。
But it could be anything else.
同样，我们通常并不关心这些特定地址。
And again, we don't typically care about these specific addresses.
理解了隐喻之后，我们真的可以做些愚蠢的事情
Once you understand the metaphor, really, we can do something silly
并且真的只是认为此邮箱存储的是
and really just think of this mailbox as storing a value that's
指向布莱恩的邮箱。
pointing at Brian's mailbox.
它是在那里绘制的某种方向，如箭头所示，
It's some kind of direction drawn there, pictorially as an arrow,
这里就像一个愚蠢的泡沫手指。
here as a silly foam finger.
或者，如果您愿意，可以使用泡沫耶鲁手指指向Brian的邮箱，
Or if you prefer, a foam Yale finger pointing, instead, at Brian's mailbox,
就像一种面包屑将我们带到屏幕上的其他价值一样。
just as a sort of breadcrumb leading us to some other value on the screen.
因此，当我们今天谈论地址之外时，
So when we talk today and beyond about addresses,
这就是我们正在谈论的全部。
that's all we're talking about.
现在，现实世界中的人类一直在使用eon的地址，
We humans in the real world have been using addresses for eons, now,
以唯一地标识我们的房屋或企业等。
to uniquely identify our homes or businesses or the like.
计算机在较低级别上执行完全相同的操作
Computers do the exact same thing at a lower level
使用他们计算机的内存。
using their computer's memory.
所以让我在这里暂停一下，看看是否有关于指针，变量的问题
So let me pause here to see if there are any questions on pointers, variables
存储地址或在这些新的运算符上，
that store addresses, or on these new operators,
像是“＆”号或“星号”
like the ampersand or the asterisk, which
从今天起有了新的含义。
now has a new meaning today onward.
还没有。
Nothing yet.
好吧，什么也没看到，现在让我们考虑一下，
All right, seeing none, well, let's consider now,
在完全不同的数据类型的上下文中是相同的故事。
the same story in the context of a completely different data type.
到目前为止，我们只玩过int。
Thus far, we've played only with ints.
但是考虑一下字符串。
But consider strings.
我们花了很多时间在字符串上，对它们使用加密
We've spent a lot of time on strings, using encryption with them
并使用用户的输入来解决实现选举算法的问题。
and solving implementing electoral algorithms using user's input.
因此，让我们考虑一个根本不同的数据
So let's consider a fundamentally different data
而不是存储单个整数的类型，而是存储文本字符串的类型。
type that stores, not individual integers, but strings of text instead.
因此，例如，在涉及字符串的任何程序中，
So for instance, in any program involving a string,
您可能会有一行看起来像这样的代码。字符串s等于，引用
you might have a line of code that looks like this. string s equals, quote
取消引用，“嗨！”
unquote, "HI!"
所有带有惊叹号的帽子。
in all caps with an exclamation point.
因此，这很可能是到目前为止我们已经看到的代码行。
So that may very well be a line of code that we've seen thus far.
计算机内存内部到底发生了什么？
What's actually going on inside of the computer's memory?
好吧，让我建议您在输入引号unquote时输入“ HI！”。在电脑上
Well, let me propose that when you type in quote unquote, "HI!" in a computer,
它最终存储在计算机内存中的某个位置。
it ends up somewhere in your computer's memory.
因此，HI感叹号加上上周的反斜线0或两周前，
So HI exclamation point, plus, per last week, a backslash 0-- or two weeks ago,
反斜杠0，这是计算机表示该字符串结尾的方式。
a backslash 0, which is how a computer represents the end of that string.
但是让我们更仔细地看一下
But let's look a little more carefully at
这里的引擎盖下面发生了什么。
what is going on underneath this hood here.
从技术上讲，我可以解决那些个人角色
Technically speaking, I could address those individual characters
从第二周开始，我们已经使用方括号表示法，例如s括号0，
we have seen as of week two, by using bracket notation like s bracket 0,
s支架1，s支架2和s支架3。
s bracket 1, s bracket 2, and s bracket 3.
我们使用方括号表示法来处理字符串
We use the square bracket notation to treat a string
好像是一个字符数组。
as though it's an array of characters.
是的，过去，现在仍然如此。
And it is, it was, and it still is.
但是事实证明，字符串也可以通过它们的地址来操纵
But it turns out, strings can also be manipulated by way of their addresses
也一样
as well.
举例来说，也许是相同的字符串HI，
And so for instance, maybe this same exact string, HI,
存储在内存地址0x123，然后存储在0x124、0x125和0x126。
is stored at memory address 0x123 and then 0x124, 0x125, and 0x126.
请注意，它们是故意相邻的
Notice that they're deliberately contiguous
地址，背对背。
addresses, back to back to back.
而且它们之间只有一个字节，因为每个字符当然都
And they're only one byte apart, because each of these chars, of course,
在C中只是一个字节
is just one byte in C.
因此，具体来说，这些数字并不重要。
So those numbers are not important, specifically.
但事实是它们彼此相距一个字节
But the fact that they're one byte apart from each other
很重要，因为这是字符串的定义，
is important, because that's the definition of a string,
确实是一个阵列，以背对背地拥有内存。
and indeed, an array, to have memory back to back to back.
现在，到底S是什么？
Now, what exactly, though, is S?
S是我刚才提到的那行代码的变量名称，
S was the name of the variable I gave a moment ago to go to that line of code,
字符串S等于引号取消引号“ HI”。
string S equals quote unquote, "HI."
好吧，S是什么？
well, what is S?
S是必须在计算机内存中存储的变量。
S is a variable that has to go somewhere in the computer's memory.
并且假设S确实是带有感叹号的HI。
And suppose that S is, indeed, HI with an exclamation point.
HI恰好住在这里。
And the HI happens to live at this location here.
您知道您可以将S视为现在，
You know what you can think of S as being now,
在高层次上不是一个字符串，但在较低层次上，
isn't, at a high level, a string, but at a lower level,
它只是一个字符串的地址。
it's just the address of a string.
更具体地说，让我们开始考虑一个字符串
More specifically, let's start thinking about a string
从技术上讲，它只是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
as technically being just the address of the first character in the string.
现在，这可能会让您暂停片刻，
Now, that might give you pause for a moment,
因为为什么第一个字符？
because why the first character?
您将如何记住这一点，请稍等片刻，该字符串不是唯一的
How are you going to remember that, wait a minute, this string isn't at and only
在0x123。
at 0x123.
它还以0x124、0x125等继续。
It also continues at 0x124, 0x125, and so forth.
但让我暂停一下，问一下这里的小组，为什么
But let me pause and ask the group here, why
也许对于一台电脑来说就足够了
might it very well be sufficient for a computer
和我们程序员只是考虑存在的字符串
and us programmers to just think of strings in terms of being
第一个字节的地址。
the address of the very first byte.
就像，为什么足够，无论多长时间
Like, why is it sufficient, no matter how long
即使是整个文本段，字符串也是
the string is, even if it's a whole paragraph of text,
为什么想到一个像S这样的字符串就足够聪明了
why is it very cleverly sufficient to think of a string like S
只是与第一个字节的地址相同？
as just being identical to the address of the first byte?
金妮，是吗？
Ginni, is it?
听众：可能是因为无论何时我们定义
AUDIENCE: Possibly because it happens that strings, whenever we are defining
一个新的字符串，共。
a new string, that is altogether.
假设，如果我写我的名字叫Ginni，那么它就是GINNI。
Suppose, if I'm writing my name, Ginni, so it will be G-I-N-N-I altogether.
因此，只要有针对性的话就足够了
So it will be sufficient if something is pointed
朝向我名字的第一个字符，这样我就可以
towards just first character of my name, so that I can just
跟进第一个字符，然后再获取所有字符。
follow up for the first character and then get all the characters afterwards.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
因此，过去几周我们拥有的所有这些基本定义
So all of these basic definitions we had over the past couple of weeks
现在走到一起。
now come together.
如果字符串只是一个字符数组-
If a string is just an array of characters--
根据数组的定义，这些字符又回来了
and by definition of array, those characters are back
背靠背，每两周一次，每个字符串
to back to back, and per two weeks ago, every string
以该常规反斜杠零或nul字符结尾。
ends with this conventional backslash zero or nul character.
考虑字符串时您需要做的所有事情
All you need to do when thinking about a string
只是想知道字符串从哪里开始，
is just to know where does the string begin,
因为您可以使用四个循环或一个while循环
because you can use a four loop or a while loop
或其他带有条件和布尔表达式的启发式方法
or some other heuristic with a condition and a Boolean expression
弄清楚字符串结尾的位置，甚至不知道，
to figure out where the string ends without even knowing,
提前，它的长度。
in advance, its length.
就是说，让我们开始吧，
So that is to say, let's start, for the moment,
认为字符串很简单
thinking of about strings as being quite simply
那只是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
that, just the address of the first character in the string.
如果我们将其视为事实，那么现在就开始吧，
And if we then take that as fact, let's go ahead, now,
然后开始玩一个不使用整数的程序，而是
and start playing with a program that doesn't use integers, but instead,
使用此基本原语的字符串。
used strings, using this basic primitive.
因此，让我继续删除我之前编写的代码，即地址。c。
So let me go ahead and delete the code I'd written before, an address.c.
让我将其更改为字符串等于引号unquote，“ HI”分号。
Let me just change it up to be string equals quote unquote, "HI" semicolon.
请注意，我没有手动输入任何反斜杠0。
And notice, I'm not manually typing any backslash 0's.
C自动为我们做到这一点。
C does that for us automatically.
当您关闭引号时，编译器会注意
When you close the quote, the compiler takes care
为您添加反斜杠0的说明。
of adding that backslash 0 for you.
现在，我要继续下一行
Now, I'm going to go ahead on the next line
并打印出％的反斜杠逗号，
and go ahead and print out percent s backslash n comma s,
如果我想打印出该字符串。
if I want to print out that string.
现在，这个程序一点也不有趣了。
Now, this program is not at all interesting anymore.
早在第一周，我们就写了-
Back in week one, we wrote something like--
好，是的，这很有趣，因为我搞砸了。
OK, yes it is interesting because I screwed up.
有五个错误。
So five errors.
我已经写了七行代码和五个错误。
I've written seven lines of code and five errors.
让我们看看发生了什么。
And let's see what's going on.
和往常一样，总是走在最前面，因为赔率很高，
As always, always go to the top, because odds are,
只是有一些令人困惑的级联效果。
there's just some confusing cascading effect.
我看到的第一个错误是使用未声明的标识符字符串。
The very first error I see is use of undeclared identifier string.
我的意思是标准n吗？
Did I mean standard n?
我不是说标准n，字符串，字符串，字符串。
I didn't mean standard n, string, string, string.
所以我可以将帮助50作为我的前沿，但是说实话，我
So I could run help 50 as my frontier, but honestly, I
经常犯这样的错误，我现在有点知道
make this mistake often enough that I kind of know now
我忘了包含cs50.h。
that I forgot to include cs50.h.
确实，如果我现在执行此操作并重新编译make地址，
And indeed, if I now do this and recompile make address--
好的，仅通过一个简单的更改，所有五个错误都消失了。
OK, all five errors are gone just by that one simple change.
如果我现在运行地址，那就很简单地说HI。
And if I run address now, it's just going to, quite simply, say HI.
但是现在让我们开始考虑发生了什么
But let's now start to consider what's going
在这个程序的幕后。
on underneath the hood of this program.
假设我很好奇，想打印出实际的内容
Suppose I am curious and want to print out what is actually
该字符串所在的地址。
the address at which this string lives.
好吧，事实证明……
Well, it turns out--
让我在这里聪明一点。
let me be clever here.
让我打印出来，不是百分比s的格式代码，而是百分比p的格式代码。
Let me print out, not a format code of percent s, but percent p.
告诉我这个与地址相同的字符串。
Show me this same string as an address.
让我继续进行重新编译，使之寻址，好像编译就可以了。
Let me go ahead and recompile, make address, seems to compile OK.
让我运行点斜杠地址。
Let me run dot slash address.
再说一次，我仍在打印s，但我问的是printf
And again, I'm still printing s, but I'm asking printf
呈现它，就像它是一个指针一样。
to present it as though it's a pointer.
有趣的是，它与以前不同。
And interesting, it's not the same as before.
但这又是合理的，因为内存地址
But again, that's reasonable because the memory addresses
不会总是一样的。
aren't going to always be the same.
但这无关紧要。
But it doesn't matter what it is.
但这有点有趣。
But that's kind of interesting.
一直以来，无论何时您一直在使用字符串，
All this time, any time you've been using strings,
您是否刚刚将百分比s更改为百分比p，
had you just changed your percent s to a percent p,
您可能已经看到了该字符串在内存中实际开始的位置。
you could have seen where, in memory, that string actually starts.
到目前为止，它在功能上对我们还没有用。
It's not functionally useful to us just yet.
但是它一直都在那儿。
But it's been there this whole time.
现在让我继续进行以下操作。
And let me go ahead and do the following now.
假设我进一步感到好奇，我做了printf。
Suppose I get a little curious further, and I do printf.
让我继续并打印出另一个地址，然后再换一行。
Let me go ahead and print out another address followed by a new line.
让我继续打印第一个字符的地址。
And let me go ahead and print out the address of the first character.
再说一次，这有点奇怪。
So again, this is a little weird to do.
而且我们通常不会经常这样做。
And we wouldn't typically do this that often.
但是，再次强调一下，这些运算符使我们非常简单
But again, just to make the point that these operators give us very simple
问题的答案，例如，这东西的地址是什么？
answers to questions like, what is the address of this thing?
如果截至CS50第二周的s括号i代表s中的第二个字符，
If s bracket i, as of week two in CS50, represented the second character in s,
因为0索引表示s括号0是第一个，s括号1是第二个。
because 0 index means s bracket 0 is the first, s bracket 1 is the second.
如果我和今天的新运营商一起玩，
If I play around with today's new operator,
我敢打赌我可以看到第二个字符的地址。
this ampersand, I bet I can see the address of that second character.
实际上，让我继续说得更明确些。
And in fact, let me go ahead and be more explicit.
让我将第一个s更改为s括号0并在此处放置一个＆符。
Let me change this first s to be s bracket 0 and put an ampersand here.
现在，让我继续，编写该程序，编写地址。
And let me go ahead, now, and make this program, make address.
好吧，有点时髦-
OK, a little funky--
我只是想念一个分号。
I just missed a semicolon.
在那里很容易修复。
So easy fix there.
让我继续并用make地址重新编译。
Let me go ahead and recompile with make address.
让我继续运行点斜杠地址。
Let me go ahead and run dot slash address.
有趣的是，也许-
And interesting, well, maybe--
对我来说很有趣。
interesting to me.
所以，您现在看到两个地址，第一个
So you see, now, two addresses, the first of which
是0x4006a4，显然是s中第一个字符的地址。
is 0x4006a4, which apparently, is the address of the first character in s.
但是请注意下一个是什么。
But notice what's curious about the next one.
几乎是相同的，只是字节相距更远。
It's almost the same except the byte is one further away.
而且我敢打赌，如果我这样做，不仅限于h和i，
And I bet if I do this, not just for the h and the i,
还有感叹号-让我去做
but also the exclamation point-- let me do
一行几乎相同的代码，只是
one more line of almost identical code, just
指出所有这些时间的确是
to make the point that all this time it's, indeed,
字符串中的所有字符都背靠背排列的情况。
been the case that all characters in a string are back to back to back.
现在您可以在代码中看到它。
And you can now see it in code.
b4，b5，b6仅相隔一个字节。
b4, b5, b6, are just one byte apart.
因此，我们看到了一些视觉确认，现在字符串确实是
So we see some visual confirmation, now, that strings are indeed
这样布置在内存中。
laid out in memory just like this.
再说一次，这不是一个非常有用的程序设计练习
Now, again, this is not a very useful programmatic exercise
查看单个字符的地址。
to look at the address of individual characters.
但是，这再次是为了强调在引擎盖下，
But again, this is just to emphasize that underneath the hood,
一些相对简单的操作正在
some relatively simple operations are being
通过这个新的“＆”号，然后是星号运算符启用。
enabled by way of this new ampersand, and in turn, star operator.
因此，让我们考虑一下这看起来到底是什么
So let's consider for a moment what this really looks
就像在计算机内存中一样。
like inside the computer's memory.
从低层次上讲，是的，s从技术上讲是一个地址。
At a low level, yes, s is technically an address.
是的，从技术上讲，这是第一个字节的地址，
And yes, it's technically the address of the first byte,
在实际的计算机中，看起来有所不同。
which in the actual computer, looked different.
但是在我这里的幻灯片中，我只是随意地提出了
But in my slide here, I just arbitrarily proposed
它位于0x123、0x124、0x125。
that it's at 0x123, 0x124, 0x125.
但是，再次，我们不必关心该详细程度。
But again, let's not care about that level of detail.
让我们挥挥手，摘掉这些地址
Let's just kind of wave our hands and abstract away these addresses
刚刚开始考虑s，这是一个字符串，从技术上讲
and just now start thinking of s, that is a string, as technically just being
一个指针。
a pointer.
指针。
A pointer.
事实证明，即使它非常有用且非常普遍
So it turns out that even though it's very useful and very common
认为字符串显然只是字符序列。
to think of strings as, obviously, just being sequences of characters.
从第一周开始就是如此。
And that's been true since week one.
您也可以将它们视为数组，
And you can also think of them as arrays,
背对背的字符序列。
back to back sequences of characters.
事实证明，从今天开始，
You can also, it turns out, starting today,
认为它们只是指针，也就是说，
think of them as just being pointers, that is,
计算机内存中某个字符的地址。
the address of a character somewhere in the computer's memory.
正如Ginni所指出的，因为字符串中的所有字符
And as Ginni notes, because all of the characters in a string
从定义上讲，是背对背，
are, by definition, back to back to back,
并且因为根据定义，所有字符串都以反斜杠0结尾，因此
and because, by definition, all strings end with a backslash 0, that
实际上是最小且唯一的信息量
is literally the smallest and only amount of information
您需要在计算机中四处走动，以了解所有字符串的位置。
you need to keep around in a computer to know where all of your strings are.
只要记住第一个字符的地址
Just remember the address of the very first character
在其中，因为您可以找到通往终点的道路
therein, because you can find your way to the end
记得这个反斜杠0确实是8 0
by remembering that this backslash 0 is, really, just eight 0
位，否则表示为反斜杠0。
bits, otherwise represented as backslash 0.
所以我们当然可以有一个if条件，
And so we could certainly have an if condition,
就像我们两个星期前在玩耍时所做的一样
much like we did two weeks ago when playing around
加上字符串的长度，这使我们能够准确地进行检查。
with the lengths of strings, that allows us to check for precisely that.
因此，当我说我们要卸下一些训练轮时，它们就到了。
And so when I say we're taking off some training wheels, here they go.
到目前为止，我们一直在使用CS50库，
So up until now, we've been using, again, the CS50 library,
这给了我们方便的功能，例如get string和get int
which gives us, conveniently, functions like get string and get int
并开始浮动等等。
and get float and so forth.
但是，一直以来，CS50库，特别是文件cs50.h，
But all this time, the CS50 library, specifically the file, cs50.h,
有一点教学上的简化。
had a little bit of a pedagogical simplification in it.
回想上周，您可以定义自己的自定义数据类型。
Recall last week, that you can define your own custom data types.
好吧，事实证明，一直以来，我们一直在声称字符串存在
Well, it turns out that all this time, we've been claiming that strings exist
它们是您可以在程序中使用的东西。
and they're something you can use in your programs.
字符串确实存在于C中。它们确实存在于Python，JavaScript，Java，
And strings do exist in C. They do exist in Python, in JavaScript, in Java,
和C ++，还有许多其他许多语言。
and C++, in many, many, many other languages.
这不是CS50术语。
This is not a CS50 term.
但是从技术上讲，字符串在C中不作为数据类型存在。相反，
But string, technically, does not exist as a data type in C. It instead,
更隐秘，更底层地称为char star。
is more cryptically and more low-level known as char star.
查尔斯星，这是什么意思？
Char star, now what does that mean?
好吧，char明星，就像几分钟前我们的int明星一样，
Well, char star, much like our int star a few minutes ago,
只是代表一个字符的地址，就像int star
just represents the address of a character, much like int star
代表一个整数的地址。
represents the address of an int.
再说一次，如果您现在也同意我的观点，
And if, again, you kind of agree with me now,
您可以将字符串视为字符序列，
that you can think of strings as sequences of characters,
或更具体地说，是字符数组，或更具体地，
or more specifically, arrays of characters, or more specifically,
到今天为止，第一个字符的地址，
as of today, the address of just the first character,
那么的确是这样，我们现在可以
then it's, indeed, the case that we now can
运用今天的指针新术语，
apply this new terminology, today, of pointer,
给我们熟悉的老朋友，弦乐。
to our old familiar friends, strings.
字符串与char star的同义词是一样的。
String is the same thing as a synonym, if you will, for char star.
实际上，在CS50库中，我们有一行代码
And it's in the CS50 library that we, essentially, have a line of code
可以简化或抽象出char char星，说实话，没人愿意
that simplifies or abstracts away char star, which honestly, no one wants
在上课的第一周去思考或挣扎，
to think about or struggle with in the first week of a class,
更不用说上课的前两，三周了。
let alone the first two or three weeks of a class.
这是一种简化的自定义数据类型，我们将其命名为string，
It's a simplification, a custom data type, that we name string,
只是您不必考虑，这颗星是什么？
just so you don't have to think about, what is this star?
角色是什么？
What is it to the character?
地址是什么？
What is it an address of?
但是今天，我们可以移除那些训练轮，并在所有时间内揭示出这些，
But today, we can remove those training wheels and reveal that, all this time,
您刚刚在操作特定地址的字符。
you've just been manipulating characters at specific addresses.
而且我们之前使用过这种技术，
And we've used this kind of technique before,
提取这些较低级别的细节。
abstracting away these lower level details.
例如，回想一下上周，我们介绍了
For instance, recall last week, that we introduced
这种结构的概念，您可以自定义自己的数据类型。
this notion of a struct, a data type that you can customize to be your own.
通过包装在一起，我们实现了更好的电话簿
We implemented a better phone book by wrapping together
自定义数据类型中的名称和数字，
a name and a number inside of a custom data type,
如果可以的话，将它们封装在我们称为“人”的内部。
encapsulating them if you will, inside of something we called person.
我们声称的每个人都有一个结构
And every person we claimed had a structure
其中包含一个名称和一个数字。
that contains a name and a number.
通过C的这种特性typedef，我们可以定义一个新类型。
And by the way of this feature of C, typedef, we can define a new type.
上周，这种类型的名字就是人。
And the name of that type, last week, was just person.
所以我们已经在使用，并且我们已经秘密地进行了
So we're using, already, and we have been sort of secretly
自C的第一周开始使用，一行代码
using since the first week of C in the class, a line of code that
实际上看起来像这样。
actually looks like this.
实际上，这是cs50.h内部的代码行之一。
And this is, indeed, one of the lines of code inside of cs50.h.
它说typedef，这意味着给我一个自定义类型。
It says typedef, which means give me a custom type.
并且它为char star创建了一个名为string的同义词。
And it creates a synonym for char star called string.
这只是我们隐藏时髦的char星的一种方式。
And it's just a way where we can hide the funky char star.
我们可以特别隐藏星号，而不会
We can hide the asterisk, in particular, which would not
在头几天玩的很开心，
be fun to play with in the first few days,
但无需更改字符串的定义。
but without changing the definition of what a string is.
因此，字符串存在于C中。但是C中没有称为字符串的数据类型
So strings exist in C. But there's no data type called string in C
直到您使用CS50之类的库为止
until you use a library like CS50's, which makes it exist
通过这种定义的方式。
by way of that kind of definition.
好吧，让我在这里停留看看是否有
All right, let me pause here to see if there's
那么，关于什么是字符串的任何问题
any questions, then, about what strings are
或这些新的思考方式。
or these new ways of thinking about them.
对字符串或字符星有任何疑问吗？
Any questions about strings or char stars?
好吧，如果这里没有问题，为什么
All right, well, if no questions here, why
我们不要继续，先在这里休息5分钟。
don't we go ahead and take our 5 minute break here first.
然后我们回到5，再来看看
And we'll be back in 5 and take another look
我们现在可以使用这些新原语做什么。
at what we can now do with these new primitives.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we're back.
现在，我们已经在代码中获得了获取某些变量地址的功能
And we have, now, this ability in code to get the address of some variable
并且也要使用＆符去一个地址
and also to go to an address using ampersand
和星号分别。
and the asterisk, respectively.
我们认为字符串不仅是连续的序列
We've thought about strings as being not only contiguous sequences
字符，也可以是数组。
of characters, but also arrays.
然后，当然，到今天为止，实际地址，
And then of course, as of today now, actual addresses,
第一个字符的地址，然后从那里开始，
the address of the first character and then, from there,
我们能否以编程方式找到最终的方法，
can we find our way, programmatically, to the end,
多亏了那个nul角色。
thanks to that nul character.
但是事实证明，我们可以使用这些地址做另一件事
But it turns out there's one other thing we can do with these addresses
或更一般地使用指针。
or with pointers more generally.
这就是所谓的指针算法。
And that's known as pointer arithmetic.
所以，当然，任何数字都可以进行数学运算。
So anything that's a number, of course, we can do math on.
数学不会变得复杂，
And the math is not going to be complicated,
但这对我们来说将是强大的。
but it is going to be powerful for us here.
因此，我将返回到最新的address.c状态。
So I'm going to go back to my most recent state of address.c.
现在让我继续，并重申我们可以打印出
And let me go ahead, now, and reiterate that we can print out
字符串中的各个字符，就像我们在第二周所做的一样，
the individual characters in a string, just like we did back in week two,
如使用方括号表示法。
as by using our square bracket notation.
因此，我暂时摆脱了那些地址的所有证据。
So I'm getting rid of all evidence of those addresses for now.
我正在将该程序重新编译为make地址。
I'm recompiling this program as make address.
然后我现在要运行点斜杠地址。
And then I'm going to run dot slash address now.
而且我看到HI感叹号，每行一个字符。
And I see HI exclamation point, one character per line.
但是现在，请考虑不需要字符串数据类型。
But now, consider that there doesn't need to be a string data type.
实际上，我们可以取消此训练轮。
In fact, we can take this training wheel off.
虽然刚开始时可能会感到不舒服，
And while it might feel a little uncomfortable at first,
如果我完全删除了第一行，因为我还是无意中省略了
if I delete this first line altogether, as I've accidentally omitted anyway
有时，我不需要继续称呼事物为字符串。
sometimes, I don't need to keep calling things strings.
我可以用口头上的字符串来形容它们。
I can describe them as strings verbally.
我可以将它们视为字符串，因为字符串
I can think of them as strings, because string
在许多不同的编程语言中都是一回事。
is a thing in many different programming languages.
但是默认情况下，在C中，它根本不作为类型存在。
But by default, in C, it just doesn't exist as a type.
取而代之的是，该类型有些隐晦地命名为char star。
Instead, the type is somewhat cryptically named, char star.
但是，这再次说明，星星意味着这里是
But again, all that means is that the star means here's
某物的地址。
the address of something.
字符表示这是一个字符的地址。
Char means it's the address of a char.
所以char star给你一个指针变量
So char star gives you a pointer variable
这将指向一个角色。
that's going to point to a character.
所以现在，如果s是，我实际上可以将其视为相同。
So now, if s is that, I can actually treat it the same.
没有理由我不能继续使用s，就像第二周返回一个字符串一样，
There's no reason I can't keep using s like a string was back in week two,
使用方括号表示法。
using our square bracket notation.
而且我可以继续打印出HI感叹号
And I can keep printing out HI exclamation point
使用相同的方括号语法。
using that same square bracket syntax.
但是我还有另一种方法可以做到这一点。
But there's one other way I can do this.
如果我现在知道s实际上只是一个地址，
If I now know that s is really just an address,
我可以摆脱这种方括号表示法。
I can get rid of this square bracket notation.
而且我实际上可以做star，因为还记得那颗star
And I can actually just do star s, because recall that star, in addition
成为我们在此处声明指针时使用的新符号，
to being the new symbol that we use when declaring a pointer up here,
它也是同一个符号，令人困惑，诚然，
it's also the same symbol, confusingly, admittedly,
我们曾经去过一个地址。
that we used to go to an address.
因此，如果s存储一个地址，根据定义它是一个指针，
So if s is storing an address, which it is by definition of being a pointer,
star的意思是去那个地址。
star s means go to that address.
根据我之前的照片，
And per my picture earlier, it would seem
s很有可能是从0x123开始的地址。
to be the case that s is most likely at an address beginning at 0x123.
在我这里的实际IDE中，它不会是一样的。
It's not going to be the same in my actual IDE here.
这将是计算机要执行的所有操作。
It will be whatever the computer has ordained.
但这将是完全相同的想法。
But it's going to be the same exact idea.
因此，让我继续前进并前往星号。
So let me go ahead and go to star s.
只是为了踢球，让我把它留在那一行。
And just for kicks, let me leave it as just that one line.
因此，让我继续并将其作为make地址重新运行。
So let me go ahead and rerun this as make address.
好的，现在是点斜杠地址。
All right, and now dot slash address.
希望我应该看到一个大写的H而只有一个H。但是请注意这一点。
I should see, hopefully, a capital H and only an H. But watch this.
如果我知道s（一个字符串）从技术上来说只是一个地址，
If I know that s, a string, is technically just an address,
我现在实际上可以对此进行数学运算。
I can actually now do math on it.
我可以继续打印出另一个字符，然后换行。
And I can go ahead and print out another character, followed by a new line.
我可以去的不是s，而是s加1。
And I can go to, not s, but how about s plus 1.
因此，如果可以的话，我可以对该指针执行一些非常简单的算术运算。
So I can do some very simple arithmetic, if you will, on that pointer.
让我继续，现在重新编译它。
And let me go ahead and now recompile this.
这样做地址，编译就可以了，点斜杠地址。
So make address, compiles OK, dot slash address.
我应该看你好。
And I should see HI.
如果我再做一行这样的代码，printf，％c，反斜杠n，
And if I do one more line of code like this, printf, percent c, backslash n,
star s plus 2，我现在可以去找角色
star s plus 2, I can now go to the character
与s相距两个字节
that is two bytes away from whatever s is,
再次，它是字符串的开头。
which again, is the start of the string.
所以现在，我用感叹号字符重印了HI
So now, I've reprinted HI with the exclamation point character
按字符，但不使用此花括号
by character, but not by using this fancy square bracket
表示法，只是在某种意义上看上它对我们来说是一种抽象，
notation, fancy only in the sense that it was sort of an abstraction for us,
如果可以的话。
if you will.
我实际上是在处理s的实际含义，这只是一个地址。
I'm instead, manipulating s for what it really is, which is just an address.
所以在这里，我之前也用过这个词，
And so here, too, and I've used this phrase before,
我们在第二周引入的方括号符号
that square bracket notation that we introduced in week two,
从技术上讲只是语法糖。
is technically just syntactic sugar.
它没有做任何根本不同的事情
It's not doing anything fundamentally different
来自这些星号和这些地址。
from these asterisks and these addresses.
老实说，它只是以一种更加友好的方式进行操作。
It's just doing it, honestly, in a much more user-friendly way.
我个人还是比较喜欢第二周的方括号表示法。
I still prefer, personally, the square bracket notation from week two.
但这与使用恒星并自己进行数学运算是一样的。
But it's the same thing as using the star and doing this math yourself.
因此，C只是为我们提供了这一方便的功能
So C is just providing us with this handy feature
使用方括号来完成所有这些所谓的指针
of using square brackets that does all of this so-called pointer
为您算术。
arithmetic for you.
但是再次，我们将要达到这个低水平
But again, we're going to this low level just
强调这到底是怎么回事。
to emphasize what it is that's going on ultimately underneath the hood here.
好吧，让我在这里停留任何疑问。
All right, let me pause here for any questions.
还有Brian，请随时对您的任何内容进行口头表达。
And Brian, please do feel free to verbalize any on your end.
布莱恩：我看到一个关于将会发生什么的问题
BRIAN: I see a question that came in about what would happen
如果您尝试打印star s plus 3。
if you tried to print star s plus 3.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：因此，我很确定这将打印出nul字符。
DAVID MALAN: So I'm pretty sure that's going to print out the nul character.
但是，让我们继续在这里进行确认，
But let's go ahead and confirm as much here,
百分比c反斜杠n星s加3。
percent c backslash n star s plus 3.
好吧，我这里有点冒险
All right, I'm getting a little adventurous here
通过看我可能不应该看的东西，因为那是
by looking at things I maybe shouldn't be looking at, because that's
低级实施细节。
a low level implementation detail.
但是，让我们看看会发生什么。
But let's see what happens.
它会编译OK，点斜杠地址。
It compiles OK, dot slash address.
它似乎是空白。
And it seems to be blank.
现在，也许这就是nul角色。
Now, maybe that's the nul character.
老实说，这并不是要成为可打印的字符。
Honestly, it's not meant to be a printable character.
这个特殊的哨兵值表示字符串的结尾。
It's this special sentinel value that indicates the end of the string.
但是我可以做到这一点。
But I could do this.
我从第二周开始就知道char是整数
I know from week two that chars are integers
如果我想用整数的话，整数就是字符。
and integers are chars if I want to think of them that way.
所以让我只更改最后一个字符
So let me change only the very last character
使用格式代码百分比i。
to use the format code percent i.
让我重新编译我的代码。
Let me recompile my code.
让我继续说一下地址。
Let me go ahead and run address.
和瞧，HI感叹号0。
And voila, HI exclamation 0.
而且这里所有的0位都表示为一个十进制数字
And there is the all 0 bits represented here as one single decimal digit thanks
占百分之一
to percent i.
现在，我可以在这里变得非常疯狂。
Now, I can get really crazy here.
为什么我们不继续打印出不只是什么字符
And why don't we go ahead and print out not just what characters
就在此序列之后，HI感叹号nul字符，
are right after this sequence, HI exclamation point nul character,
我们为什么不去-哦，该如何处理1000字节的距离，
why don't we go to-- oh heck, how about address 1,000 bytes away,
并真的让我的计算机内管闲事？
and really get nosy inside of my computer?
让我重新编译该点斜杠地址。
Let me recompile that dot slash address.
好吧，那边什么都没有发生。
OK, nothing really going on over there.
大约10,000个字节如何？
How about 10,000 bytes away?
让我继续发言。
Let me go ahead and make address.
让我继续运行此细分错误。好的
Let me go ahead and run this segmentation fault. All, right
那很糟。
that's bad.
您可能是幸运的少数人，之前也曾见过此错误
And you might be among the fortunate few who have seen this error before
通过触摸内存，您不应该这样做。
by touching memory you shouldn't.
今天，我们将故意考虑这一点。
And we're going to deliberately consider this today.
但是，细分错误实际上意味着您已经做了一些事情
But a segmentation fault, indeed, means that you have done something
错误的代码中的某个地方。
wrong somewhere in your code.
这往往意味着您触及了一段内存
And it tends to mean that you touched a segment of memory
你不应该拥有的
that you shouldn't have.
老实说，我没事，要看10,000个字节
And I have no business, honestly, looking 10,000 bytes away
从我知道的内存中属于字符串。
from the memory that I know belongs to the string.
就像随意查看计算机内存中的任何地方，
That's like arbitrarily looking anywhere in your computer's memory,
看来，这可能不是一个好主意。
which probably, it seems, is not a good idea.
但是更多的只是一点点。
But more on that in just a bit.
现在，让我们考虑一下其中的一些含义
So let's consider, now, some of the implications
这些基本的实施细节
of these underlying implementation details
再考虑一下，从上周开始，为什么我们做了一些事情
and consider, now, from last week, why we did a few things the way
实际上，我们在过去几周中做到了。
we did in the past few weeks, in fact.
因此，string只是一个char明星。
So string is just a char star.
现在，让我们考虑一个示例。
And let's, now, consider an example.
让我放大自己的记忆，这样我就可以一次添加更多内容。
Let me zoom out on my memory, just so I can cram more in at once.
让我们考虑一个我可能想写的例子
Let's consider an example where I might want to write
比较两个字符串的程序。
a program that compares two strings.
这次，让我继续在新文件中编写一些新代码，
Let me go ahead and write some new code here in a new file this time,
例如，称为compare.c。
called, for instance, compare.c.
很简单，我对该程序的目标是
My goal with this program, quite simply, is
将会打印出内容-或进行比较
going to be to print out the contents of-- or rather to compare
用户可能输入的两个字符串。
two strings that the user might input.
我将继续进行，并包含cs59.h，
I'm going to go ahead and include cs59.h,
不是因为我想再说一遍字符串，
not because I want string, per say, anymore,
但是因为我想使用get string只是为了方便。
but because I want to use get string just for convenience.
但是，我们也会暂时取消该训练轮。
But we'll take that training wheel off in a bit, too.
在这个程序中，我将继续进行
And in this program, I'm going to go ahead and first
使用，尚未获取字符串。
use, not get string yet.
让我继续保持简单，从get int开始。
Let me go ahead and keep it simple and start with get int.
我会问用户一个变量i。
And I'll ask the user for a variable i.
然后让我再做一个int并问
And let me do another one of these in get int and ask
用户输入j的值。
the user for a value for j.
然后让我继续简单地说，如果我等于j，
And then let me go ahead and quite simply say, if i equals equals j,
然后继续打印其他内容。
then go ahead and print out same else.
让我继续打印不同的内容。
Let me go ahead and print out different.
因此，这是第一周的工作，我在其中使用了两个变量。
So this is week one stuff, where I'm using a couple of variables.
我正在使用带有两个分支的条件
I'm using a condition with two branches, and I'm
使用printf打印出两个变量i和j是否相同。
using printf to print out whether those two variables, i and j, are the same.
因此，让我们继续进行编译。
So let's go ahead and compile this.
一切都很好。
All is well.
运行比较，然后让我给数字1和2。
Run compare, and let me give it digits 1 and 2.
实际上，它们是不同的。
And indeed, they're different.
让我继续给它1和1，它们是相同的。
And let me go ahead and give it 1 and 1, and they're the same.
因此，我认为从逻辑上讲可以通过示例进行证明，如果您愿意，
So I think, logically, proof by example, if you will,
这个程序看起来正确。
this program looks correct.
但是让我通过不使用整数来快速使它看起来不正确。
But let me quickly make it seemingly uncorrect, by not using integers.
但是，通过使用字符串代替。
But how about, by using strings instead.
让我继续，给我自己一个字符串。
Let me go ahead and give myself a string.
虽然，不，我不再需要该训练轮。
Although, no, I don't need that training wheel anymore.
让我们做char star s equals获得s的字符串。
Let's just do char star s equals get string of s.
但是再说一次，即使我称它为char star，
But again, even though I'm calling it char star,
仍然像几周前一样。
it's still a string like it was weeks ago.
让我给自己另一个字符串t，以保持名称简短。
Let me give myself another string called t, just to keep the name short.
s会得到-
And s will get--
t将在那里获得该值。
t will get that value there.
而且让我只是，非常幼稚，但有一点合理，
And let me just, very naively but kind of reasonably,
假设s等于t，让我们继续打印出来。
say if s equals equals t, let's go ahead and print out same.
否则，让我们继续进行打印。
And otherwise, let's go ahead and print out different.
因此，相同的确切代码，只是不同的数据类型，并且使用
So same exact code, just different data types, and using
获取字符串而不是获取整数。
get string instead of get int.
让我继续进行比较，似乎可以编译好了，点斜杠进行比较。
Let me go ahead and make compare, seems to compile OK, dot slash compare.
让我继续输入HI！-
Let me go ahead and type in HI!--
哇，嗨！
woops, HI!.
让我继续输入HI！再次。
Let me go ahead and type in HI! again.
和瞧，不同。
And voila, different.
而且我忘记了反斜杠n，但这似乎是我遇到的最少问题。
And I forgot my backslash n's, but that seems to be the least of my problems.
让我重新编译一下，进行比较，现在，让我再次运行它。
Let me recompile this, make compare, and now, let me run it again.
怎么样，让我们做一个快速测试。
How about, let's do a quick test.
大卫，布莱恩，这些绝对不同。
David, Brian, these are definitely different.
好好
OK, good.
因此，该程序似乎可以正常工作。
So the program seems to work.
大卫，大卫呢？
How about David, David?
也不同。
Also different.
，让我再试一次。
Huh, let me try again.
布莱恩，布莱恩，也有所不同。
Brian, Brian, also different.
但是我很确定那些字符串是相同的。
But I'm pretty sure those strings are the same.
为什么该程序有缺陷？
Why might this program be flawed?
此程序现在有什么问题？
What is wrong with this program right now?
布莱恩：聊天中的几个人
BRIAN: A couple of people in the chat are
说我们实际上不是在比较字符，
saying that we're not actually comparing the characters,
我们正在比较地址。
we're comparing the addresses.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，这是今天的逻辑结论
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so that's sort of the logical conclusion from today's
字符串真正是什么的定义。
definition of what a string really is.
如果字符串只是其第一个字符的地址，
If a string is just the address of its first character,
那么如果您实际上是在做s等于t，
then if you're literally doing s equals equals t,
您正在比较这两个地址。
you're comparing those two addresses.
他们可能会有所不同，
And they are probably going to be different,
即使我输入相同的内容，因为每次
even if I type in the same thing, because every time we've
称为get int或get string，有点用户的输入
called get int or get string, it's kind of plopped the user's input
在我计算机内存中的某个位置。
somewhere in my computer's memory.
但说实话，我们现在有了工具来回答这个问题或审查这个回答
But we now have the tools, honestly, to answer this or vet this answer
我们自己。
ourselves.
让我继续简化此程序。
Let me go ahead and simplify this program.
然后，就像快速进行健全性检查一样，打印出s。
And let's, just as a quick sanity check, print out s.
让我们继续，并在每行之后使用新行打印出来，
And let's go ahead and print out t using a new line after each,
以便我们可以看到字符串是什么。
just so we can see what the strings are.
因此，让我继续进行此操作，进行比较，编译正常，点斜杠
So let me go ahead and do this again, make compare, compiles OK, dot slash
比较。
compare.
我输入HI，HI。
Let me type in HI, HI.
它们看起来在视觉上是相同的。
And they seem to be visually the same.
但是回想一下，现在，我还有其他格式的代码，
But recall that, now, I have this other format code,
这样我现在就可以开始处理弦乐了
such that I can now start treating strings
作为技术上的地址。
as the addresses they technically are.
因此，让我在两个地方将百分比s更改为百分比p。
So let me change percent s to percent p in both places.
然后让我重新编译程序，然后重新运行HI和HI。
Let me then recompile the program, and now, rerun compare with both HI and HI
完全相同的类型。
identically typed.
但是请注意，它们最终位于稍微不同的内存位置。
But notice, they've ended up at slightly different memory locations.
即使我碰巧键入了相同的内容，C和我的计算机
Even though I have coincidentally typed the same thing, C and my computer
不会太冒昧，以至于两个字符串都使用相同的字节。
are not going to be so presumptuous as to use the same bytes for both strings.
那不会给我太大的灵活性
That's not going to give me much flexibility
如果我想换一个。
if I want to change one or the other.
它将非常简单地将一个放入此内存中
It's going to very simplistically put one in this chunk of memory
另一个在此内存块中。
and the other in this chunk of memory.
实际上，这些地址分别是但任意地
And indeed, those addresses are respectively, but arbitrarily,
0x22fe670和0x22fe6b0。
0x22fe670 and 0x22fe6b0.
因此它们分散开了一段距离。
So they are spread apart some distance.
但是同样，这取决于计算机来决定将它们实际放置在何处。
But again, it's up to the computer to decide where to actually put those.
那么，计算机内存内部到底发生了什么？
So what's actually going on inside of the computer's memory?
好吧，让我们考虑一下，例如，这是我的指针，还是真的，
Well, let's consider if, for instance, this is s, my pointer, or really,
我的绳子。
my string.
但这只是一个指针。
But it's just a pointer now.
这是某物的地址。
It's the address of something.
请注意，我将其绘制为占用八个正方形，
Notice that I've drawn it as taking up eight squares,
因为同样，现代系统上的指针是八个字节。
because again, a pointer on modern systems is eight bytes.
这就是为什么这个东西这么大的原因。
So that's why this thing is so big.
同时，当我用感叹号输入HI之类的内容时，
Meanwhile, when I type in something like HI with the exclamation point,
然后它最终会出现在内存中的某个地方。
then it ends up somewhere in memory.
我们真的不知道也不在乎它在哪里。
We don't really know or care where it is.
因此，我们随便说一下它恰好在那儿结束了
So let's just arbitrarily say it happens to end up there
在我计算机的内存中。
in my computer's memory.
现在，这些字节中的每个字节当然都有一个地址。
Now, each of those bytes, of course, has an address.
我不一定知道或不在乎它们是什么。
I don't necessarily know or care what they are.
但是为了说明起见，让我们像以前一样对它们再次编号，
But for explanation's sake, let's just number them again like before,
0x123、0x124、0x125、0x126。
0x123, 0x124, 0x125, 0x126.
然后，当我在左侧分配s时，从右侧的get string中获取值，
When I then assign s on the left the value from get string on the right,
得到字符串，怎么办？
get string, what is it going to do?
好吧，自从第一周开始，所有的时间，因为您一直在使用它，
Well, all of this time since week one, since you've been using it,
是的，获取字符串并将其作为返回值返回给您。
it is, yes, getting a string and handing it back to you as a return value.
但这到底是什么意思？
But what does that really mean?
好吧，如果字符串只是一个地址，那么函数的返回值
Well, if a string is just an address, the return value of a function
就像获取字符串是要返回的，而不是字符串本身，因为那是
like get string is to return to, not the string per se, because that's
一种高级概念。
kind of a high level concept.
获取字符串一直为我们做的事情
What get string has always been doing for us
返回字符串的地址，或者更多
is returning the address of the string, or more
具体来说，是字符串中第一个字符的地址。
specifically, the address of the first character in the string.
因此，从技术上讲，要清楚地存储在s中的是该地址0x123。
And so what is technically stored in s, to be clear, is that address, 0x123.
它并没有返回到整个字符串，即H，I，感叹号。
It's not returning to the whole string, the H, the I, the exclamation point.
相反，它只是向您返回一个值。
Rather, it's returning just one value to you.
它仅向您返回该字符串的第一个字符的地址。
It's returning only to you the address of the first character of that string.
但是同样，这对于s来说都是非常好的。
But again, this is all very good for just s.
t怎么了？
What's going on with t?
t有点类似，因为我要再次调用get string。
t is kind of the same story, because I'm calling get string again.
t将被分配第一个字符的地址
t is going to get assigned the address of the first character
此版本的HI。
of this version of HI.
我们随便说一下它是0x456、0x457、0x458和0x459。
And let's just arbitrarily say it's at 0x456, 0x457, 0x458, and 0x459.
此时，t将取值为0x456。
And at this point, t is going to take on the value of 0x456.
现在，老实说，到这一点，我们真的进入了杂草丛生。
And now, at this point, honestly, we're really getting into the weeds.
让我们开始将所有这些抽象出来
Let's just start abstracting all of this away
并使用箭头指向这些值。
and use arrows to point at the values.
实际上，这些箭头仅代表指针
And indeed, these arrows just represent pointers
当我们不再关心特定的地址时。
when we stop caring about the particular addresses.
所以s实际上只是一个指针，一个变量指向
So s is really just a pointer, a variable pointing
在这里HI的第一个字符处。
at the first character of HI here.
t只是指向HI的第一个字符的变量。
t is just a variable pointing at the first character of HI there.
因此，当您比较两个字符串时
And so when you are comparing two strings
就像我以前在程序的早期版本中一样，
as I was before in the earlier version of my program,
在检查s是否等于t的地方，的确是在比较s和t。
where I was checking if s equals equals t, I was, indeed, comparing s and t.
s和t是什么？
What are s and t?
s和t分别是0x123和0x456，
s and t, respectively, are 0x123 and 0x456,
或实际值是多少
or whatever the actual values happen to be,
这不会是相同的，因为它们发生了
which are not going to be the same because they happen
指向不同的内存块。
to point to different chunks of memory.
好吧，谁在乎？
All right, well who cares?
这是一种很好的智力练习。
This is all kind of a nice intellectual exercise.
但谁在乎？
But who cares?
那么，我们如何解决这个问题呢？
Well, how do we solve this problem?
让我们考虑一下我在上一个演示中的实际操作。
Let's consider what I actually did in a previous demo.
我有点抢先提到了这个功能，字符串比较，
I sort of preemptively mentioned that there's this function, string compare,
可以比较两个字符串。
that allows you to compare two strings.
我保证我们最终会解释
And I promised that we would eventually explain
为什么我们使用str compare而不是仅使用等号。
why we use str compare as opposed to just using the equal equal sign.
好吧，要使用此功能，我将需要添加
Well, to use this function, I'm going to need to add
大约每时每刻在string.h中。
in string.h up here per lat time.
但是，如果字符串比较st，让我继续进行重新编译，
But if string compare s t, let me go ahead and recompile this,
比较点斜线比较。
compare dots slash compare.
现在，让我输入HI！和嗨！同样。
Now, let me type HI! and HI! identically.
现在，它们似乎仍然不同。
Now, they still seem to be different.
该死的，我犯了和上次一样的愚蠢错误。
And dammit, I made the same stupid mistake as I did last time.
有谁知道我在比较两个字符串时犯了什么错误？
Does anyone know what mistake I made when comparing two strings?
我似乎以某种方式非常善于犯这个错误。
Somehow I seem to be very good at making this mistake.
布莱恩：易卜拉欣建议您添加一个相等的零。
BRIAN: Ibrahim is suggesting that you add an equal equal zero.
戴维·马兰：谢谢。
DAVID MALAN: Thank you.
易卜拉欣说得很对。
Ibrahim is quite right.
str比较的返回值，回想，
The return value, recall, of str compare,
如果相同，则返回0；如果相同，则返回负数
is to return 0 if they're the same, a negative number if one comes
在另一个之前，如果一个在另一个之后，则为正数，
before the other, and a positive number if one comes after the other,
如ASCIIbetical顺序。
as in ASCIIbetical order.
所以上次和这次我应该做的，
So what I should have done, both last time and this time,
是检查是否等于0。
is check for equality with 0.
让我继续并重新编译该程序。
Let me go ahead and recompile this program.
好好
OK, good.
现在，让我用HI重新运行该程序！
Now, let me rerun this program with HI!
两次。
twice.
瞧，他们是一样的。
Voila, they're the same.
只是为了确保，让我再做一次检查。
And just to make sure, let me do one other check.
让我来做大卫和布莱恩，这的确应该有所不同。
Let me do David and Brian, which should be, indeed, different.
因此，现在再说一次，我与上次没有做任何不同的事情。
So now, again, I haven't really done anything different from that last time.
但是我现在正在考虑这些字符串从根本上说只是
But I'm now thinking about these strings as being fundamentally just
他们的地址。
their addresses.
因此，现在，让我们将其与实际联系起来。
And so, now, let's make this actually germane.
让我继续创建一个新文件。
Let me go ahead and create a new file altogether.
并且，让我们相当合理地尝试复制一个字符串并对其进行更改。
And let's, pretty reasonably, try to copy one string and make changes to it.
所以我要在这里继续。
So I'm going to go ahead here.
为了方便起见，我将继续使用CS50库，
And just for convenience, I'm going to still use the CS50 library,
不是用于字符串数据类型，而是用于
not for the string data type, but just for the
获取字符串函数，我们将看到它比其他东西更方便-
get string function, which we'll see is more handy than other things--
比其他的做事方式。
than other ways of doing things.
我将继续介绍标准io点h。
And I'm going to go ahead and include standard io dot h.
我将继续介绍string.h。
And I'm going to go ahead and include, how about, string.h.
让我继续做int main void。
Let me go ahead and do int main void.
让我继续前进，在这个程序中，让自己成为一个字符串。
And let me go ahead, in this program, and get myself a string.
但是请注意，我们不再将其称为字符串。
But note, we won't call it string anymore.
我们就称它为char star。
We'll just call it char star.
因此，再次开始脱下训练轮。
So again, start taking off that training wheel.
我将继续获取名为s的字符串。
And I'm going to go ahead and get a string called s.
然后我将获得另一个字符串。
And then I'm going to get another string.
但我不会这样称呼。
But I won't call it that.
我称它为char star t。
I'll call it char star t.
我想复制s。
And I want to copy s.
因此，您可能会根据第一周，第二周以及自那以后的情况来考虑，
And so you might think, based on week one, week two, and since, that OK,
如果要复制变量，请执行此操作。
if you want to copy a variable, just do it.
我的意思是，我们使用了赋值运算符
I mean, we've used the assignment operator
将变量从右向左复制为整数，字符，
to copy a variable from right to left for integers, for chars,
对于其他数据类型，也许也是如此。
and for other data types, perhaps, too.
现在，我将继续进行操作，并对原始字符串进行更改。
I'm going to go ahead, now, and make a change to the original string.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续说，让我们更改t的第一个字符
Let me go ahead and say, let's change the first character of t
大写。
to be uppercase.
回想一下，上面有这个功能，
Recall that there's this function, to upper,
它接受一个字符（例如t中的第一个字符）作为输入，
which takes, as input, a character, like the first character in t,
并返回大写版本。
and returns the uppercase version.
现在，要使用上层，我需要另一个头文件，
Now, to use to upper, I need another header file,
我从几周前回想起，现在我需要ctype.h。
which I recall from a couple of weeks ago now, I need ctype.h.
因此，让我抢先回去，把它放在那里。
So let me preemptively go back and put that there.
现在，让我继续打印这两个字符串。
And now, let me go ahead and print these two strings.
让我继续打印s为该百分比s。
Let me go ahead and print out s as being this percent s.
让我继续，用百分比s打印出t的值，如下所示。
And let me go ahead and print out the value of t with percent s as follows.
再说一遍，我正在做的是从用户那里得到一个字符串。
So again, what I'm doing is I'm getting a string from the user.
今天唯一的新事物是char star，它是string的同义词。
And the only new thing here is char star today, which is synonymous with string.
在这里的第10行，我从右到左复制字符串。
On line 10 here, I'm copying the string from right to left.
然后我只大写第一个字母
And then I'm capitalizing only the first letter
在副本中，也称为t。
in the copy, otherwise known as t.
然后我只是将两者都打印出来。
And then I'm just printing both out.
因此，让我继续进行复制，然后编译即可。
So let me go ahead and make copy, compiles OK.
制作警察-点斜线副本。
Make cop-- dot slash copy.
让我继续输入嗨！小写，全部小写，
Let me go ahead and type in hi! in lowercase, all lowercase,
然后输入。
and then enter.
瞧，呵呵。
And voila, huh.
似乎我以某种方式将S和T都大写，即使我只是
It would seem that I somehow capitalized both S and T, even though I only
任何想法都吸引到T. Brian的追捧
called to upper on T. Brian, any thoughts
关于为什么我会意外和错误地大写的内容
from the group on why I've accidentally and erroneously capitalized
两者都以某种方式？
both somehow?
布莱恩：有人说t只是s的别名。
BRIAN: A couple of people are saying that t is just an alias of s.
DAVID MALAN：只是s的别名，这是对它的合理思考，
DAVID MALAN: Just an alias of s, that's a reasonable way of thinking of it,
当然。
sure.
更准确地说，还有其他关于为什么这是不正确的想法吗？
And more precisely, any other thoughts on why this is incorrect somehow?
布莱恩：彼得现在建议他们使用相同的地址。
BRIAN: Peter is now suggesting that they have the same address.
DAVID MALAN：是的，更具体地说，我所做的只是将s复制到t中。
DAVID MALAN: So yeah, more specifically, all I've done is copy s into t.
但是再说一遍，今天是什么？
But again, what is s as of today?
这只是一个地址。
It's just an address.
是的，我已经复制了。
So yes, I have copied s.
但是我已经按原样复制了它，这意味着复制了它的地址0x123，
But I've copied it literally, which means copying its address, 0x123,
或它是什么。
or whatever it is.
然后在第12行上，请注意我正在通过大写字母来更改t。
And then on line 12, notice that I'm changing t by uppercasing it.
但是t与s位于相同的地址。
But t is at the same address of s.
所以说真的，我要在同一字符串中更改一个。
So really, I'm changing one in the same string.
因此，如果我们以计算机的内存来考虑这一点，
So if we think about this in terms of the computer's memory,
让我们考虑一下我刚刚做了什么。
let's consider what I've just done.
让我清除计算机的内存。
Let me clear the computer's memory.
让我像以前一样放下心来。
Let me put s down as before.
我打招呼！像以前一样下降，但是这次全部小写。
Let me put hi! down as before, but all lowercase this time.
回想一下，它可能是地址0x123、124、125和126。
And recall that it might be it addresses 0x123, 124, 125, and 126.
现在，如果我们从技术上考虑
And now, if we consider that s technically
包含第一个字符的地址0x123，
contains the address of that first character, 0x123,
然后我继续创建一个新变量t并给t赋s的值，
and I proceed to create a new variable, t, and assign t the value of s,
我必须从字面上接受该声明。
I got to take that statement literally.
我实际上只是在这里放0x123。
I'm literally just putting 0x123 here.
如果我们现在将这些细节抽象出来
And if we now abstract away these details just
为了从视觉上更清楚地说明正在发生的事情，
to make it more clear visually what's going on,
这就像说s和t都一样
that's pretty much like saying that both s and t point
到内存中的相同位置。
to the same location in memory.
是的，从这个意义上讲，t只是s的别名，
So yes, in that sense, t is just an alias for s,
这是一种合理的思考方式。
which is a reasonable way of thinking of it.
但是实际上，只是t与s相同。
But really, just t is identical to s.
因此，当您使用方括号表示法时
So when you use the square bracket notation
转到t的第一个字符，您等效
to go to the first character of t, you are equivalently
转到s中的第一个字符。
going to the first character in s.
他们是一样的。
They are one in the same.
因此，当我呼叫鞋面时，我会在这个角色上呼叫它，这当然是
So when I call to upper, I'm calling it on this character, which of course, is
故事中唯一的一个。
the one and only h in the story.
当我打印s并打印t时，printf为
And when I print s and I print t, printf is
跟随那些面包屑，如果您愿意的话，
following those same breadcrumbs, if you will,
并最终显示与更改相同的值。
and ultimately displaying the same value as having changed.
因此，我们似乎需要从根本上重新考虑
So we would seem to need to fundamentally rethink
我们如何复制字符串。
how we are copying strings.
让我问一下，如果这是将一个字符串复制到另一个字符串的错误方法，那是什么
And let me ask, if this is the wrong way to copy one string into the other, what
是正确的方法吗？
is the right way?
即使您没有头脑中的功能或正确的词汇，
Even if you don't have the functions in mind or the right vocabulary,
只是直觉上，如果我们想以人类将要复制的方式
just intuitively, , if we want to copy a string in the way that a human would
想到将一个副本复制到另一个副本中，例如照片或影印本，
think of copying one into the other, like a photograph or a photocopy,
我们要如何做到这一点？
how do we want to do this?
有什么想法吗，布莱恩？
Any thoughts, Brian?
布莱恩：是的，索菲亚建议我们以某种方式进行循环
BRIAN: Yeah, Sophia suggested we would want to somehow loop over
s中的元素并将其放入t。
the elements in s and put them into t.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，我喜欢。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, I like that.
因此，循环遍历s的元素并将其放入t。
So loop over the elements of s and put them into t.
因此，这听起来需要更多工作。
So it sounds like more work.
但这又是我们将要拥有的
But that's, again, what we're going to have
如果我们想考虑这些-
to do if we want to think of these--
如果我们要接受一个事实，即s和t只是地址，
if we want to accept the fact that these things, s and t, are just addresses,
我们现在必须去追踪那些面包屑。
we're going to now have to go and follow those breadcrumbs.
因此，让我们继续考虑该程序的变体。
So let's go ahead and consider a variant of this program.
让我继续，在这里，更改它，使我仍然得到字符串s。
Let me go ahead, here, and change this such that I'm still getting a string s.
但是现在，让我继续提出确切的建议，
But now, let me go ahead and propose exactly that,
我们复制单个字符。
that we copy the individual characters.
但是我需要将它们复制到某个地方。
But I need to copy them somewhere.
所以我觉得这是复制字符串过程中的又一步
So I feel like another step in this process of copying a string
必须给自己一些额外的记忆。
has to be to give myself some additional memory.
如果我有n个感叹号，
If I have H i exclamation point in nul character,
我现在需要以某种方式控制这种情况
I need to, now, somehow take control of this situation
并以某种方式告诉计算机，再给我四个字节的内存
and tell the computer somehow, in code, give me four more bytes of memory
这样我就可以在其中复制这些字符的位置。
so that I have location for t in which to copy those characters.
因此，今天有一个新功能。
So here's a new function today.
如果我想创建一个字符串t（今天又称为字符星），
If I want to create a string t, otherwise known today as a char star,
我们可以使用一个名为malloc的新函数
there is a new function we can use called malloc, which
表示内存分配。
represents memory allocation.
幸运的是，这是一个非常漂亮的函数，非常易于使用。
This is a pretty fancy function that, fortunately, is pretty simple to use.
它仅需要一个数字作为输入。
It takes, as input, just a number.
您要向计算机请求多少字节的内存？
How many bytes of memory do you want to ask the computer for?
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do this?
好吧，我的感叹号为反斜杠0，我可以说四个。
Well, H i exclamation point backslash 0, I could literally just say four.
但这感觉并不动态。
But this doesn't feel very dynamic.
我想我可以以编程的方式更优雅地实现这一点。
I think I can programmatically implement this a little more elegantly.
让我继续说，给我尽可能多的字节
Let me go ahead and say, give me as many bytes
因为s中有字符加1。
as there are characters in s plus 1.
加1，为什么我要这样做？
Plus 1, why am I doing this?
好吧，我的感叹号是nul字符，从技术上讲
Well, H i exclamation point nul character, that's technically
存储在引擎盖下的东西。
what's stored underneath the hood.
但是您和我对Hi的长度有何看法？作为？
But what do you and I think of the length of Hi! as being?
好吧，在人类世界中，这很可能是我的感叹号。
Well, odds are, in the human world, it's H i exclamation point.
谁在乎这个低级的细节，这个nul终结者。
And who cares about this low level detail, this nul terminator.
您不要在英文单词或任何单词的长度中包含该单词。
You don't include that in the length of an English word or any word.
您只想到可以看到的实际字符。
You only think of the actual characters you can see.
因此，H的长度，我，感叹号3。
So the length of H, i, exclamation point 3.
但是我确实需要巧妙地为nul角色添加一口，第四口，
But I do need to cleverly add one more bite, a fourth, for the nul character,
因为我也必须将其复制过来。
because I'm going to have to copy that over as well.
否则，如果我没有相同的nul字符，
Otherwise, if I don't have an identical nul character,
t不会有明显的结局。
t is not going to have an obvious ending.
那么，现在如何将一个字符串复制到另一个字符串中？
So how do I copy, now, one string into the other?
好吧，让我继续前进，带走我们的老朋友for循环，
Well, let me go ahead and take out our old friend, the for loop,
从第一周开始。
from week one.
并说，因为我等于0-
And say, for i equals 0--
实际上，n等于s的字符串长度。
how about, actually, n equals string length of s.
我们以前做过这个技巧。
We've done this trick before.
我小于n，我++。
i is less than n, i++.
让我继续，很简单地说，说“括号i”得到“ s括号i”。
Let me go ahead and, quite simply, say t bracket i gets s bracket i.
因此，这将一次从s逐字复制每个字符
So this will literally copy, from s, each of the characters one at a time
到t
into t.
但是我现在需要变得更聪明。
But I need to be a little smarter now.
即使我们几乎总是使我小于n，
Even though we almost always do i less than n,
我实际上要非常积极地说我小于或等于n。
I'm actually going to very aggressively say i less than or equal to n.
为什么？
Why?
我为什么比我通常认为的要往前走一步
Why am I going one step further than I feel we normally
在遍历字符串时执行，比您更进一步
do when iterating over strings, and one step further than you
遍历凯撒密码或字符串时可能做过
probably did when iterating over a caesar cipher or a string
在那种情况下？
in that context?
布莱恩，这里有什么想法吗？
Brian, any thoughts here?
为什么我第一次从i小于或等于n开始？
Why am I going from i less than or equal to n kind of for the first time here?
布莱恩：西莉娜（Celina）建议我们将nul字符包括在内。
BRIAN: Celina is suggesting that we need to include the nul character.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，如果我-现在，我了解字符串的工作原理。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so if I-- and now I understand how strings works.
因此仅复制H，I，感叹号是不够的。
So it's not sufficient to just copy the H, I, exclamation point.
我需要更进一步，比字符串的长度还要多。
I need to go one step further, one more than the length of the string.
最简单的方法是小于或等于n。
And the easiest way to do that would be less than or equal to n.
或者我可以在那里做一个加号1。
Or I could just do a plus 1 there.
或者，我可以通过多种方法来执行此操作。
Or I can do this any number of ways.
没关系，怎么做。
Doesn't matter how you do it.
但是我认为小于或等于是这样做的一种合理方法。
But I think a less than or equal to is one reasonable way to do it.
现在，让我们深入到这里，现在
And now, let's go down to the bottom here and now actually
进行大写。
do this capitalization.
现在让我们更改t中的第一个字符
Let's now change the first character in t
是在t的第一个字符上调用upper的结果。
to be the result of calling to upper on the first character of t.
然后，像以前一样，让我们继续打印出s是什么。
And then, as before, let's go ahead and print out whatever s is.
和以前一样，让我们继续打印
And like before, let's go ahead and print out
不管t是什么，现在都希望只有t被大写。
whatever t is and hope now that only t has been capitalized.
但是，我现在确实需要进行一次更改。
But I do need to make one change now.
事实证明，该函数malloc来了
It turns out that this function, malloc, comes
在称为标准lib点h的文件中。
in a file called standard lib dot h.
同样，您可以在笔记中记下这种事情。
And again, this is the kind of thing that you can jot down in notes.
您可以随时通过Google进行此类操作。
You can always Google these kinds of things.
甚至我都忘记了有时会在这些头文件中声明这些函数。
Even I forget what header files these functions are sometimes declared in.
但这恰好是一个新的库，称为标准库
But it happens to be a new one called standard lib for library
这使您可以访问malloc。
that gives you access to malloc.
现在让我继续进行比较。
So let me go ahead, now, and make compare.
好的，到目前为止很好。
All right, so far so good.
点斜线比较-抱歉，这不是比较。
Dot slash compare-- sorry, this is not compare.
旧程序运行正常。
The old program works fine.
复印-哦，天哪，七个错误。
Make copy-- oh my god, seven mistakes.
我在这错了吗？
What'd I do wrong here?
哦，看来我忘记了i和n的类型。
Oh, it looks like I forgot the type of i and n.
因此，让我进入我的for循环并添加int。
So let me go into my for loop and add the int.
那是我的错让我再次复印。
That was my fault. Let me make copy again.
好的，幸运的是，所有七个错误都消失了。
OK, all seven errors, thankfully, went away.
进行复制，让我们继续并输入嗨！小写，然后按Enter。
Make copy, let's go ahead and type in hi! in lower case and hit Enter.
瞧，现在我只将s的副本大写，也就是
And voila, now I have capitalized only the copy of s, a.k.a.
t。
t.
为了清楚起见，我有点退缩了
And just to be clear, I've kind of regressed back
老实说，以我的方括号表示法，因为它是完全可以接受的。
to my square bracket notation, honestly, because it's perfectly acceptable.
这是非常可读的。
It's very readable.
但是请注意，如果我真的想炫耀，
But notice, if I really want to show off,
我可以说些类似的话，好吧，去t&#39;s plus i location。
I could say something like, well, go to t's plus i location.
然后，再次执行此操作，出于可读性考虑，我不一定会建议这样做。
And then do this, which again, I don't necessarily recommend for readability.
但是同样，这是等效的。
But again, there is this equivalence.
方括号表示法与指针算术相同。
The square bracket notation is the same thing as pointer arithmetic.
因此，如果您想前往位于t的地址加上我想抵消的任何金额
So if you want to go to the address at t plus whatever i is to offset yourself
一个或多个字节，您完全可以做到这一点。
one or more bytes, you can totally do that.
如果我想花哨的话，我可以去这里说：
And if I want to be fancy, I can go down here and say,
转到t的第一个字符并将其大写。
go to the first character in t and capitalize it.
但是我还是要说，即使，是的，你非常聪明
But again, I would argue that even though, yes, you're very clever
并且您现在了解了指针和地址
and that you understand pointers and addresses at this point
如果您正在编写这样的代码。
if you're writing code like this.
老实说，它不一定具有可读性。
Honestly, it's not necessarily as readable.
因此，完全坚持使用方括号表示法的第二周语法
So sticking with week two syntax of the square bracket notation, totally
合理，完全正确，完全精心设计，甚至可能更可取，
reasonable, totally correct, totally well-designed, and perhaps preferable,
虽然我在这里要小心
though I should be careful here.
这行代码对我来说有点冒险
This line of code is a little bit risky for me
因为如果用户只是按Enter键而他们没有键入hi怎么办
because what if the user just hits Enter and they don't type hi
或大卫或布莱恩。
or David or Brian.
如果他们只输入Enter，该怎么办？
What if they type nothing except Enter?
在这种情况下，字符串的长度可能为0。
In that case, the length of the string might be 0.
然后我可能不应该将第一个字符大写
And then I probably shouldn't capitalizing the first character
甚至根本不存在的字符串中。
in a string that doesn't really even exist.
所以我可能应该进行一些错误检查，
So I should probably have some error checking,
例如，如果t的字符串长度至少大于0，
like if, for instance, the string length of t is at least greater than 0,
然后继续并安全地执行此操作。
then go ahead and safely do that.
但是同样，这只是一些其他错误的例子
But again, this is just one example of some additional error
检查我可以添加到程序中。
checking I can add to the program.
实际上还有一个错误检查
There's actually one more piece of error checking
我真的应该在一个完全正确的程序中做，
I should really do in a fully correct program,
就像您应该在问题集中做的那样。
as you should do in problem sets.
有时情况可能会出错。
Sometimes things can go wrong.
而且如果您的程序太大，那么花哨，也很耗内存
And if your program is so big, so fancy, and so memory-hungry
您正在分配大量的内存，
that you're mallocing lots and lots of memory,
在这么小的程序中您不会做的，
which you won't do in the program this small,
但是随着时间的流逝，您可能需要越来越多的内存，
but over time you might need more and more memory,
我们还应确保t实际上具有有效地址。
we should also make sure that t actually has a valid address.
事实证明，在大多数情况下，malloc
It turns out that malloc, most of the time,
将返回给您的内存块的地址
is going to return to you the address of a chunk of memory
它已经为您分配了。
it has allocated for you.
就像获取字符串一样，它将返回给您
Just like get string, it will return to you
内存块的第一个字节的地址
the address of the first byte of the chunk of memory
它已经找到了空间。
that it has found space for.
但是，有时情况可能会出错。
However, sometimes things can go wrong.
有时您的计算机可能内存不足。
Sometimes your computer can be out of memory.
您可能已经看到Mac或PC冻结，挂起或自行重启。
You've probably seen your Mac or PC freeze or hang or reboot itself.
这通常是内存错误的结果。
That is very often the result of memory errors.
因此，我们实际上应该检查类似这样的内容。
So we should actually check something like this.
如果t等于这个特殊值nul，
If t equals equals this special value nul,
然后我将继续前进，纾困并归还，
then I'm going to go ahead and just bail out and return one,
退出，让我们退出程序。
quit, let's get out of the program.
这是行不通的。
It's not going to work.
这可能只发生一百万分之一。
This might only happen one out of a million times.
但是检查nul更正确。
But it's more correct to check for nul.
现在，不幸的是，C类的设计师还是程序员
Now, unfortunately, the designers of C kind of used-- or programmers
更笼统地说，使用这个词，与NUL几乎相同，
more generally, use this word, which is almost the same as N-U-L,
否则称为反斜杠0。
otherwise known as backslash 0.
不幸的是，这是一个不同的值。
Unfortunately, this is a different value.
NULL表示空指针。
N-U-L-L represents a nul pointer.
这是假地址。
It is a bogus address.
这是没有地址。
It is the absence of an address.
从技术上讲，其地址为0。
Technically, its address 0.
它与反斜杠0不同。
It is different from backslash 0.
就像我们今天所做的那样，您可以在指针的上下文中使用NULL。
You use N-U-L-L in the context of pointers, as we are doing today.
您使用反斜杠0，否则在口头上会知道，
You use backslash 0, otherwise known verbally,
在字符上下文中为NUL或nul。
as an N-U-L, or nul, in the context of characters.
因此，反斜杠0用于字符。
So backslash 0 is for characters.
所有大写中的NULL用于指针。
N-U-L-L in all caps is for pointers.
这只是我们今天要介绍的新符号
And it's just a new symbol we're introducing today
这个标准的lib dot h文件附带的文件。
that comes with this standard lib dot h file.
好的，事实证明，我不需要做一些这项工作。
All right, so it turns out, honestly, I don't need to do some of this work.
原来，如果我想将一个字符串复制到另一个字符串，
It turns out that if I want to copy one string to another,
有一个功能。
there is a function for that.
而且，您将不必编写太多的代码行
And increasingly, you will not have to write as many lines of code
就像以前一样，因为如果您在手册页中查找
as you previously did, because if you look up in the manual pages
或者您已经听说或在线找到了另一个功能，例如一个
or you've heard about or find online that there's another function, like one
实际上，您可以更简单地执行名为strcpy的类似操作。
called strcpy, you can actually, more simply, do something like this.
因此，即使我真的很喜欢这个主意，并且使用for循环也是正确的
So even though I really liked the idea, and it was correct to use a for loop
要将s中的所有字符复制到t中，有一个功能。
to copy all of the characters from s into t, there's a function for that.
叫做strcpy。
It's called strcpy.
它有两个参数，目的地，后跟源。
It takes two arguments, the destination followed by the source.
而且它将处理所有循环
And it will just handle all of the looping
对我们来说，所有对我们的复制，包括反斜杠0，
for us, all of the copying for us, including the backslash 0,
这样我就可以专注于自己想做的事情，在这种情况下，
so that I can focus on what I want to do, which in this case,
实际上是大写东西。
is actually capitalize things.
因此，如果我们现在考虑这个示例，在我的计算机内存中，
So if we consider, now, this example, in the context of my computer's memory,
我们会看到它的布局有些不同。
we'll see that it's laid out a little differently.
但是，我还想再修复一个错误。
But there's one more bug I do want to fix first.
这是我们尚未要做的事情。
And this is something we've not had to do yet.
事实证明，每当您使用malloc分配内存时，
It turns out that any time you allocate memory with malloc,
您要求计算机提供内存，程序员，您的责任就在您身上，
you ask the computer for memory, the onus is on you, the programmer,
最终将其还给。
to eventually give it back.
我的意思是，如果您分配四个字节，
And by that, I mean if you allocate four bytes,
或谁知道，400万字节的内存用于更大的程序，
or who knows, four million bytes of memory for an even bigger program,
您最好将其还给计算机，更具体地说，
you'd better give it back to the computer, more specifically,
操作系统，无论是Linux还是Mac OS或Windows，
the operating system, be it Linux or Mac OS or Windows,
这样您的计算机最终不会耗尽内存。
so that your computer eventually doesn't run out of memory.
如果您所要做的只是请求更多的内存，请请求更多的内存，
If all you ever do is ask for more memory, ask for more memory,
可以说最终您的计算机将耗尽，这是有原因的，因为
it stands to reason that eventually your computer will run out, because it only
具有有限的内存。
has a finite amount of memory.
它有一定数量的硬件召回。
It's got a finite amount of hardware recall.
因此，当您完成记忆后，这应该是您的最佳做法
So when you're done with memory, it should be your best practice
以后再释放它。
to free it afterward as well.
与malloc相反，它只是一个名为free的函数，它需要
And the opposite of malloc is just a function called free, which takes,
作为其输入，无论malloc的输出是什么。
as its input, whatever the output of malloc was.
并回想一下malloc的输出，malloc的返回值，
And recall that the output of malloc, the return value of malloc,
只是它已为您分配的内存的第一个字节的地址。
is just the address of the first byte of memory that it has allocated for you.
因此，如果您要求它提供四个字节，就像我几年前对malloc所做的那样，
So if you ask it for four bytes, like I did a few lines ago with malloc,
您将取回那些字节中第一个字节的地址。
you're going to get back the address of the first of those bytes.
而且，您要记住所要求的字节数。
And it's up to you to remember how many bytes you asked for.
在免费的情况下，您要做的就是
In the case of free, all you have to do is
通过其输入免费告诉malloc给您的地址是什么。
tell free via its input what the address was that malloc gave you.
因此，如果您像我一样存储该地址，则在名为t的变量中，
So if you stored that address as I did, in this variable called t,
当您用完称为free t的内存后，就足够了。
it suffices when you're done with that memory just called free t.
然后计算机将为您释放该内存。
And the computer will go about freeing up that memory for you.
而且，您很可能稍后再找回它。
And you might very well get it back later on.
但是至少您的计算机不会耗尽内存
But at least your computer won't run out of memory
速度很快，因为它现在可以将该空间重用于其他用途。
as quickly, because it can now reuse that space for something else.
好吧，让我继续，然后提出
All right, let me go ahead, then, and propose
我们为此画一幅图-
that we draw a picture of this--
现在是新程序的内存，我们可以在其中复制内容。
now new program's memory, where we copy things.
所以回想一下，这是我们在比较两个字符串之前停止的地方。
So recall, this is where we left off before when comparing two strings.
如果这是s并且s指向h，即小写的感叹号，
If this was s and s was pointing to h, i, exclamation point in lowercase,
我在copy.c中的新版本代码，请注意，
this new version of my code in copy.c, notice,
仍然给了我另一个指针t。
still gives me another pointer called t.
因此，故事的那一部分没有改变。
So that part of the story hasn't changed.
但是我现在叫malloc。
But I call malloc now.
而malloc将返回给我一些新的内存。
And malloc is going to return to me some new chunk of memory.
我事先不知道它在哪里。
I don't know in advance where it is.
但是malloc的返回值将是地址
But malloc's return value is going to be the address
该记忆的第一口。
of the first bite of that memory.
因此，例如0x456或其他值。
So for instance, 0x456 or whatever it is.
随后的字节将增加一个
And the subsequent bytes are going to be increasing by one
一次为0x457、0x458、0x459。
byte at a time, 0x457, 0x458, 0x459.
那么，当我为其分配malloc的返回值时，最终存储在t中的是什么？
So what is, ultimately, stored in t when I assign it the return value of malloc?
不管那个地址是什么。
It's whatever that address is.
再次，我可以从技术上在这里写0x456。
Again, I could technically write 0x456 up here.
但同样，我们有点过去了。
But again, we're kind of past that.
那是30分钟前。
That's very 30 minutes ago.
现在，让我们仅关注作为指针的抽象。
Let's now focus on just the abstraction that is a pointer.
指针只是从变量指向的箭头
A pointer is just an arrow pointing from the variable
到内存中的实际位置。
to the actual location in memory.
所以现在，如果我打算使用strcpy或更手动地将s复制到t中，
So now, if I go about copying s into t using strcpy, or more manually,
使用我的for循环，会发生什么？
using my for loop, what happens?
好吧，我正在将h从s复制到t。
Well, I'm copying the h over from s into t.
我要将i从s复制到t，将感叹号从s复制到t。
I'm copying the i over from s into t, the exclamation point from s into t.
最后，从n到t的终止nul字符。
And then lastly, the terminating nul character from s into t.
因此，情况现在根本不同了。
So the picture is now fundamentally different.
t指的不是同一件事。
t is not pointing at the same thing.
它指向的是自己的内存块，一次只有一步，
It's pointing at its own chunk of memory that has now, one step at a time,
一直在复制地址s上的内容。
been duplicating whatever was at the address s.
因此，这就是您和我作为人类所考虑的，大概是，
And so this is what you and I as humans would consider, presumably,
成为程序的正确副本。
to be a proper copy of the program.
那么，对引入malloc和free所做的事情有任何疑问吗？
Any questions, then, on what we've just done by introducing malloc and free?
第一个分配内存并为您提供
The first of which allocates memory and gives you
您现在可以使用的内存的第一个字节的地址，
the address of the first byte of memory that you can now use,
后者会将其交给您的操作系统，并说：
the latter of which hands it back to your operating system and says,
我已经完成了。
I'm done with this.
现在可以将其重用于其他变量，其他变量，
It can now be reused for something else, some other variable,
也许，如果我们的程序更长的话，在路上。
maybe, down the road, if our program were longer.
布莱恩，有什么问题或困惑可以帮助您吗？
Brian, any questions or confusion I can help with?
布莱恩：有人问，即使您使用的是strcpy
BRIAN: Someone asked, even if you're using strcpy
复制字符串，而不是一次复制一个字符，
to copy the string instead of copying the characters one at a time yourself,
您还需要释放内存吗？
do you still need to free the memory?
戴维·马兰：好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Good question.
即使您使用的是strcpy，您仍然需要免费使用。
Even if you're using strcpy, you do need to still use free.
是的，此后任何时候使用malloc都必须使用free。
Yes, anytime you use malloc henceforth, you must use free.
每次使用malloc时，都必须使用free来释放该内存。
Anytime you use malloc, you must use free in order to free up that memory.
strcpy正在将一个内存块的内容复制到另一个。
strcpy is copying the contents of one chunk of memory to the other.
它不是为您分配或管理该内存。
It is not allocating or managing that memory for you.
本质上，它只是在实现for循环。
It is just implementing, essentially, that for loop.
也许也是时候，我可以脱下另一个训练轮了
And it's, perhaps, time too, where I can take off another training wheel
口头上
verbally.
事实证明，一直以来获取字符串都是一种神奇。
It turns out that get string, all this time, is kind of magical.
从CS50库获取字符串的事情之一
One of the things that get string does from the CS50 library
它本身是否使用malloc。
is it itself uses malloc.
毕竟，考虑一下，当我们员工几年前写成字符串时，
Consider, after all, when we, the staff, wrote get string years ago,
我们不知道您的名字今年要待多久。
we have no idea how long your names are going to be this year.
我们不知道你要说什么句子
We have no idea what sentences you're going
键入，要键入的段落，要分析的文本
to type, what paragraphs you're going to type, what text you're going to analyze
对于像可读性这样的程序。
for a program like readability.
所以我们必须以这种方式实现get string
So we had to implement get string in such a way
您可以在键盘上输入的字符数可以少或多
that you can type as few or as many characters at your keyboard
如你所愿。
as you want.
并且我们将确保该字符串有足够的内存。
And we will make sure there's enough memory for that string.
因此，在引擎盖下获取字符串，如果您看一下我们，员工的代码，
So get string, underneath the hood, if you look at the code we, the staff,
有一天写了，您会看到我们使用了malloc。
wrote someday, you'll see that we use malloc.
我们调用malloc以获得足够的内存以适合该字符串。
And we call malloc in order to get enough memory to fit that string.
然后，CS50库也在暗中进行操作，
And then, what the CS50 library is also secretly doing,
它也为您免费打电话吗？
is it is also calling free for you.
从本质上讲，有一种奇特的方式
There's, essentially, a fancy way where you
可以编写一个程序，一旦main将要退出或返回
can write a program that, as soon as main is about to quit or return
闪烁的提示，一些特殊的代码
to your blinking prompt, some special code
我们在最后一刻写了很多东西，释放了所有的记忆
we wrote swoops in at that final moment, frees any of the memory
我们图书馆分配给您
that we, the library, allocated so that you
不要因为我们而耗尽内存。
don't run out of memory because of us.
但是你们所有人在使用malloc时都会拥有
But you all, when using malloc, will have
拨打免费电话，因为图书馆不会为您做到这一点。
to call free, because the library is not going to do that for you.
实际上，今天和下周及以后的目标
And indeed, the goal of today and next week and beyond
最终将完全停止使用CS50库。
is to stop using the CS50 library, ultimately, altogether.
好吧，好吧-我认为这将是不公平的，
All right, well let's-- it would be unfair, I think,
如果我们引入了所有这些新颖的技术，但不一定
if we introduced all of these fancy new techniques but don't necessarily
为您提供确定跟踪错误的各种工具
provide you with any sort of tools with which to determine to chase down bugs
现在，使用新的精美代码或解决问题，
in your new fancy code or solve problems, now,
与记忆有关。
that are related to memory.
值得庆幸的是，有一些程序可以通过
And thankfully, there are programs via which
您可以追查与内存相关的错误。
you can chase down memory-related bugs.
这是除了printf之外的功能，
This is in addition to printf, that function,
以及更常见的help50和check50以及debug50和调试器。
and help50 and check50 and debug50 and debuggers more generally.
该程序-这实际上是我们将向您介绍的新工具中的最后一个
This program-- and it's really the last of the new tools we'll introduce you
C中的to称为valgrind。
to in C-- is called valgrind.
这是CS50 IDE中存在的程序。
And this is a program that exists in CS50 IDE.
但它存在于Mac，PC和Linux计算机上
But it exists on Macs and PC's and Linux computers
任何地方，您都可以在自己的代码上运行它
anywhere, where you can run it on your own code
来检测您的内存是否有问题。
to detect if you're doing anything wrong with memory.
您可能会在内存上做错什么？
What might you do wrong with memory?
好吧，以前，请记住，我触发了该细分错误。
Well, previously, remember, I triggered that segmentation fault.
我感动了我不应该的记忆。
I touched memory that I should not.
Valgrind是可以帮助您找出问题的工具，
Valgrind is a tool that can help you figure out,
您在哪里接触了本不应该拥有的记忆，
where did you touch memory that you shouldn't have,
以便将您自己的注意力集中在任何代码行上
so as to focus your own human attention on whatever lines of code
可能是越野车。
might be buggy.
Valgrind Grant还可以检测您是否忘记免费拨打电话。
Valgrind grant can also detect if you forget to call free.
如果您多次调用malloc，但不免费
If you call malloc one or more times, but don't call free
相应的次数，valgrind
a corresponding number of times, valgrind
是一个可以注意到并告诉您您有
is a program that can notice that and tell you that you have
所谓的内存泄漏。
what's called a memory leak.
实际上，这与我们自己的Mac和PC有密切关系。
And indeed, this is germane to our own Macs and PCs.
同样，如果您使用的是Mac或PC，有时
Again, if you've been using your Mac or PC or sometimes
甚至很长一段时间，甚至您的手机
even your phone for a long, long time, and maybe
一次运行许多不同的程序，许多浏览器选项卡
running lots of different programs at once, lots of browser tabs
打开，许多不同的程序同时打开，
open, lots of different programs open at once,
您的Mac或PC可能已经开始缓慢地爬行。
your Mac or PC might very well have begun to slow to a crawl.
如果不是不可能的话，可能会很烦人，
It might be annoying, if not impossible to use,
因为一切都太慢了。
because everything is so darn slow.
那很可能是因为您正在使用的一个或多个程序
That may very well be because one or more of the programs you're using
有一个错误，程序员可以不断分配内存
has some bug in it whereby a programmer kept allocating memory
从来没有绕过免费电话。
and never got around to calling free.
也许是一个错误，也许是故意的，
Maybe it's a bug, maybe it was deliberate,
他们没想到你会打开这么多窗户。
they didn't expect you to have so many windows open.
但是valgrind可以检测到这样的错误。
But valgrind can detect errors like that.
老实说，你们中的一些人，如果您像我一样，
And honestly, some of you, if you're like me,
您很可能会同时打开10、20、50个不同的浏览器标签，
you might very well have 10, 20, 50 different browser tabs open at once,
想着哦，即使我们从不这样做，我还是有一天会回到那一天。
thinking oh, I'm going to come back to that someday, even though we never do.
这些选项卡中的每一个都占用内存。
Each of those tabs takes up memory.
从字面上看，每当您打开浏览器标签时，都要想一想，
Literally, any time you open a browser tab, think of it,
确实如此，例如Chrome或Edge或Firefox或其他任何形式
really, as Chrome or Edge or Firefox or whatever
你在用引擎盖下的东西
you're using, underneath the hood, they're
可能在Mac OS或Windows上调用了一个函数
probably calling a function on Mac OS or Windows
像malloc这样可以给您更多的内存来包含该网页的内容
like malloc to give you more memory to contain the contents of that web page
暂时地。
temporarily.
而且，如果您继续打开越来越多的浏览器标签，
And if you keep opening more and more browser tabs,
这就像调用malloc，malloc，malloc。
it's like calling malloc, malloc, malloc.
最终，您将用光。
Eventually, you're going to run out.
这些天，计算机可以变得很聪明。
And computers can be smart these days.
他们可以暂时从内存中删除内容以释放空间。
They can kind of temporarily remove things from memory to free up space.
这称为虚拟内存。
This is called virtual memory.
但是最终，某些事情将会崩溃。
But eventually, something is going to break.
这很可能是您的用户体验
And it might very well be your user experience
当事情变得如此缓慢以至于您不得不退出程序时
when things get so slow that you literally have to quit the program
甚至重启计算机。
or maybe even reboot your computer.
那么我们如何使用valgrind？
So how do we use valgrind?
好吧，让我继续写一个简短的程序
Well, let me go ahead and write a short program
并没有做任何有用的事，但是证明了
that doesn't do anything useful, but demonstrates
与内存相关的多个错误。
multiple memory-related mistakes.
我称这个文件为memory.c。
I'll call this file memory.c.
我要继续打开文件memory.c
I'm going to go ahead and open up the file memory.c
并包括在最高标准的io点h上。
and include at the top standard io dot h.
然后我要先发制人
And then I'm going to also, preemptively,
包括标准的lib点h，它可以回想malloc，int main void在哪里。
include standard lib dot h, which recalls where malloc, int main void.
我将保持这一简单。
And I'm going to keep this one simple.
我要继续，只给自己一堆整数。
I'm going to go ahead and just give myself a whole bunch of integer.
因此，这实际上很酷。
So this is actually kind of cool.
事实证明-
It turns out that--
好吧，让我们继续吧。
well, let's go ahead.
是的，我可以做到。
Yeah, I can do this.
让我们继续执行此操作。
Let's go ahead and do this.
字符星获取malloc。
Char star s gets malloc.
让我继续前进，给我自己，这三个呢。
And let me go ahead and give myself, how about three of these.
让我继续，为三个字符分配空间。
Let me go ahead and allocate space for three chars.
或者实际上，像以前一样，让我给我四个。
Or actually, let's give me four, just like before.
现在，我要说s的括号0等于72。
Now, I'm going to go ahead and say s bracket 0 equals 72.
s支架1 –实际上，我将手动执行此操作。
s bracket 1-- actually, I'll just do this manually.
让我们做吧。
Let's do h.
我来吧
Let's do i.
让我们做我们通常的感叹号。
Let's do our usual exclamation point.
然后只是出于很好的考虑，s支架3得到了
And then just for good measure, s bracket 3 gets
引用取消引用，反斜杠0。
quote unquote, backslash 0.
这实际上是一种非常手动的方式-
This is the very manual way of actually--
这是实际构建字符串的非常手动的方法。
this is the very manual way of actually building up a string.
但是，让我介绍一个错误。
But let me introduce a mistake.
我不小心分配了三个字节，
Let me accidentally allocate only three bytes,
即使我显然需要四分之一的终止nul字符。
even though I clearly need a fourth for that terminating nul character.
还要注意，缺少免费。
And notice too, the absence of free.
我会很草率地打扰，免费打扰。
I'm going to, very sloppily, not bother calling free.
现在，我将继续编译该程序，创建内存。
Now, I'm going to go ahead and compile this program, make memory.
OK，它会编译OK，所以很好，点斜杠内存。
OK, it compiles OK, so that's good, dot slash memory.
好吧，什么也没发生，但是那种
OK, nothing happens, but that kind of makes
有道理，因为我没有告诉它做任何事情。
sense because I didn't tell it to do anything.
只是为了踢球，让我们像往常一样打印出该字符串。
Just for kicks, let's print out that string just like we always do.
现在让我重新编译内存，然后继续编译。
Let me now recompile memory, still compiles.
让我运行点斜杠内存。
Let me run dot slash memory.
好的，这似乎可行。
OK, it seems to work.
因此，乍一看，您可能会为自己感到骄傲。
So at first glance, you might be really proud of yourself.
您编写了另一个正确的程序，似乎通过了check50。
You've written another correct program, seems to pass check50.
您提交。
You submit.
你忙得不亦乐乎。
You go about your day.
几天后你很失望
And you're very disappointed some days later
当你意识到，该死的时候，我没有得到充分的认可，因为
when you realize, dammit, I did not get full credit on this because there's
实际上是一个潜在的错误。
actually a latent bug.
所以有时候确实在您的代码中有错误
So sometimes, indeed, there are bugs in your code
你不一定要看得见，你不一定
that you don't necessarily see visually, you don't necessarily
自己运行时的经验，但最终在那里
experience when running it yourself, but eventually, there
运行足够的时间可能是一个错误。
might be an error when running it enough times.
最终，计算机可能会注意到您做错了什么。
Eventually, a computer might notice that you're doing something wrong.
值得庆幸的是，存在像valgrind这样的工具，
And thankfully, tools exist like valgrind,
可以让您检测到。
that can allow you to detect that.
因此，让我继续前进，只需在此处增加终端窗口的大小即可。
So let me go ahead and just increase the size of my terminal window here.
让我继续，在点斜杠内存上运行valgrind。
And let me go ahead and run valgrind on dot slash memory.
因此，这就像debug50。
So it's just like debug50.
不用运行debug50然后使用斜杠来表示任何程序，
Instead of running debug50 and then dot slash whatever the program is,
您运行valgrind点斜杠内存。
you run valgrind dot slash memory.
不幸的是，这只是一个命令行界面。
This one, unfortunately, is only a command line interface.
没有像debug50这样的图形用户界面。
There's no graphical user interface like debug50.
老实说，这是一个令人毛骨悚然的输出序列。
And honestly, it's a hideous sequence of output.
乍一看，这应该会让您不知所措。
This should overwhelm you at first glance.
这里有疯狂的神秘感。
There's crazy cryptic-ness here.
这不是设计最好的程序。
It's not the best-designed program.
它确实是为最舒适的人准备的。
It really was meant for the most comfortable people.
但是我们可以摆脱一些有用的花招。
But there are some useful tidbits we can take away from it.
一如既往，让我一直展示到顶部
As always, let me show all the way to the top
到输出的第一行。
to the very first line of output.
我会提请您注意以下几点
And I'll draw your attention to a couple of things
那将开始跳到你身边。
that will start to jump out to you.
并且help50可以帮助您。
And help50 can help you with this.
如果您对valgrind的输出感到困惑，请重新运行它。
If you're confused by valgrind's output, rerun it.
但是请在开始时使用help50。
But put help50 at the beginning.
就像我现在将口头上做的一样，可以提供帮助50
And just like I will do now verbally, so can help50
帮助您注意到这种疯狂的输出混乱中的重要事项。
help you notice the important things in this crazy mess of output.
这太令人担忧了。
This is worrisome.
Valgrind在此注意这一点，大小为1的无效权限。
Valgrind is noting on this line here, invalid right of size 1.
那是在memory.c的第10行上。
And that's on line 10 of memory.c.
因此，我们稍后再讨论。
So we'll look at that in a moment.
如果我进一步向下滚动，则读取的大小为1。
If I scroll down further, invalid read of size 1.
这似乎也出现在了memory.c的第11行上。
And that also seems to be on here, it looks like, on line 11 of memory.c.
然后如果我继续滚动，继续滚动，继续滚动，
And then if I keep scrolling, keep scrolling, keep scrolling,
我不喜欢这个
I'm not liking this.
不管是什么，在丢失记录中肯定会丢失1个块中的3个字节。
3 bytes in 1 blocks are definitely lost in loss record, whatever that is.
但是肯定会丢失1个块中的三个字节。
But three bytes in 1 blocks are definitely lost.
然后在这里，泄漏摘要，肯定会丢失，共1个块3个字节。
And then down here, leak summary, definitely lost, 3 bytes in 1 blocks.
顺便说一句，显然语法不正确。
Incidentally, 1 blocks, obviously not correct grammar.
这是当您的程序不执行时会发生的情况
This is what happens when your program doesn't
具有if条件，用于检查数字是1还是正数或0。
have an if condition that checks if the number is 1 or positive or 0.
您可以使用简单的if条件在语法上诚实地解决此问题。
You could fix this, grammatically, honestly, with a simple if condition.
他们几年前写这个程序时还没有。
They did not when writing this program years ago.
所以这里有两个或三个错误。
So there's two or three mistakes here.
一种是某种无效的读取或写入。
One is some kind of invalid read or write.
另一个是这种泄漏。
And another is this leak.
那么，什么是写？
Well, what is a write?
写只是指更改值。
A write just refers to changing a value.
只读只是指读取或使用或打印值。
A read just refers to reading or using or printing a value.
因此，让我们关注第10行。
So let's focus on line 10.
如果我向下滚动到我的代码并看第10行，
If I scroll back down to my code and look on line 10,
这是无效的写入，无效的写入。
this was an invalid write, invalid write.
好吧，为什么它无效？
Well, why is it invalid?
好吧，按照今天的定义，如果您要分配3个字节，
Well, per today's definition, if you are allocating 3 bytes,
欢迎您触摸第一个字节，第二个字节和第三个字节。
you are welcome to touch the first byte, the second byte, and the third byte.
但是你没事碰第四个字节
But you have no business touching the fourth byte
如果您只要求三个。
if you've only asked for three.
这就像是一个小规模的版本，非常冒险且不合适
This is like a small scale version of the very adventurous and inappropriate
当我看着10,000字节远时，我就在附近闲逛。
poking around I did when I looked at 10,000 bytes away.
甚至看一个字节都是一个潜在的错误
Even looking one byte away is a potential bug
并可能导致程序崩溃。
and can cause a program to crash.
同时，第11行也有问题，
Meanwhile, line 11 is also problematic, which
是无效的读取，因为现在，您要说去打印出此字符串。
is an invalid read, because now, you're saying go print out this string.
但是那个字符串包含一个内存地址
But that string contains a memory address
首先您不应该碰触到。
that you should not have touched in the first place.
而内存泄漏，第三个问题，是由于事实
And the memory leak, the third problem, stems from the fact
我没有释放那段记忆。
that I didn't free that memory.
同样，这需要一些实践和经验，一些自己的错误，
So again, it'll take some practice and experience, some mistakes of your own,
注意并理解这些错误。
to notice and understand these bugs.
但是，让我这样修复前两个问题。
But let me fix the first two like this.
让我给自己四个字节。
Let me just give myself four bytes.
然后让我修复第二个或第三个问题，
And let me fix the second one or the third one,
确实，通过在最后释放s来完成，因为再一次，无论何时您使用malloc
really, by freeing s at the very end, because again, any time you use malloc
您必须免费使用。
you must use free.
让我继续并重新编译内存，似乎可以编译。
Let me go ahead and recompile memory, seems to compile.
让我重新运行它，仍然在视觉上保持不变。
Let me rerun it, still works the same, visually.
但是现在，让我们在上面重新运行valgrind，看看现在是否有任何错误，
But now, let's rerun valgrind on it and see if there are any errors now,
所以valgrind点斜线记忆，回车。
so valgrind dot slash memory, Enter.
输出看起来仍然很神秘。
The output's still going to look pretty cryptic.
但是请注意，无论这意味着什么，所有堆块都已释放。
But notice all heap blocks were freed, whatever that means.
没有泄漏是可能的。
No leaks are possible.
确实没有比这更明确的了。
It doesn't really get more explicit than that.
这是好事。
That's a good thing.
而且，如果我向上滚动，将看不到那些无效的读写操作。
And if I scroll up, I see no mention of those invalid reads or writes.
因此，从本周的问题和下周的C语言开始，
So starting with this week's problems and next week's in C,
您不仅要使用工具
not only are you going to want to use tools
例如help50和printf以及debug50和check50，
like help50 and printf and debug50 and check50,
但是即使您认为您的代码正确，输出看起来也正确，
but even if you think your code's right, the output looks right,
您可能有一个潜在的错误。
you might have a latent bug.
即使您的程序很小，它们也可能不会使计算机崩溃。
And even when your programs are small, they might not crash the computer.
它们可能不会导致该分段错误。最终，他们会的。
They might not cause that segmentation fault. Eventually, they will.
而且您确实想使用这样的工具来消除任何此类错误。
And you do want to use tools like this to chase down any such mistakes.
否则，可能会发生不好的事情。
Otherwise, bad things can happen.
会发生什么？
And what might happen?
好吧，让我继续在这里展示一个例子
Well, let me go ahead and reveal an example here
所提供的代码有些危险。
that presents some code that's a little dangerous.
因此，例如，这里是一个示例
So here, for instance, is an example where
我在函数顶部声明了int star x和int star y。
I'm declaring at the top of the function, int star x and int star y.
那是什么意思呢？
So what does that mean?
好吧，按照今天的说法，这意味着给我
Well, per today's parlance, this just means give me
指向x的整数的指针。
a pointer to an integer called x.
给我一个指向y的整数的指针。
Give me a pointer to an integer called y.
换句话说，给我一个叫做x的变量
Put another way, give me a variable called x that I
可以存储int的地址。
can store the address of an int in.
给我一个名为y的变量，我可以在其中存储另一个int的地址。
Give me a variable called y that I can store the address of another int in.
但是请注意我在前两行中没有做的事情。
But notice what I am not doing on these first two lines.
直到第3行，我才真正给它们赋值。
I'm not actually assigning them a value until line 3.
在第3行上，即使这很奇怪-这也不是我们分配空间的方式
On line 3, even though this is weird-- this is not how we've allocated space
对于之前的整数-
for integers before--
没有理由不能使用malloc
there's no reason that you can't use malloc
并说给我足够的空间来容纳一个整数。
and say, give me enough space for the size of an integer.
sizeof是新的。
sizeof is new.
只是C语言中的一个运算符，它告诉您数据类型的大小，
It's just an operator in C that tells you the size of a data type,
就像一个int的大小一样。
like a size of an int.
所以也许您忘记了int是4。
So maybe you forgot that an int is 4.
实际上，在所有系统中，int通常为4，但并不总是4。
And indeed, an int is usually 4, but not always 4 in all systems.
所以int的大小只是确保它始终会为您提供正确的答案，
So size of int just makes sure that it will always give you the right answer,
无论您使用的是现代计算机还是旧计算机。
whether you're using a modern computer or an old one.
因此，这实际上意味着在现代系统上为我分配4个字节。
So this just means, really, allocate 4 bytes to me on a modern system.
并将第一个字节的地址存储在x中。
And it stores the address of the first byte in x.
有人介意翻译成外行的术语吗？
Would someone mind translating to layman's terms, what
恒星x等于42在做什么？
is star x equal 42 doing?
同样，Star是取消引用运算符。
Star, again, is the dereference operator.
意思是去那个地址。
It means go to the address.
怎么办？
And do what?
您如何用口头评论来描述，
How would you describe, with a verbal comment,
x等于42的恒星在做什么？
what star x equals 42 is doing?
布莱恩，您介意表达任何想法吗？
Brian, would you mind verbalizing any thoughts?
布莱恩：是的，所以索菲亚建议在那个地址上，我们将放置42。
BRIAN: Yeah, so Sophia suggested that at that address, we are going to place 42.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
在该地址放42。
At that address put 42.
同样，转到x中的该地址并将数字42放在此处。
Equivalently, go to that address in x and put the number 42 there.
就像去Brian的邮箱并将42放入他的邮箱，
It's like going to Brian's mailbox and putting the 42 in his mailbox,
而不是我们以前在那里的数字50。
instead of what we previously had there, which was the number 50.
接下来的第五行，星y等于13呢？
How about this next fifth line, star y equals 13?
布莱恩，你能说给别人听吗？
Brian, could you verbalize someone else?
y等于13的恒星对我们有什么作用？
What does star y equals 13 do for us?
13倒霉并不是偶然的。
And it's not an accident that 13 tends to be unlucky.
布莱恩：彼得说，在地址y处输入13。
BRIAN: Peter says, put 13 at the address y.
DAVID MALAN：好的，在y的地址中输入13。
DAVID MALAN: Good, put 13 at the address in y.
或者换种方式，转到y中的地址，然后在其中放置13。
Or put another way, go to the address in y and put 13 there.
但是这里有一个逻辑问题。
But there's a logical problem here.
y是什么？
What is in y?
如果倒带，则实际上不会分配ya值。
If I rewind, I never actually assign y a value.
我一开始就没有，最终也没有。
I don't initially, and I don't eventually.
至少使用x，即使我在此处声明它时没有给它一个值
At least with x, even though I didn't give it a value in declaring it up here
作为变量，我最终设法将实际地址存储在其中。
as a variable, I eventually got around to storing in it the actual address.
现在，为了真正挑剔，我可能甚至应该在该程序中
Now, just to be really nit picky, I should probably even, in this program,
检查nul，以防万一出问题了。
check for nul just in case anything went wrong.
但这是另一个问题。
But that's a whole other problem.
这是一个更加令人发指的问题，我什至没有重视。
It is a more damning problem that I haven't even given y a value.
这是我们可以揭示有关计算机的其他详细信息的地方。
And here's where we can reveal one other detail about a computer.
到目前为止，我们一直认为您和我几乎总是初始化
Thus far, we've been taking for granted that you and I almost always initialize
我们的记忆。
our memory.
如果我们想给自己一个字符，一个整数，一个字符串，
If we want to give ourselves a char, an int, a string,
我们从字面上将其输入到程序中
we literally type it out into the program
本身，以便它在我们需要时就在那儿。
itself so that it's there when we want it.
但是如果我们在这里考虑这张照片，
But if we consider this picture here, which
现在只是您计算机中某些内容的物理化身
is now just a physical incarnation of some of the contents of your computer's
记忆，俏皮地贴着很多奥斯卡的食人鱼，
memory, playfully labeled with a lot of Oscar the Grouches,
这是因为您永远不应该信任计算机内存中的内容
this is because you should never trust the contents of your computer's memory
如果您自己还没有在那儿放东西。
if you yourself have not put something there.
编程中有一个术语叫做垃圾值。
There's a term of art in programming called garbage values.
如果您自己尚未在内存中放置任何值，
If you yourself have not put a value somewhere in memory,
为了安全起见，您应该假定它是引用的“垃圾值”。
you should assume, to be safe, that it is a quote unquote, "garbage value."
这不是一个怪异的值。
It's not a weird value.
只是1、2，A，B，C
It's just a 1, a 2, an A, a B, a C, you just
不知道它是什么，因为如果您的程序随着时间运行
don't know what it is, because if your program is running over time
并且您正在调用函数，并且函数正在返回。
and you're calling functions and functions are returning.
您正在调用其他函数，并且函数正在返回。
You're calling other functions and functions are returning.
您计算机内存中的这些值在不断变化，
These values in your computer's memory are constantly changing,
并且您的内存被重用。
and your memory gets reused.
当您释放内存时，不会擦除它或将其全部设置回0或对其进行设置
When you free memory, that doesn't erase it or set it all back to 0's or set it
全部回到1。
all back to 1's.
它只是留下来，以便您可以重复使用
It just leaves it alone so that you can reuse
它，这意味着随着时间的流逝，您的计算机中会残留
it, which means over time, your computer contains remnants
在这里，这里，在程序中使用过的所有变量
of all of the variables you've ever used in your program over here, over here,
在那边。
over there.
因此，在这样的程序中，您尚未显式初始化y
And so in a program like this, where you have not explicitly initialized y
无论如何，你应该假设奥斯卡·格鲁奇（Oscar the Grouch）可以这么说，
to anything, you should assume that Oscar the Grouch, so to speak,
在那个位置。
is at that location.
它是一个垃圾值，看起来像一个地址，但不是有效的地址。
It is a garbage value that looks like an address but is not a valid address.
因此，当您说星号y等于13时，这意味着转到该地址。
And so when you say star y equals 13, that means go to that address.
但实际上，请转到该虚假地址并在其中放置一些内容。
But really, go to that bogus address and put something there.
很有可能，您的程序将崩溃。
And odds are, your program is going to crash.
您将遇到细分错误，
You are going to get a segmentation fault,
因为通过转到任意垃圾值地址，
because by going to some arbitrary garbage value address,
这就像拿起一张随机的纸，上面有一个数字
it would be like picking up a random piece of paper with a number on it
然后转到该邮箱。
and then going to that mailbox.
为什么？
Why?
它确实属于您。
It does it belong to you.
如果您尝试取消引用未初始化的变量，
If you try to dereference an uninitialized variable,
您的程序可能会崩溃。
your program may very well crash.
也许这没有更好的表现
And this is, perhaps, no better-presented
而不是我们的一些朋友，斯坦福大学教授尼克·帕兰特（Nick Parlante）
than by some of our friends, Nick Parlante, a professor at Stanford
大学，他的生活以黏土化中的角色“ Binky”为生。
University who is breathed life into a character in claymation known as Binky.
我们只有2分钟的剪辑来描绘坏事
We have just a 2 minute clip from this that paints the picture of bad things
确实在您不应该触摸内存时发生。
indeed happening when you touch memory that you shouldn't.
因此，希望能对如何使用指针和不使用指针提供有用的提示。
So hopefully, a helpful reminder as to what to do and not to do with pointers.
开始了。
Here we go.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-宾基。
- Hey, Binky.
醒来，是时候玩转指针了。
Wake up, it's time for pointer fun.
- 那是什么？
- What's that?
了解指针？
Learn about pointers?
哦，天哪！
Oh, goody!
-好吧，开始吧，我想我们需要几个提示。
- Well, to get started, I guess we're going to need a couple pointers.
-好的，此代码分配了两个可以指向整数的指针。
- OK, this code allocates two pointers which can point to integers.
-好的，我看到了两个指针。
- OK, well I see the two pointers.
但是他们似乎并没有指向任何东西。
But they don't seem to be pointing to anything.
- 这是正确的。
- That's right.
最初，指针不指向任何东西。
Initially, pointers don't point to anything.
他们指向或称为指向对象的东西。
The things they point to or called pointees.
设置它们是一个单独的步骤。
And setting them up's a separate step.
-哦，对，对。
- Oh, right, right.
我知道。
I knew that.
指示者是分开的。
The pointees are separate.
那么，你如何分配一个pointee呢？
So how do you allocate a pointee?
-好的，这段代码分配了一个新的整数指针。
- OK, well, this code allocates a new integer pointee.
这部分将x指向它。
And this part sets x to point to it.
-嘿，看起来好多了。
- Hey, that looks better.
因此，使其有所作为。
So make it do something.
-好的，我将取消引用指针x以将数字42存储到其指针中。
- OK, I'll dereference the pointer x to store the number 42 into its pointee.
对于这个技巧，我需要我的魔术师取消引用。
For this trick, I'll need my magic wand of dereferencing.
-您取消引用的魔杖？
- Your magic wand of dereferencing?
那太棒了。
That's great.
-这就是代码的样子。
- This is what the code looks like.
我将设置电话号码，然后-
I'll just set up the number and--
[流行音乐]
[POP]
-嘿，看，到了。
- Hey, look, there it goes.
因此，在x上进行解引用遵循箭头以访问其指针。
So doing a dereference on x follows the arrow to access its pointee.
在这种情况下，要在其中存储42。
In this case, to store 42 in there.
嘿，尝试使用它通过另一个指针y存储数字13。
Hey, try using it to store the number 13 through the other pointer, y.
- 好的。
- OK.
我将在这里转到y并设置数字13
I'll just go over here to y and get the number 13 set up
然后拿起取消引用的魔杖，然后-
and then take the wand of dereferencing and just--
[HORN]哇！
[HORN] whoa!
-哦，嘿，那没用。
- Oh, hey, that didn't work.
说，Binky，我认为取消引用y不是一个好主意，因为设置
Say, Binky, I don't think dereferencing y is a good idea, because setting up
指示人是一个单独的步骤。
the pointee is a separate step.
而且我认为我们从未做到过。
And I don't think we ever did it.
-嗯，好点。
- Hmm, good point.
-是的，我们分配了指针y。
- Yeah, we allocated the pointer y.
但是我们从来没有将它指向一个指向对象。
But we never set it to point to a pointee.
-嗯，非常细心。
- Hmm, very observant.
-嘿，你在那里看起来不错，宾基。
- Hey, you're looking good there, Binky.
您能解决这个问题，以使y指向与x相同的指针吗？
Can you fix it so that y points to the same pointee as x?
-当然，我将使用我的魔术棒进行指针分配。
- Sure, I'll use my magic wand of pointer assignment.
-这会像以前一样成问题吗？
- Is that going to be a problem like before?
-不，这不会触碰到指示者。
- No, this doesn't touch the pointees.
它只是更改一个指针以指向与另一个指针相同的事物。
It just changes one pointer to point to the same thing as another.
- 哦，我明白了。
- Oh, I see.
现在，y指向与x相同的位置。
Now, y points to the same place as x.
所以等等，现在y是固定的。
So wait, now y is fixed.
它有一个pointee。
It has a pointee.
因此，您可以尝试再次取消引用的魔杖以发送13个。
So you can try the wand of dereferencing again to send the 13 over.
- 哦好的。
- Oh, OK.
来了
Here it goes.
[流行音乐]
[POP]
-嘿，看那个。
- Hey, look at that.
现在，对y进行解引用。
Now, dereferencing works on y.
而且由于指针共享一个pointe，所以他们都看到了13。
And because the pointers are sharing that one pointee, they both see the 13.
-是的，分享，随便吧。
- Yeah, sharing, whatever.
那我们现在要换地方吗？
So are we going to switch places now?
-哦，看，我们没时间了。
- Oh look, we're out of time.
- 但 -
- But--
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，所以我们还没有时间。
DAVID MALAN: All right, so we are not quite out of time.
但是，让我们继续前进，在这里进行第二个5分钟的休息。
But let's go ahead and take our second 5 minute break here.
当我们回来时，我们将仔细研究奥斯卡等等。
And when we return, we'll take a closer look at Oscar and more.
返回5。
Back in 5.
好吧，我声称所有这些垃圾
All right, so I claim that there's all these garbage
您计算机内存中的值。
values in your computer's memory.
但是你怎么看到他们呢？
But how can you see them?
Binky所做的当然是尝试取消引用垃圾值
What Binky did was, of course, try to dereference a garbage value
当坏事发生时。
when bad things happen.
但是，实际上我们可以用自己的代码看到这一点。
But we can actually see this with code of our own.
所以，让我继续快速进行一下，在这里编写一个小程序，
So let me go ahead, quickly, and whip up a little program here,
就像我们在第一周或第二周所做的一样，
just like something we did in week one or week two,
但做得不好。
but without doing it very well.
让我继续，像往常一样包含标准io点h，它是int main void。
Let me go ahead and include standard io dot h as usual, int main void.
然后让我继续，给自己一些分数。
And then let me go ahead and give myself an array of scores.
三个分数的数组怎么样？
How about an array of three scores?
在从用户那里收集分数之前，我们已经完成了此操作。
And we've done this before where we collected scores from a user.
但是这次，我将故意
But this time, I'm going to deliberately make
没有真正初始化那些分数的错误
the mistake of not actually initializing those scores
甚至要求人类提供这些分数。
or even asking the human for those scores.
我只是盲目地从i等于0迭代到3。
I'm just going to blindly go about iterating from i equals 0 on up to 3.
在每次迭代中，我都将假定打印任何内容
And on each iteration, I'm just going to presumptuously print whatever is
在分数支架i中的那个位置。
at that location in scores bracket i.
因此，从逻辑上讲，我的代码在尝试执行时是正确的，
So logically, my code is correct in what it's trying to do,
打印出分数值。
print out the values in scores.
但是请注意，我没有故意初始化任何
But notice that I have deliberately not initialized any
阵列中1、2、3分的总分。
of the 1, 2, 3 scores in that array.
那么谁知道那里将会发生什么呢？
So who knows what's going to be there?
确实，它应该是某种垃圾值
Indeed, it should be garbage values of some sort
我们不一定可以事先预测。
that we couldn't necessarily predict in advance.
因此，让我继续进行垃圾处理，因为该程序
So let me go ahead and make garbage, since this program
在一个名为garbage.c的文件中。
is in a file called garbage.c.
编译正常，但是当我现在运行垃圾时，我们
Compiles OK, but when I now run garbage, we
应该看到三个分数，即833060864，它们在密码上是负数。
should see three scores, which are cryptically negative, 833060864.
另一个是32765。
Another one is 32765.
第三个恰好是0。
And the third just happens to be 0.
所以有那些垃圾值，因为同样，计算机
So there are those garbage values, because again, the computer
不会为您初始化任何这些值。
is not going to initialize any of those values for you.
现在，有例外。
Now, there are exceptions.
有时，我们使用了全局变量，
We have, on occasion, used a global variable,
在main函数和我所有其他函数的上下文之外的常量。
a constant that is outside the context of main and all of my other functions.
全局变量（如果未设置），
Global variables, if you do not set them,
通常会为您初始化为0或nul。
are conventionally initialized to 0 or nul for you.
但是您通常不应该依赖这种行为。
But you should generally not rely on that kind of behavior.
您的直觉应该是始终初始化值
Your instinct should be to always initialize values
在考虑触摸或阅读它们之前
before thinking of touching or reading them
如通过printf或其他某种机制。
as via printf or some other mechanism.
好吧，让我们看看现在对内存的了解，
All right, well, let's see how this understanding, now, of memory,
可以引导我们解决问题，但同时也会遇到新类型的问题，
can lead us to solve problems, but also encounter new types of problems,
但是我们现在可以希望理解的问题。
but problems that we can now hopefully understand.
我将继续在这里创建一个新程序。
I'm going to go ahead and create a new program here.
回想一下上周这很普遍
And recall from last week that it was very common
让我们想交换价值。
for us to want to swap values.
当布莱恩（Brian）为我们做分类时，无论是选择还是冒泡
When Brian was doing our sorts for us, whether it was selection or bubble
排序中，发生了很多交换。
sort, there was a lot of swapping going on.
但是，我们并未真正为这些算法编写任何代码。
And yet, we didn't really write any code for those algorithms.
很好。
And that's fine.
但是让我们考虑一下
But let's consider that very simple primitive of just
交换两个值，例如，交换两个整数。
swapping two values, for instance, swapping two integers.
让我继续，让我自己开始一个程序，然后在这里swap.c。
Let me go ahead and give myself the start of a program and swap.c here.
我将包括标准io点h，int main void。
I'm going to include standard io dot h, int main void.
在main内部，我要给自己两个整数。
And inside of main, I'm going to give myself two integers.
让我们给自己一个名为x的int并将其分配为1，一个称为y的int
Let's just give myself an int called x and assign it 1, an int called y
并分配给它2。
and assign it 2.
然后让我继续，然后打印出这些值是什么。
And then let me go ahead and just print out what those values are.
我只是说，从字面上看，x是百分比，逗号是y是反斜杠n。
I'll just say, literally, x is percent i comma y is percent i backslash n.
然后，我将继续打印x逗号y。
And then I'm going to go ahead and print out x comma y, respectively.
然后我最终要编写一个名为
And then I'm eventually going to write a function called
交换x和y的交换。
swap that swaps x and y.
但是，现在就假设存在。
But let's assume, for the moment, that exists.
不会，因为我当时想做的正确
It doesn't, because what I then want to do right
之后，只是重印了同一件事，x现在是百分比i，
after that is just reprint the same thing, x is now percent i,
y是百分比i，我的假设是x和y的值
y is percent i, my presumption being that the values of x and y
将被交换。
will be swapped.
那么我该如何交换这两个值呢？
So how might I swap these two values?
好吧，让我继续执行自己的功能。
Well, let me go ahead and implement my own function.
我认为它不需要返回任何东西，
I don't think it needs to return anything,
所以我要说void是返回类型。
so I'm going to say void is the return type.
我称之为交换。
I'll call it swap.
它需要两个参数作为输入。
It's going to take two arguments as input.
我们将其称为a和b，两者都是整数。
We'll call it a and b, both integers.
但是我可以随便叫它。
But I could call it anything I want.
但是a和b似乎是合理的。
But a and b seems reasonable.
现在，我想继续并交换两个值。
And now, I want to go ahead and swap two values.
现在，布莱恩（Brian）上周用两只手做了这种事。
Now, Brian was kind of doing this with his two hands last week.
很好，但是我们可能应该更仔细地考虑这一点。
And that's fine, but we should probably consider this a little more closely.
实际上，我们让Brian代替数字
In fact, Brian, instead of numbers, let's
做一些更真实的世界。
do something a little more real world.
我认为您面前有几杯饮料。
I think you have a couple of beverages in front of you.
布莱恩：是的。
BRIAN: Yeah.
所以在这里，我有一个红色的玻璃杯和一个蓝色的玻璃杯，
So right here, I have a red glass and a blue glass,
例如，我猜我们可以用来表示两个变量。
which I guess we can use to represent two variables, for instance.
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
现在，让我假设-
Now, let me suppose--
希望我提前告诉您。
I wish I'd told you in advance.
我实际上更希望红色液体是
I'd actually prefer that the red liquid be
在蓝色玻璃杯中，蓝色液体在红色玻璃杯中。
in the blue glass and the blue liquid be in the red glass.
因此，您介意交换这两个值吗？
So do you mind swapping those two values,
就像您上周交换了数字一样？
just like you swapped numbers last week?
布莱恩：是的，当然。
BRIAN: Yeah, sure.
这样我就可以拿起两个眼镜，并且可以切换它们的位置。
So I can just take the two glasses, and I can switch their places.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好吧，等等，那不完全是-
DAVID MALAN: OK, wait, OK, that's not exactly--
你从字面上也把我带走了。
you took me too literally.
我认为，如果我们现在将眼镜视为特定位置
I think here, if we think of the glasses, now, as specific locations
在记忆中，你不能只是身体移动
in memory, you can't just physically move
交换计算机内部内存的芯片。
the chips of memory inside of your computer to swap things.
所以我认为我确实需要您移动蓝色液体
So I think I literally need you to move the blue liquid
进入红色玻璃杯和红色液体进入蓝色玻璃杯
into the red glass and the red liquid into the blue glass
因此它更像是计算机的内存。
so that it's more like a computer's memory.
布莱恩：好的，我可以尝试这样做。
BRIAN: OK, I can try to do that.
不过，我有点紧张，因为我觉得我不能只是
I'm a little nervous, though, because I feel like I can't just
将蓝色液体倒入红色玻璃中，因为红色液体已经
pour the blue liquid into the red glass, because the red liquid's already
在那里。
in there.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，所以这可能不会很好地结束，
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so this probably doesn't end well,
如果他必须在两副眼镜之间进行某种转换。
if he's got to do some kind of switcheroo between the two glasses.
那么这里有什么想法吗？
So any thoughts here?
就像这个怪异但真实的问题在现实世界中的解决方案是什么？
Like what is the real world solution to this weird but real problem, where
我们想交换这两个位置的内容，
we want to swap the contents of these two locations,
就像Brian交换两个内存位置的内容一样
just like Brian was swapping the contents of two memory locations
上个星期？
last week?
布赖恩，如果您希望同时进行聊天，
Brian, if you have your eye on the chat in parallel,
谁能对我们如何交换这两种液体有任何想法？
might anyone have ideas on how we could swap these two liquids?
布莱恩：是的，有几个人在说我需要第三杯。
BRIAN: Yeah, a couple of people are saying that I need a third glass.
大卫·马兰：好吧，布莱恩，你呢
DAVID MALAN: All right, well Brian, do you
恰好有第三杯你在后台后面吗？
happen to have a third glass with you back there behind back stage?
布莱恩：事实上，我想是的。
BRIAN: In fact, I think I do.
因此，我在这里有了第三杯，恰好是空的。
So I have a third glass here that just so happens to be empty.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
您现在将如何交换这两件事？
And how would you, now, go about swapping these two things?
布莱恩：好的，所以我想将蓝色液体放入红色玻璃杯中。
BRIAN: All right, so I want to put the blue liquid inside the red glass.
因此，我认为我需要做的第一件事是，
So the first thing I need to do, I think,
只是清空红色玻璃，为蓝色液体腾出空间。
is just to empty out the red glass to make space for the blue liquid.
所以我要服用红色液体，我只是
So I'm going to take the red liquid, and I'm just
将其倒入此额外的玻璃杯中。
going to pour it into this extra glass.
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：暂时，对吧？
DAVID MALAN: Temporarily though, right?
布莱恩：是的，是的。
BRIAN: Temporarily, yeah.
戴维·马兰：好的。
DAVID MALAN: OK.
布莱恩：只是为了保存它在那里。
BRIAN: Just to keep it to store it there.
现在，我想我可以倒入蓝色液体
And now, I think I can just pour the blue liquid
放入原始的红色玻璃杯中，因为现在我可以这样做了。
into the original red glass, because now I'm free to do so.
因此，我将蓝色液体倒入那里。
So I'll pour the blue liquid there.
我想我现在要做的最后一件事就是，现在这蓝色
And I think the last thing I need to do now is, now this blue--
原来装有蓝色液体的玻璃杯现在是空的。
this glass that originally held the blue liquid is now empty.
因此，在此临时玻璃内部的红色液体
So the red liquid, which was inside of this temporary glass over here,
我可以把红色的液体倒入这里。
I can take the red liquid and just pour it into this glass here.
现在，我没有调换眼镜的位置。
And now, I didn't swap the positions of the glasses.
但是液体实际上已经切换了位置。
But the liquids have actually switched places.
现在，蓝色液体在左侧，红色液体在右侧。
Now, the blue liquid is on the left and the red liquid is on the right.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：太好了。
DAVID MALAN: Awesome.
是的，我认为这是一个更实际的实现
Yeah, I think that is a more literal implementation
你上周所做的事情和理所当然的事情，
of what you were doing and taking for granted last week,
在两个不同的位置交换两个值。
swapping the two values in two separate locations.
因此，这似乎很简单。
So it seems pretty straightforward.
我只需要一点空间。
I just need a little more space.
如果需要的话，我需要代码中的一个临时变量。
I need a temporary variable in code, if you will.
看来我需要三个步骤。
And it seems I need three steps.
我需要倒一个，倒另一个，然后倒另一个。
I need to pour one out, pour the other one out, pour the other one back in.
所以我想我可以在这里将其翻译成代码。
So I think I can translate that into code here.
让我继续给自己一个临时变量，
Let me go ahead and give myself a temporary variable,
就像布赖恩一样。
like a glass, like Brian did.
我将其称为tmp，TMP，
And I'll call it tmp, T-M-P, which is pretty conventional when
您想交换代码中的两件事。
you want to swap two things in code.
我将暂时签署a的价值。
And I'm going to sign it, temporarily, the value of a.
然后我将把a的内容更改为等于B的任何内容
I'm going to then change the contents of a to equal whatever the contents of B
是。
are.
然后，我将b更改为tmp的内容。
And then I'm going to change b to be whatever the contents of tmp were.
所以这感觉很合理也很正确，
So this feels pretty reasonable and pretty correct,
因为这只是文字转换为代码，
because it's just a literal translation into code,
现在，布莱恩在现实世界中所做的事情。
now, of what Brian did in the real world.
而且我认为这会编译。
And I think this will compile.
因此，让我们从那里开始，进行交换。
So let's start there, make swap.
可以-哦，不可以编译。
It does-- oh, doesn't compile.
好吧，以前的隐式声明，哦，天哪，有这么多错误。
OK, previous implicit declaration, oh, so many errors, my god.
函数交换的隐式声明-
Implicit declaration of function swap--
等一下。
wait a minute.
我以前见过。
I've seen that before.
我以前犯过这个错误。
I've made this mistake before.
您可能也有。
You might have as well.
每当您看到此内容时，请记住这只是您缺少原型。
Anytime you see this, recall it's just that you're missing your prototype.
请记住，编译器将按字面意义带您进入。
Remember that the compiler is going to take you literally.
而且，如果看到它时不知道swap这个词存在，
And if it doesn't know the word swap exists when it sees it,
它不会成功编译。
it's not going to compile successfully.
因此，我们需要将原型包含在文件的顶部。
So we need to include my prototype at the top of my file.
现在，让我再试一次，进行交换。
Now, let me try this again, make swap.
好的，可以编译。
OK, that compiles.
现在让我继续进行交换，并回想一下，主要是我所做的
Let me go ahead now and run swap and recall that, in main, what I did
将x初始化为1，y初始化为2。
was initialize x to 1, y to 2.
然后，我打印出x是和y是什么。
I then print out what x is and what y is.
我调用swap，然后再次打印出x和y。
I call swap, and then I print out what x is and y is again.
所以我应该看到1、2，然后是2、1。
So I should see 1, 2, and then 2, 1.
因此，让我们按Enter键。
So lets hit Enter.
呵呵，似乎没有用。
Huh, it does not seem to be working.
好吧，让我们再试一次，以防万一-
Well, let's try it again, just in case--
不，不工作。
no, not working.
好吧，让我尝试一下。
Well, let me try this.
让我补充一点-printf是我的朋友。
Let me add some-- printf is my friend.
让我继续说a是百分之一。
Let me go ahead and say a is percent i.
b是我反斜杠n，a，b的百分比。
b is percent i backslash n, a, b.
因此，让我们将其打印出来。
So let's print that out.
让我们将其打印两次。
And let's print that out twice.
因此，这将是一种合理的调试技术。
So this would be a reasonable debugging technique.
如果您想知道引擎盖下面发生了什么，请添加一些printf。
If you want to know what's going on underneath the hood, add some printf's.
让我继续进行交换。
Let me go ahead and make swap.
编译后，点斜杠交换。
That compiles, dot slash swap.
让我们看一下，a是1，b是2，a是2，b是1。
And let's see, a is 1, b is 2, a is 2, b is 1.
但是x和y不变。
But then x and y are unchanged.
所以我觉得我的逻辑是对的。
So I feel like my logic is right.
它正在切换a和b。
It's switching a and b.
但是实际上并没有切换x和y。
But it's not actually switching x and y.
我可以确认很多，对吗？
And I could confirm as much, right?
调试此功能的更强大的方法是
The more powerful way to debug this would
要运行debug50，设置一个断点，例如在第17行
be to run debug50, set a break point, for instance, at line 17,
逐步完成我的代码，逐步进入交换功能。
step through my code, step by step, stepping into the swap function.
但就目前而言，交换似乎很有效。
But for now, it seems clear that swap works.
但是main并没有真正看到那些结果。
But main isn't really seeing those results.
那么到底是怎么回事？
So what's actually going on?
好吧，让我们考虑一下我的记忆在现实世界中的化身
Well, let's consider this real world incarnation of what my memory is
所以我实际上可以四处移动。
so I can actually move things around.
这一切都要归功于我们在剧院后面的道具店里的朋友们。
And this is all thanks to our friends in the theater's prop shop in back.
如果我们将此视为我的计算机的记忆，
If we think of this as my computer's memory,
最初，所有都是垃圾值。
initially, it's all garbage values.
但是我可以将其用作画布以开始在内存中分配内容。
But I can use this as a canvas to start laying things out in memory.
到目前为止，调用函数是我们理所当然的事情。
But calling functions is something we've taken for granted thus far.
事实证明，当您调用函数时，默认情况下是计算机，
And it turns out, when you call functions, the computer, by default,
以一种标准方式使用此内存。
uses this memory in kind of a standard way.
实际上，让我继续绘制更多的图片。
In fact, let me go ahead and draw a more pictorial picture.
如果可以的话，让我在这里更直观地描述计算机的内存
Let me draw a more literal picture here, if you will, of the computer's memory
再次。
again.
因此，如果这是计算机的内存，并且我们放大其中一个芯片，
So if this is the computer's memory and we zoom in on one of the chips,
我们认为该芯片具有这样的一堆字节。
and we think of the chip as having a whole bunch of bytes like this.
让我们抽象出实际的硬件，并像往常一样思考它。
Let's abstract away the actual hardware and think of it as we have been.
只是这个大的矩形存储区域，与所有那些奥斯卡奖不同
It's just this big rectangular region of memory, not unlike all of those Oscar
片刻之前的Grouches。
the Grouches a moment ago.
但是按照惯例，您的计算机不仅会放东西
But by convention, your computer does not just plop things
在内存中的随机位置。
in random locations in memory.
它具有一定的经验法则。
It has certain rules of thumb that it adheres to.
特别是，它会处理计算机内存的不同部分
In particular, it treats different portions of your computer's memory
以不同的方式。
in different ways.
它以标准方式使用它，因此它不是完全随机的。
It uses it in a standard way so that it's not completely random.
例如，当您通过在CS50 IDE上执行点斜杠来运行程序时
For instance, when you run a program by doing dot slash something on CS50 IDE
或更一般地在Linux上，或者双击Mac OS上的图标
or on Linux more generally, or you double click an icon on Mac OS
或Windows，会触发计算机的-
or Windows, that triggers the computer's--
该程序的0和1存储在您的硬盘上，可以在此处加载，
the program's 0's and 1's stored on your hard drive to be loaded up here,
称为机器代码，也就是0和1。
to what we'll call machine code, which again, is the 0's and 1's.
因此，如果您再次隐喻地思考，作为您的记忆
So if you think again, metaphorically, as your memory
是这个矩形区域，然后是机器代码，
is this rectangular region, then the machine code,
组成您的程序的0和1被加载到内存的顶部。
the 0's and 1's composing your program are loaded into the top part of memory.
同样，顶部，底部，左侧，右侧没有基本的技术含义。
And again, top, bottom, left, right, it has no fundamental technical meaning.
这只是艺术家的作品。
It's just an artist's rendition.
但是它确实进入标准位置。
But it does go into a standard location.
在此之下是所有全局变量。
Below that are all of your global variables.
放在函数之外的常量也是如此。
So are your constants that you put outside of your functions.
这些将最终在机器代码之下，
Those are going to end up just below the machine code,
同样，在计算机内存的顶部。
so again, at the top of your computer's memory.
在此之下是所谓的堆。
Below that is what's called the heap.
这是一个技术术语。
And this is a technical term.
它指的是分配给内存的很大一块
And it refers to a big chunk of memory that malloc
用于为您提供一些备用内存。
uses to get you some spare memory.
每次调用malloc时，都会获得一些内存块的地址
Any time you call malloc, you are given the address of some chunk of memory
在此区域中，在机器代码下方，在全局变量下方。
up in this region, below the machine code, below your global variables.
这是一个很大的区域。
And it's kind of a big zone.
但是要注意的是，您内存的其他部分的使用方式有所不同。
But the catch is that other parts of your memory are used differently.
实际上，尽管堆被认为处于关闭状态，
In fact, whereas the heap is considered to be here on down, somewhat
令人担忧的是，堆栈被认为位于此处。
worrisomely, the stack is considered to be here on up.
也就是说，当您调用malloc并请求内存时，
This is to say, when you call malloc and ask for memory,
在这里分配。
that gets allocated up here.
但是，当您调用一个函数时，这些函数
When you call a function, though, those functions
使用所谓的堆栈空间而不是堆空间。
use what's called stack space instead of heap space.
因此，任何时候调用函数，main或swap或strlang或string比较
So any time you call a function, main or swap or strlang or string compare
或您到目前为止使用的任何功能，
or any of the functions you've used thus far,
您的计算机将自动存储任何
your computer will automatically store any
这些函数中的局部变量或参数。
of the local variables or parameters from those functions down here.
现在，这不一定是最好的设计，
Now, this is not necessarily the best design,
因为您可以看到两个箭头指向一个
because you can see the two arrows pointing at one
另一辆火车就像是两列火车相互冲撞而下。
another is like two trains barreling down the tracks at one another.
坏事最终可能会发生。
Bad things can eventually happen.
幸运的是，我们通常有足够的内存
Thankfully, we typically have enough memory
这两件事不会发生冲突，但仅此而已。
that these two things don't collide, but more on that in just a bit.
同样，当您调用函数时，将使用此处的内存。
So again, when you call functions, memory down here is used.
当您使用malloc时，将使用此处的内存。
When you use malloc, memory up here is used.
现在，对于我的交换功能，我没有使用malloc。
Now, for my swap function, I'm not using malloc.
因此，我不必担心堆。
So I don't think I have to worry about heap.
而且我没有任何全局变量。
And I don't have any global variables.
而且我并不真正在乎我的机器代码。
And I don't really care about my machine code.
我只需要知道它存储在某个地方即可。
I just need to know that it's stored somewhere.
但是，让我们考虑一下堆栈到底是什么。
But let's consider, then, what the stack is all about.
实际上，堆栈就是这种动态的地方
The stack, indeed, is this sort of dynamic place
内存不断使用和重用的地方。
where memory keeps getting used and reused.
因此，例如，当您调用main时，就像您在使用该交换程序时一样
So for instance, when you call main, as you might when this swap program is
运行时，main会在此图片的底部使用一小段内存（如果您愿意的话）。
run, main uses a sliver of memory at the bottom of this picture, if you will.
所以main中的局部变量，例如x和y，
So the local variables in main, like x and y,
最终在内存的此底部。
end up at this bottom portion of memory.
当您调用swap时，swap会在main上方使用一块内存，
When you call swap, swap uses a chunk of memory just above main,
象形图，在此图中，例如变量a和b以及temp，
pictorally, in this diagram, such as variables a and b and temp,
对于这个问题。
for that matter.
然后，一旦交换返回并完成执行，那一小段内存
And then, once swap returns and is done executing, that sliver of memory
本质上消失了。
essentially goes away.
现在，它并没有消失。
Now, it doesn't disappear.
显然，那里仍然有物理内存。
Obviously, there's still physical memory there.
但这是我们再次讨论垃圾值的时候。
But that's when we get into the discussion of garbage values again.
他们仍然像整个地方的《食尸鬼奥斯卡》一样。
They're still like Oscar the Grouches all over the place.
您只是不知道或目前不在乎这些值是什么。
You just don't know, or at this point care, what the values are.
但是那里有价值。
But there are values there.
这就是为什么刚才我打印出未初始化得分的原因
And that's why, a moment ago, when I printed out that uninitialized score's
数组，我确实看到了一些伪造的值，因为仍然存在
array, I did see some bogus values, because there's still
将会是之前剩下的0和1。
going to be 0's and 1's there that are left over from before.
但是，问题是这样的。
The problem, though, is this.
让我谈谈我们对记忆的身体化身
Let me go over to this physical incarnation of our memory
并认为这是我们的堆栈，因此它正在不断发展。
and consider this as being our stack, so it's growing on up.
实际上，如果我想像我一样拥有两个局部变量x和y，
And in fact, if I want to have two local variables like I do, x and y,
让我们继续，以这里的这行内存为主，
let's go ahead and think of this row of memory here as being main,
例如，在这里。
for instance, here.
我将继续替换所有这些垃圾值
And I'm going to go ahead and replace all these garbage values
具有我关心的实际价值。
with an actual value that I care about.
而我关心的实际值，我们将称为x和y，就像
And the actual values that I care about, we're going to call x and y, just as
前。
before.
因此，每个奥斯卡奖都是一个字节。
So each of these Oscars happens to be one byte.
但是一个int是4个字节。
But an int is 4 bytes.
因此，值得庆幸的是，我们在道具店里的朋友们，
So thankfully, from our friends in the prop shop,
我们有这些更大的整数块。
we have these bigger integer-sized blocks.
我将继续将其滑入此处。
And I'm going to go ahead and slide this in here.
稍后，我们将其视为x。
And we're going to think of this, in a moment, as x.
实际上，我将继续使用标记将其称为x。
And indeed, I'm going to go ahead and call this x with a marker.
然后我要继续给自己一个整数，大小为4，
And then I'm going to go ahead and give myself another integer, a size 4,
放到这里
and put it down here.
我们将认为这是y。
And we're going to think of this as y.
回想一下，我将这些值初始化为什么？
And recall, what do I initialize these values to?
好吧，初始值为1，初始值为2。
Well, the value 1, initially, and the value 2.
但是后来我调用了交换功能。
But then I called the swap function.
swap函数有两个参数，a和b。
And the swap function has two arguments, a and b.
由于我将x逗号y传递给了我，所以这些在设计上成为x和y的副本。
And those, by design, become copies of x and y, because I passed in x comma y.
我将swap定义为逗号b。
And I defined swap as taking a comma b.
所以我认为实际上我现在需要做的是
So I think what I need to do, physically here, is now
认为这第二行内存现在属于交换功能，
think of this second row of memory as now belonging to the swap function,
不主要。
not to main.
在第二行的内存中，我将
And inside of this second row of memory, I'll
认为这属于交换。
think of this as belonging to swap.
在交换行中，我将拥有另一个大小为4的整数。
And within the swap row, I'm going to have another integer of size 4.
我们将其称为“ a”，如下面所示。
And we're going to call this one a, as down there, a.
然后，我将再得到另一个大小为4的块。
And then I'm going to have another chunk of size 4.
我们将其称为b。
And we're going to call this b.
再说一次，因为这些只是参数，x逗号y，否则
And again, because those are just the arguments, x comma y, otherwise
现在称为逗号b，我将1和2复制到这些值中。
now known as a comma b, I copy 1 and 2 into those values.
但是swap具有第三个变量。
But swap has a third variable.
布赖恩提出了一个临时变量。
Brian proposed a temporary variable.
所以我要继续给自己四个字节，
So I'm going to go ahead and give myself four more bytes,
从而摆脱那里的垃圾值
thereby getting rid of whatever the garbage value's there
并将其实际设置为整数调用tmp。
and actually setting it to an integer call tmp.
因此，我将继续将其称为tmp，TMP。
So I'm going to go ahead and call this thing tmp, T-M-P.
我首先做了什么？
And what did I do first?
我将tmp设置为a。
I set tmp equals to a.
因此，tmp等于a。
So tmp equals to a.
因此，如果a为1，则tmp为1。
So if a is 1, tmp is 1.
那我怎么办
Then what did I do?
然后我做了一个等于b。
I then did a equals b.
所以b是2。
So b is 2.
a也为2。
a is 2 as well.
最后，我做了什么？
And then lastly, what did I do?
我没有b获得tmp。
I did b gets tmp.
所以我必须继续将其更改为tmp的值
So I have to go ahead and change this to be whatever the value of tmp
是，现在是数字1。
is, which is now the number 1.
这样一来，您就可以看到交换是正确的
So you can see that swap is correct insofar
因为它交换a和b的值。
as it is swapping the values of a and b.
但是当交换返回时，这些返回
But the moment swap returns, these return
被认为是垃圾值。
to being thought of as garbage values.
Main仍在运行中。
Main is still in the middle of running.
交换不再运行。
Swap is no longer running.
但是这些价值观仍然存在。
But these values stay there.
所以这些是垃圾值。
So those are garbage values.
我们碰巧知道它们是什么，但它们不再有效，
We happen to know what they are, but they're no longer valid,
因为当我第二次打印x和y时，x和y是什么？
because when I go to print out x and y for the second time, what are x and y?
他们还是一样。
They're still the same.
这就是说，当您实际编写带有参数的代码时
And so this is to say, when you actually write code that takes arguments
然后您将参数从一个函数传递给另一个函数，
and you pass arguments from one function to another,
这些参数从一个函数复制到另一个函数。
those arguments are copied from one function to another.
实际上，x和y被复制到a和b中。
And indeed, x and y are copied into a and b.
因此，您的代码可能会正确切换，因此看起来很正确。
So your code may very well look correct in that it's swopping correctly.
但这只是在交换上下文中正确交换，
But it's only swapping correctly in the context of swap,
不触及原始值。
not touching the original values.
所以我认为从根本上说我们需要做的是
So what I think we need to do, fundamentally,
重新实现交换的方式是，我们实际上
is reimplement swap in such a way that we actually
更改x和y的值。
change the values of x and y.
但是，我们该怎么做呢？
But how can we do this?
布莱恩，如果我们可以在这里打电话的话。
Brian, if we could call in someone here.
我如何从概念上更改我的交换实现
How could I conceptually change my implementation of swap
从而以某种方式授权我更改x和y，而不更改x和y的副本？
so that it somehow empowers me to change x and y, not change copies of x and y?
我可以将什么兑换成货币，Brian？
What could I pass into swap, Brian?
布莱恩：伊戈尔建议我们改用指针。
BRIAN: Igor is suggesting that we use pointers instead.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，所以今天也许是这里的首要问题。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so perhaps the leading question here today.
但是指针似乎可以为我们提供解决方案。
But pointers would seem to give us a solution.
如果指针本质上像是宝藏
If pointers are essentially like a treasure
映射到计算机内存中的特定地址，我应该真正
map to a specific address in your computer's memory, what I should really
从main到swap的字面意义上不是传递x和y，
do from main to swap is pass in not x and y literally,
但是为什么我不传递x的地址和y的地址，
but why don't I pass in the address of x and the address of y,
这样交换就可以转到这些地址了
so that swap can now go to those addresses
并实际执行了Brian亲自进行的那种互换。
and actually do the sort of swap that Brian enacted in person.
因此，请为函数提供这些值的映射，指向这些值的指针，
So give the function a sort of map to those values, pointers to those values,
然后转到这些值。
and then go to those values.
那我该怎么办呢？
So how might I do this?
好吧，现在的代码必须有所不同。
Well, the code has to be a little different now.
这次我打电话给swap时，我真正需要做的是
When I call swap this time, what I really need to do
是传递这两个变量的地址。
is pass in the addresses of these two variables.
因此，我不一定知道这些地址是什么。
So I don't necessarily know what those addresses are.
但是为了这个故事，我们可以
But for the sake of the story, we can just
假设该地址例如为0x123。
assume that this address, for instance, is like, 0x123.
然后，距离该值的四个字节可能是0x127。
And then four bytes away from that might be 0x127, for instance.
但是再次，它到底是什么并不重要。
But again, it doesn't really matter what it is.
但是它们确实有地址x和y。
But they do have addresses, x and y.
因此，指针的回忆往往很大。
So a pointer recall tends to be pretty big.
所以我们需要拿出一块更大的木头，
So we needed to get out a bigger piece of wood,
代表一个指针的八个字节。
eight bytes that represents a pointer.
实际上，我现在需要在交换中使用更多的内存。
And I actually need to use a bit more memory in swap now.
如果我现在声明a为非整数，
If I now declare a to be, not an integer,
但是一个指向int的指针，这是一个int星型变量，
but a pointer to an int, that is a int star variable,
我现在可以称呼这件事。
I could call this thing a now.
我可以在其中存储x的地址，例如0x123。
And I could store, in it, the address of x, like 0x123.
如果我然后将b的定义更改为
If I then change the definition of b to be
不是整数，而是指向整数的指针，
not an integer, but a pointer to an integer,
那是另一个int星，恰好是八个字节。
that is another int star, which happens to be eight bytes.
我将为此使用更多的内存，但是没关系。
I'm going to use a little more memory for this thing, but that's OK.
它的名字现在将是b。
And its name is going to be b now.
它将包含0x127。
And it's going to contain 0x127.
我仍然需要一个临时变量。
I still need a temporary variable.
我仍然需要一个临时变量，但这很好。
I still need a temporary variable, but that's fine.
我只需要四个字节，因为变量
I just need four bytes for that, because the variable
本身只需要存储一个int，就像Brian暂时将其存储在玻璃杯中一样。
itself just needs to store an int, like Brian temporarily stored it in a glass.
所以我只需要一个额外的四个字节，就像以前一样。
So I just need an additional four bytes, like before, for that.
现在，让我们考虑一下逻辑。
And now, let's just consider the logic.
这是主要的。
Here's main.
现在，swap正在使用这些3--
And swap is now using these 3--
2和1/2行内存。
2 and 1/2 rows of memory.
很好。
And that's fine.
正如我建议的那样，它正在向上发展。
It's growing upward as I proposed.
X位于地址0x123。
X is at address 0x123.
y位于地址0x127。
y is at address 0x127.
因此，我在概念上提出a和b，就像Igor提出的那样，
Therefore, a and b, I propose conceptually, like Igor proposed,
分别存储a，x和y的地址。
store the addresses of a, x and y, respectively.
现在，我想我的代码需要这么说。
And now my code, I think, needs to say this.
将变量a中的任何内容存储在地址t中。
Go and store, in the variable tmp, whatever is at the address a.
因此，您可以将其视为此处的箭头。
So you can kind of think of this as being an arrow down here.
跟随箭头，确定。
Follow the arrow, OK.
地址0x123是什么？
What is at address 0x123?
数字1。
The number 1.
因此，就像以前一样，我们在tmp中放入了一个。
So we put one in tmp, just like before.
那我们该怎么办？
Then what do we do?
好吧，现在，我要继续改变，而不是改变a的价值，
Well, now, I'm going to go ahead and change, not the value of a,
但我要更改的位置是
but I'm going to change what is at the location in a to be
b中的位置是什么，这是一个指向此处向下的箭头，0x127。
whatever is at the location in b, which is an arrow pointing down here, 0x127.
因此，我现在将其更改为2。
So I'm going to change this 1, now, to be a 2.
回忆起来，第三步也是最后一步，对我来说，
And the third and final step, recall, is for me, now,
去，而不是去b，而是去b指向的位置，恰好是y，
to go, not to b, but to go where b points to, which happens to be y,
并将其更改为tmp的值，当然这是在这里。
and change that to be the value of tmp, which of course, is up here.
在故事的这一点上，它仍然只是三行代码。
And at this point in the story, it's still just three lines of code.
它们是不同类型的代码行。
They're different types of lines of code.
这是三行代码。
It's three lines of code.
但是当交换完成执行后，请注意我们已经完成了。
But when swap is done executing, notice what we've done.
通过让我们成功地交换了x和y
We have successfully swapped x and y by letting
交换去那些地址，而不是天真地得到
swap go to those addresses as opposed to just naively getting
其中的值的副本。
copies of the values therein.
现在，即使这段代码看起来有些晦涩，
Now, even though this code is going to look a little cryptic,
坦白说，它只是到目前为止所见逻辑的一种应用。
it's, frankly, just an application of the logic we've seen thus far.
我将继续并返回旧的越野车版本。
I'm going to go ahead and go back to my old buggy version.
我将更改交换的定义
And I'm going to change the definition of swap
说它不需要两个整数a和b，而是两个
to say that it doesn't take two integers, a and b, but two
指向整数a和b的指针。
pointers to integers a and b.
声明指针调用的方式就是变量的类型
And the way you declare a pointer recall is the type of variable
您指向后跟一个星星，然后是它的名称。
you point at followed by a star and then the name of it.
诚然，在上下文中我们还没有看到它
And we haven't seen it, admittedly, in the context
带有参数的函数。
of a function taking parameters yet.
但这很简单。
But it's quite simply that.
我加了星星。
I added the stars.
在这里，我需要说的是，无论存储在tmp中是什么。
Down here, I need to say, store in tmp, whatever is at a.
我该如何表达去？
How do I express go to a?
只需在此处添加星星。
Just add a star here.
我该如何表达去a并把b处的任何值放进去？
How do I express go to a and put whatever is at b?
我在那里加星。
I add stars there.
我怎么说，去b并存储tmp中的所有内容？
How do I say, go to b and store whatever is at tmp?
我在那里加一颗星。
I add one star there.
因此，tmp只是一个简单的整数。
So tmp is just a simple integer.
就像布赖恩一样，这只是一个空杯子。
It's just an empty glass like Brian had.
那里没有幻想。
There's nothing fancy there.
因此，我们不需要tmp周围的星星。
So we don't need stars around tmp.
但是我现在确实需要更改我使用a和b的方式，
But I do, now, need to change how I'm using a and b,
因为现在它们是我实际要访问的地址。
because now they are addresses that I actually want to go to.
在这种情况下，不需要操作员的地址。
There's no need for the address of operator in this context.
但是在这里，我将需要进行更改。
But up here, I'm going to need to make a change.
我确实需要更改原型以使其匹配。
I do need to change the prototype to match.
所以这只是一个复制粘贴。
So that's just a copy paste.
但我敢打赌，您可以想象最后需要改变的地方。
But I bet you can imagine what, lastly, needs to change.
调用swap时，我不想天真地传递x和y，因为同样，
When calling swap, I don't want to pass in naively x and y, because again,
他们将被复制。
they're going to get copied.
我想输入x的地址和y的地址，
I want to pass in the address of x and the address of y,
这样交换现在具有某种特殊的访问权限
so that swap now has sort of special access
到内存中那些位置的内容
to the contents of those locations in memory
以便它实际上可以在其中进行一些更改。
so that it actually can make some changes therein.
而且，确实，如果我现在重新编译该程序，进行交换，然后执行
And that, indeed, if I now recompile this program, make swap, and I do
点交换，交叉我的手指，瞧。
dot swap and cross my fingers, voila.
现在，我已经成功交换了代码行。
Now, I have successfully swapped lines of code.
所以上周，如果您想知道，
So last week, if you were wondering, perhaps,
为什么我们不向您展示如何进行交换，我们本来可以的。
why we didn't show you how to do swap, we could have.
而且我们不需要特殊功能。
And we didn't need a special function.
如果我们主要进行了所有这些操作，则不一定需要指针。
You don't necessarily need pointers if we did all of this in main.
但是我试图引入一个抽象，这个函数
But I'm trying to introduce an abstraction, this function that
确实像Brian为我们交换了那些眼镜一样进行了交换。
does swap just like Brian swapped those glasses for us.
并将值从一个函数传递给另一个函数，
And to pass values from one function to another,
您确实需要了解计算机内存中正在发生的事情
you do need to understand what's going on in your computer's memory
以便您实际上可以再次传入小面包屑，
so that you can actually pass in little breadcrumbs again,
再次感谢这些东西，将藏宝图映射到这些位置和记忆
treasure maps to those locations and memories, again, thanks to these things
称为指针。
called pointers.
好吧，让我提出并强调，
All right, well let me propose and emphasize,
然后，将堆的设计放在顶部，
then, that this design of the heap being up at the top,
其中malloc使用内存，而堆栈是
where malloc uses memory and the stack being
在您自己的函数使用内存的底部，
at the bottom where your own functions use memory,
这显然是一个等待发生的问题。
this is a problem clearly waiting to happen.
这些问题实际上都有名称。
And those problems actually have names.
还有一些以前编程的人
And some of you who have programmed before
可能知道其中一些术语，无论是堆溢出还是栈溢出。
might know some of these terms, either heap overflow or stack overflow.
实际上，您中的许多人可能只是将stackoverflow.com视为一个网站。
And in fact, many of you might know stackoverflow.com as just a website.
好吧，有一个起源故事的名字。
Well, there is an origin story to its name.
堆栈溢出是指多次调用函数的过程
A stack overflow refers to the process of calling a function so many times
它溢出了堆。
that it overflows the heap.
也就是说，每次您调用该函数时，
That is, every time you call the function,
就像我在这里所做的那样，可以说，您使用了越来越多的内存行。
like I did here, you use more and more rows, so to speak, of memory.
如果您一次又一次调用这么多函数，
And if you call so many functions again and again,
最终，您很可能会在称为堆的内存区域中运行。
eventually, you may very well run over the area of memory called heap.
到那时，您的程序将崩溃。
And at that point, your program will crash.
除了不做之外，没有根本的解决方案。
There is no fundamental solution to that problem other than don't do that.
不要使用过多的内存。
Don't use too much memory.
但这很难做到。
But that can be hard to do.
实际上，那是当今编程的危险之一。
And indeed, that's one of the dangers of programming today.
实际上，我们可以自己故意对此进行一些诱导。
And we can actually induce this a little bit deliberately ourselves.
实际上，例如，我认为我们可以重新考虑一下，
And in fact, I thought we could revisit, for instance,
我们上次与马里奥（Mario）离开的地方是这张照片。
where we left off with Mario last time, which was this picture here.
回想一下，这当然是一座金字塔，
Recall that this was a pyramid, of course,
比您可能遇到的问题（0）更简单。
simpler than the one you might have played with for problems at 0.
但这是递归金字塔，您可以定义高度为4的金字塔
But it's a recursive pyramid in that you can define a pyramid of height 4,
就高度3的金字塔而言，就高度2的金字塔而言
in terms of a pyramid of height 3, in terms of a pyramid of height 2
身高1。
and a height 1.
的确，我上周使用这些代码块构建了该代码。
And indeed, I built that last week using these very blocks.
好吧，你可以像这样实现马里奥的金字塔
Well, you can implement Mario's pyramid like this
以几种不同的方式。
in a couple of different ways.
一个只是使用循环，使用第一个星期的样式迭代。
One is just using week one style iteration, using a loop.
实际上，让我继续快速提出一个解决方案，
And in fact, let me go ahead and whip up a quick solution that
确实做到了。
does exactly that.
让我继续将此电话称为mario.c。
Let me go ahead and call this mario.c.
我将继续进行，并包含cs50.h。
And I'm going to go ahead and include cs50.h.
因此，我们可以使用我们的get函数之一。
So we can use one of our get functions.
我将使用标准io点h。
I'm going to use standard io dot h.
而且我将做int main void。
And I'm going to do int main void.
我要做的就是打印出这个金字塔。
And all I want to do is print out this pyramid.
但是我想问一下使用者的身高。
But I want to ask the user for the height.
所以我要说的是int height等于get int。
So I'm going to say int height equals get int.
就像您对问题1所做的那样，我们将询问用户身高。
And we'll ask the user for the height, just like you did for problem set 1.
然后，我将继续绘制该高度的金字塔。
And then I'm going to go ahead and draw a pyramid of that height.
现在，绘图不存在。
Now, draw doesn't exist.
但这很好。
But that's fine.
我现在要继续进行绘制，自己实施绘制。
I'm going to go ahead and draw this now, implement draw myself.
它不需要返回值，因为我只是
It doesn't need to return a value, because I'm just
在屏幕上打印东西。
printing stuff on the screen.
该函数称为“绘制”，它将用到
Function's called draw, and it's going to take
例如，一个名为h的输入。 h为高度，
an input called h, for instance. h for height,
但是我可以随便说它的说法。
but I could call its argument anything I want.
然后我将要执行此操作，因为我得到1，
And then I'm just going to do this, for int i gets 1,
我小于或等于h，我++。
i less than or equal to h, i++.
然后，在其中，您可能会从问题集一中回忆起这一点，
And then inside of this, this is where you might recall, from problem set one,
发现嵌套循环很有用。
have found a nested loop to be useful.
我来做int j等于1，j小于或等于i，j ++。
Let me do int j gets 1, j less than or equal to i, j++.
这将与不舒适或更舒适的情况相似但不相同
This will be similar but not identical to either the less comfortable or more
过去舒适版本的马里奥，
comfortable version of Mario from the past,
因为这个金字塔的形状朝着不同的方向。
because this pyramid is shaped in a different direction.
现在，您在此处打印一个哈希值。
Now, you print a hash there.
然后让我继续在这里打印新行。
And then let me go ahead and print a new line here.
所以我很快就做到了。
So I did this super quickly.
但是从逻辑上讲，我正在做的是迭代
But logically, what I'm doing is iterating
在每一行上，从1到h，例如第1、2、3、4行。
over every row, so from 1 through h, so row 1, 2, 3, 4, for instance.
然后在每一行上，我故意从1迭代到i。
And then on each row, I'm deliberately iterating from 1 through i.
所以我先打印1，然后2，然后3，然后4。
So I print 1, then 2, then 3, then 4.
再说一次，如果需要的话，我可以将索引设为零。
And again, I could zero index if I want.
我发现在这种情况下，对用户更友好，更易懂
I find that in this context, more user friendly, more intelligible to me
从1开始索引，如果您认为完全合理
to index from 1, totally reasonable if you think
有一个引人注目的设计论点。
there's a compelling design argument.
因此，让我继续制作Mario。
So let me go ahead and make Mario.
啊，该死。
Ah, darn it.
哦，我错过了我的原型。
Oh, I missed my prototype.
所以请注意，它不是在理解平局。
So notice, it's not understanding draw.
所以解决办法是要么移动整个功能
So the fix for that is to either move the whole function
或者，正如我们所鼓吹的那样，只是将您的原型放在首位。
or, as we've preached instead, to just put your prototype up top.
让我重新编译Mario。
Let me recompile Mario.
好的，现在成功了。
OK, now successful.
马里奥，让我们将高度设为4，瞧。
Mario, let's do a height of 4, and voila.
现在，我有一个相对简单的-尽管我当然
Now, I have a relatively simple-- though I certainly
没有您的练习，它的速度比您更快-
did it faster than you might without some practice--
实施马里奥金字塔。
implementation of Mario's pyramid.
但是，这里的事情变得很酷。
But here's where things get kind of cool.
让我规定那是一个正确的迭代解决方案，即使
Let me stipulate that that is a correct iterative solution, even
如果它可能需要您执行一些步骤或反复试验
if it might take you some number of steps or trial and error
以获得正确的基于循环的迭代代码。
to get that iterative loop-based code correct.
现在让我将其更改为递归。
Let me change this, now, to be recursive.
回想一下，递归函数是一个可以自我调用的函数。
And recall, a recursive function is one that calls itself.
您如何打印高度为h的金字塔？
How do you print a pyramid of height h?
好吧，回想一下，您打印了一个高度为h减去1的金字塔。
Well, recall that you print a pyramid of height h minus 1,
然后您继续打印另一行块。
and then you proceed to print one more row of blocks.
因此，让我从字面上理解。因为我得到零。
So let me take that literally. for int i gets zero.
我小于h，我++。
i is less than h, i++.
我继续打印那排砖
Let me go ahead and just print that extra row of bricks
像这样，然后换行。
like this, followed by a new line.
所以现在，我做了这样的快速。
So now, I did this kind of fast.
但是我在这里做什么？
But what am I doing here?
好吧，如果高度等于1，我希望此循环迭代一次。
Well, if the height equals 1, I want this loop to iterate one time.
如果高度等于2，我想迭代两次，等等，依此类推。
If the height equals 2, I wanted to iterate two times, 3, and so forth.
因此，我认为，使用这里的零索引技术，这也将起作用。
So I think, using my zero-indexing technique here, this will work too.
但是，如果您愿意，我当然可以将其更改为1
But if you prefer, I could certainly just change this to a 1
并更改此2。
and change this 2.
但是我要继续前进-
But I'm going to go ahead and--
实际上，不。
actually, no.
在这种情况下，我想保留它，零索引，
In this case, I want to leave it as such, zero index,
就像我们通常所做的一样。
just like we typically do.
好吧，让我继续编译一下，使Mario成为可能。
All right, let me go ahead and compile this, make Mario.
好的，糟糕，很有趣。
OK, oops, interesting.
通过此函数的所有路径都将自行调用。
All paths through this function will call itself.
因此，这里的clang有点聪明，因此，
So clang is being kind of smart here, whereby,
注意到在我的draw函数中，我正在调用我的draw函数。
it's noticing that in my draw function, I'm calling my draw function.
这是一个永不改变的过程。
And that's a process that never changes.
实际上，让我看看是否可以覆盖它。
In fact, let me see if I can override that.
让我手动使用clang并使用mario.c编译一个名为mario的程序。
Let me use clang manually and compile a program called mario using mario.c.
让我继续并链接到CS50。
And let me go ahead and link in cs50.
所以我从第二周开始使用旧式语法。
So I'm using our old school syntax from week two.
好的，编译完成。
OK, that compiled.
那为什么编译呢？
And why did that compile?
好吧，make还是一个使用编译器clang的程序。
Well, make is, again, a program that uses your compiler clang.
而且我们将make配置为更加用户友好和更多
And we've configured make to be a little more user-friendly and a little more
通过打开特殊功能来保护您
protective of you by turning on special features
我们在那里发现类似的问题。
where we detect problems like that.
通过现在直接使用clang，我将禁用那些特殊检查。
By using clang directly now, I'm disabling those special checks.
看看当我现在跑马里奥车到高度为4时会发生什么。
And watch what happens when I run Mario now for height of 4, for instance.
繁荣，它崩溃了。
Boom, it crashed.
它甚至什么也没打印。
It didn't even print anything.
它很快崩溃了。
It crashed pretty quickly.
同样，分段错误意味着您接触了不应该的内存。
And again, a segmentation fault means you touched memory that you shouldn't.
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
好吧，如果您认为此记忆代表主要静止物体，然后绘制，
Well, if you think of this memory as representing main still, but then draw,
画，画，画，画，画。
draw, draw, draw, draw, draw.
如果您的每一次抽奖电话都导致再次抽奖，
If every one of your calls to draw just cause draw again,
为什么会停止？
why would it ever stop?
似乎并不一定要在这里停止。
It wouldn't seem to stop here, necessarily.
因此，似乎我的递归版本中缺少一个关键细节。
So it seems that I'm missing a key detail in my recursive version.
你知道吗？
You know what?
如果没有要绘制的东西，如果高度等于0，让我继续前进，那么，
If there's nothing to draw, if height equals equals 0, let me go ahead, then,
并立即返回。
and just return immediately.
否则，我会继续绘制金字塔的一部分
Otherwise, I'll go ahead and draw part of the pyramid
然后添加新行。
and then add the new row.
因此，您需要这种所谓的基本情况，从字面上看
So you need this so-called base case, which you literally
选择等于一些简单值，例如height为0，height为1
choose to equal some simple value, like height of 0, height of 1,
任何硬编码的值，以便最终draw不会自行调用。
any hardcoded value, so that eventually, draw does not call itself.
因此，让我继续使用clang或make进行重新编译。
So let me go ahead and recompile this with clang or make.
让我重新运行它，高度为4，瞧。
Let me rerun it, height of 4, and voila.
它仍然像内部版本一样工作，
It's still working just like the interior version,
但现在正在使用递归。
but it's now using recursion.
所以这是一种设计问题。
So here's a sort of design question.
迭代比递归好吗？
Is iteration better than recursion?
这取决于。
It depends.
迭代将始终有效。
Iteration will always work.
使用迭代版本时，我永远不会溢出堆栈
When using the iterative version, I will never overflow the stack
然后撞上堆
and hit the heap.
为什么？
Why?
因为我不会一次又一次地调用函数。
Because I'm not calling functions again and again.
只有主次和一次平局调用。
There's only main and one invocation of draw.
但是对于递归版本，这是一种很酷，功能强大的方法
But with the recursive version, it's kind of a cool, powerful way
做事情。
to do things.
就像，哦，我可以给你画一个高度为h的金字塔。
Like, oh, I can draw you a pyramid of height h.
让我给你画一个高度为h减去1的金字塔
Let me just have you draw me a pyramid of height h minus 1,
然后我将添加一行。
and then I'll add a row.
这种聪明的循环论证确实非常优雅地工作。
It's kind of this clever, cyclical argument that does work very elegantly.
但是有危险。
But there's a danger.
实际上，即使这种基本情况确保了这种情况不会永远持续下去，
And in fact, even though this base case ensures that it doesn't go forever,
它可能会持续很长时间-也许让我们尝试10,000次调用。
it could go on so long-- maybe let's try 10,000 invocations.
这样就可以了。
So that worked OK.
有点慢。
It's a little slow.
我失去了对键盘的控制。
I'm losing control over my keyboard.
因此，Control C是您的朋友。
So Control C is your friend.
让我再试一次。
Let me try this once more.
让我继续进行约20亿次的尝试，看看是否可行。
Let me go ahead and do something like 2 billion and see if that works.
繁荣。
Boom.
因此，即使这样也不起作用。
So even that doesn't work.
因此，递归存在固有的危险，因此，
So there's this inherent danger with recursion, whereby,
即使它使我们上周有能力更有效地解决问题
even though it empowered us last week to solve a problem even more efficiently
通过合并排序，我们有点幸运，因为我们并没有试图疯狂
with merge sort, we kind of got lucky, in that we weren't trying to crazy big
东西放在Brian的书架上，因为如果您使用递归，这似乎
things on Brian's shelf, because it would seem if you use recursion
并一次又一次地给自己打电话，
and call yourself again and again and again and again,
即使是有限的多次，您最终也可能会碰到不应该使用的内存。
even finitely many times, you might eventually touch memory you shouldn't.
那这里的解决方案是什么？
And what's the solution here?
不幸的是，它不是那样做的。
Unfortunately, it's don't do that.
设计算法，以这种方式选择输入
Design your algorithms, choose your inputs in such a way
就是没有那种风险。
that there just isn't that risk.
我们将在几周后再次使用递归
And we'll use recursion again in a few weeks
是时候我们看一下更复杂的数据结构了。
time when we look at more sophisticated data structures.
但同样，总会有这种权衡。
But again, there's always this trade off.
只是因为您可以设计更多一点
Just because you can design something a little more
优雅地不一定意味着它总会为您工作。
elegantly doesn't necessarily mean that it's always going to work for you.
但是更常见的是，您是否还会遇到其他问题？
But more commonly, are you likely to run into other problems as well?
有一种叫做缓冲区溢出的东西。
There's something called a buffer overflow.
这肯定会在未来几周内完成。
And this you will surely trip over in the coming weeks.
缓冲区溢出是在分配数组时
A buffer overflow is when you allocate an array
并走得太远了。
and go too far past the end of it.
或者您使用malloc，但是您走得更远
Or you use malloc and you, nonetheless, go farther
比您分配的内存块的末尾要多。
than the end of the chunk of memory that you allocated.
缓冲区只是一块内存，可以这么说，您可以使用它
A buffer it's just a chunk of memory, so to speak, that you can use as you see
合身。
fit.
缓冲区溢出意味着超出该数组的范围。
Buffer overflow means going beyond the boundaries of that array.
您可能会使用-您现在正在使用视频。
You might use-- you're using, right now, video.
您可能知道视频中的短语缓冲，
You might know the phrase buffering from videos,
就像在Netflix上缓冲和烦扰您一样，
like sort of buffering and annoying you on Netflix,
因为那里有一个旋转的图标或其他。
because there's a spinning icon or whatnot.
好吧，这就是这个意思。
Well, that means exactly this.
在YouTube或Zoom或Netflix的上下文中，
A buffer, in the context of YouTube or Zoom or Netflix,
表示已检索的一些内存
means some chunk of memory that was retrieved
通过malloc或一些类似的工具来填充
via malloc or some similar tool that gets filled
包含您的视频的字节。
with bytes comprising your video.
这是有限的，这就是为什么您只能缓冲这么多秒
And it's finite, which is why you can only buffer so many seconds
或几分钟的视频，如果您不在线，那么最终，
or minutes of video before, eventually, if you're offline,
您的视频内容用完了，无法观看。
you run out of video content to watch.
然后出现愚蠢的图标，您可以
And the stupid icon comes up, and you can
不用再看了，因为缓冲区只是一块内存，是一个内存数组。
watch no more, because a buffer is just a chunk of memory, an array of memory.
如果Netflix，Google或其他公司不安全地实施其代码，
And if Netflix or Google or others were to implement their code unsafely,
他们也很可能会越过这个边界。
they might very well go too far past that boundary as well.
因此，在最后的几分钟中，让我们考虑一下
So with all this said, let's consider, in some of our final minutes
今天在这里，我们从这些培训轮中学到了什么，
here today, just what else we've been getting from these training wheels,
因为我们确实想把它们主要带给您。
because we do want to take them mostly off for you.
因此，CS50库不仅为您提供
So the CS50 library not only provides you
有了这种字符串类型的抽象，这又是
with this abstraction of a string type, which again,
没有为您提供任何新功能。
doesn't give you any new functionality.
C中的字符串存在，只是不存在该名称。
Strings in C exist, just not by that name.
它们被更恰当地称为“ char star”。
They're known more properly as char stars.
但是所有这些功能都在CS50库中
But all of these functions in the CS50 library
可以用CS50以外的其他实际C函数来实现，
can be implemented with other actual C functions that weren't from CS50,
即使用一种叫做scanf的文件。
namely using one called scanf.
但是您马上就会看到一些危险
But you're going to see, immediately, some of the dangers
使用scanf之类的东西，这是一种古老的功能。
of using something like scanf, which is an old school function.
它并非像CS50的库那样具有自卫性。
It was not designed to be self-defensive like CS50's library.
因此，很容易犯错误。
And so it's very easy to make mistakes.
例如，让我继续，并创建一个文件
Let me go ahead, for instance, and create a file
名为scanf.c只是为了演示此功能。
called scanf.c, just to demonstrate this function.
我将不使用CS50库，而仅使用标准io点h。
I'm not going to use the CS50 library, just standard io dot h.
而且我要给自己int主要空白。
And I'm going to give myself int main void.
我要继续给自己一个变量x。
And I'm going to go ahead and give myself a variable x.
我将继续打印引号unquote“ x：”
And I'm going to go ahead and print out quote unquote, "x:"
就像CS50的get int函数一样。
just like CS50's get int function does.
然后我将调用scanf。
And then I'm going to call scanf.
我将继续说，从用户的键盘扫描，一个整数，
And I'm going to go ahead and say, scan from the user's keyboard, an integer,
并将其存储在x的位置。
and store it in the location of x.
然后，我将继续进行打印，
Then, I'm going to go ahead and print out, again,
x，冒号和反斜杠百分比我反斜杠n。
x, and a colon and a backslash percent i backslash n.
我要打印x。
And I'm going to print x.
那么这是怎么回事？
So what's going on here?
在第5行中，我声明了一个名为x的变量，就像第一周一样。
In line 5, I'm declaring a variable called x, just like in week one.
第6行，仅在第一周就使用printf。
Line 6, just using printf, like in week one.
有趣的东西似乎在第7行中。
The interesting stuff seems to be in line 7.
Scanf是一个需要用户输入的函数，就像get int，get
Scanf is a function that takes input from the user, just like get int, get
字符串，获取浮点数，依此类推。
string, get float, and so forth.
但这只有在您必须了解指针的情况下才能实现，
But it does it only by you having to understand pointers,
因为回想一下我们的交换示例，如果您想拥有一个功能，
because recall from our swap example, if you want to have a function,
像我们对a和b所做的那样更改变量的内容
change the contents of a variable, as we did with a and b
x和y，您必须传入变量的地址，
and x and y, you have to pass in the address of the variable, whose
您要更改的值。
value you want to change.
您不能只传递x本身。
You can't just pass in x itself.
因此，如果我们在第一周不使用CS50库，
So if we didn't use the CS50 library in week one,
您可能只是为了从用户那里获取一个int而编写这样的代码。
you would have been writing code like this just to get an int from the user.
而且您将不得不了解指针。
And you would have had to understand pointers.
而且您将必须了解＆符和星号等。
And you would have to understand ampersand and stars and so forth.
当我们在头几周内关心所有事情时，这太过分了
It's just too much, when all we care about in the first weeks
是循环，变量，条件和基本原理。
are loops and variables and conditions and sort of the fundamentals.
但是在这里，我们现在可以调用scanf，告诉它
But here, we now have the ability to call scanf, tell it
从用户的键盘进行扫描，可以这么说，
to scan from the user's keyboard, so to speak,
整数或f百分比会给我们一个浮点数或其他类似的代码，
an integer, or percent f would give us a float or other such codes,
并传递x的地址，以便scanf可以转到该地址
and pass in the address of x so that scanf can go to that address
然后将用户键盘上的整数放在此处。
and put the integer from the user's keyboard there.
第8行就像第一周的东西。
Line 8 is like week one stuff.
我只是打印出价值。
I'm just printing out the value.
这很安全。
And this is pretty safe.
我将继续进行扫描。
I'm going to go ahead and make scanf.
编译就可以了。
It compiles OK.
我要继续运行它。
I'm going to go ahead and run it.
我要输入50。
I'm going to type in 50.
瞧，它会打印出50。
And voila, it prints out a 50.
但是有些奇怪，因为如果您也运行此程序
But there's some weirdness, because if you run this program too
并输入cat，那么x为0。
and type in cat, well then x is 0.
而且没有错误检查。
And there's no error checking.
所以立即，您应该瞥见那一个
So immediately, you should glimpse that one
CS50库的功能，召回，
of the features of the CS50 library, recall,
是我们会不断提示用户，如果他们不是
is that we keep prompting the user again and again if they're not
合作并给您一个情报。
cooperating and giving you an int.
这就是您从库中获得的功能。
So that's one feature you get from the library.
但是事实证明，获取字符串甚至更强大，
But it turns out that get string is even more powerful,
因为如果我现在去更改此程序，而不是获取整数，
because if I go and change this program now, not to get an int,
但是像字符串这样的幻想者
but something fancier like a string--
或等待，我们现在将其称为char star。
or wait, we're calling it char star now.
我将继续做类似的事情。
I'm going to go ahead and do something very similar.
我将提示用户输入字符串s。
I'm going to prompt the user for string s.
我将使用scanf。
And I'm going to use scanf.
我将使用percent，就像printf使用percent一样。
And I'm going to use percent s, just like printf uses percent s.
我要传递s。
And I'm going to pass in s.
现在，要明确一点，我不需要在这里使用＆号，
Now, to be clear, I don't need to do ampersand s here,
因为现在，我们都知道s从根本上是一个地址。
because now, we all know that s is fundamentally an address.
因此只需传递您已经拥有的地址即可。
So it suffices just to pass in the address that you already have.
现在，我将继续打印冒号，百分号的反斜杠n，
Now, I'm going to go ahead and print out s colon, percent s backslash n,
并打印出来。
and print out s.
但是当我编译它时，使scanf，它不喜欢它
But when I compile this, make scanf, it doesn't like it
当我在这里使用未编译的变量s时。
when I compile variable s's uninitialized when used here.
好吧，如果我真的想冒险，
All right, well if I really want to be sort of adventurous,
我可以覆盖make的保护。
I can override make's protections.
而且我可以自己自己使用scanf手动编译它-
And I can just compile this manually myself using scanf--
直接使用clang。
using clang directly.
可行，点斜杠scanf。
That worked, dot slash scanf.
让我继续输入例如“ HI！”。
Let me go ahead and type in, for instance, "HI!"
然后你会觉得很奇怪
and you see weirdness, nul.
好吧，幸运的是，然后再发出叮当声，
Well, fortunately, make, and in turn clang,
是帮助我们在那里自助的一种方式。
were kind of helping us help ourselves there.
指出您声明了s。
It was pointing out that you declared s.
因此，您被声明为一个指针的8个字节。
So you were declared 8 bytes for a pointer.
但是那里什么也没有。
But there's nothing there.
这是一个垃圾值。
It's a garbage value.
因此，无处可放。
And so there's nowhere to put this.
幸运的是，printf和scanf足够聪明
And thankfully, printf and scanf are being smart enough
不只是盲目地走到那儿，我，
by not just blindly going there and plopping H, I,
nul字符中的感叹号。
exclamation point in a nul character.
他们只是不理会它。
They're just leaving it alone.
这个括号只是一个printf功能，说，你搞砸了。
And this parenthetical nul is just a printf feature saying, you screwed up.
如果看到nul，说明您做错了什么。
If you see nul, you've done something wrong.
它只是大方而不会崩溃。
It's just being generous and not crashing on you.
如果我确实想获得用户的输入，则需要比这更聪明。
If I actually want to get user's input, I need to be smarter than this.
正如我们今天早些时候所做的那样，我需要为自己分配4个字节。
And I need to either allocate myself 4 bytes, as we've done earlier today.
或者我可以回到第二周，说些类似的话，给我4个字节。
Or I could go back to week two stuff and say something like, give me 4 bytes.
不过，这给了我4个字节的堆栈空间
This, though, gives me 4 bytes on the stack somewhere
可以这么说。
down here in main's frame, so to speak.
这些行称为框架。
These rows are called frames.
如果我改用malloc，它来自所谓的堆，
If I use malloc instead, it comes from the so-called heap,
没有画出来的，有点像在这里。
which not pictured, is sort of up here.
唯一的区别是，如果我使用的是malloc，则必须使用free。
And the only difference is that if I'm using malloc, I have to use free.
如果像第二周那样使用堆栈，则不必使用免费。
If I'm using the stack, as I did in week two, I don't have to use free.
它会自动为我管理。
It's automatically managed for me.
坦率地说，今天有很多新东西。
So frankly, there's so much new stuff today.
我喜欢坚持旧派的想法。
I like the idea of sticking with the old school arrays.
所以现在，尽管如此，如果我继续进行scanf的制作，现在它会使用make进行编译。
So now, though, if I go ahead and make scanf, now it compiles with make.
如果然后运行scanf并输入HI !，瞧，这似乎可行。
If I then run scanf and type in, HI!, voila, it seems to work.
但这是因为我很聪明，并期待HI，
But that's because I was smart and anticipated that H-I,
确定四个字符。
OK four characters.
我给了自己4个字节。
I gave myself 4 bytes.
但是，如果用户键入HI THERE，DAVID，您好吗？
But what if the user types in, HI THERE, DAVID, HOW ARE YOU?
显然，超过四个字节。
Clearly, more than four bytes.
我现在按Enter键，发生了一些奇怪的事情。
And I hit Enter now, something weird there happened.
剩下的就是丢失。
The rest is just lost.
这真的很烦人，非常令人沮丧
And this would really be annoying and very frustrating
如果您尝试在课程的第一周获得用户输入。
if you-- trying to get user input in the first week of the class.
获取字符串可以避免这种情况。
Get string avoids this for you.
为您获取字符串调用malloc。
Get string calls malloc for you.
它要求它像字符串一样占用大量内存
And it calls it for as big a chunk of memory as the string
人类输入。
the human types in.
长话短说，我们有点看着他们在打字
Long story short, we sort of watch what they're typing character
逐个字符地。
by character by character.
并且我们确保分配或重新分配
And we make sure to allocate or reallocate
足够的内存来适应人类键入的内容。
just enough memory to fit whatever it is the human has typed in.
因此，scanf本质上是一个类似于CS50库的函数
So scanf is, essentially, how a function like the CS50 library
在引擎盖下工作。
works underneath the hood.
但这是为您做的所有事情。
But it is doing all of this for you.
坦白说，一旦您拿走了这样的训练轮，
And as soon as you take away training wheels like that, or frankly,
像这样的库，实际上是一天结束了。
libraries like that, which it really is at the end of the day.
它不仅是一种教学工具。
It's not just a teaching tool.
这是一个有用的库。
It's a useful library.
您必须自己开始实施更多此类低级内容。
You have to start implementing more of this low-level stuff yourself.
因此，这是一个折衷方案。
So again, there is a trade off.
如果您不想使用CS50库之类的东西，那就很好。
If you don't want to use something like the CS50 library, that's fine.
现在，您有责任避免所有这些可能的错误情况。
Now, the onus is on you to avoid all of these possible error conditions.
好了，这么说，我们有一个最后的功能
All right, with that said, we have one final feature
为了激发您本周的问题，其中
to give you in order to motivate this week's problems, wherein
您实际上将探索，操纵和编写代码来更改文件。
you'll actually explore and manipulate and write code to change files.
为此，我们需要文件I / O的最后一个主题。文件I / O
And for that, we need one final topic of file I/O. File I/O
是一种术语，它描述了从文件中获取输入和输出。
is the term of art that describes taking input and output from files.
到目前为止，几乎我们编写的每个程序都只使用内存，就像这样
Pretty much every program we've written thus far just uses memory, like this
在这里，您可以将内容放入内存中。
here, whereby, you can put stuff in memory.
但是，一旦您的程序结束，便会蓬勃发展。
But as soon as your program ends, boom.
它消失了。
It's gone.
内存的内容不见了。
The contents of memory are gone.
文件，当然是您和我在计算世界中的位置
Files, of course, are where you and I in the computing world
保存我们的论文，文件和简历
save our essays and documents and resumes
并将所有这些永久存储在您的计算机上。
and all of that permanently on your computer.
当然，在C语言中，您有能力自己编写代码，
In C, you have the ability, certainly, to write code yourself that
长期保存文件。
saves files long term.
例如，让我继续在这里编写自己的程序，
So for instance, let me go ahead and write my own program here,
在文件中存储姓名和电话号码的电话簿程序。
a phonebook program that stores names and numbers in a file.
为了方便起见，我将继续介绍CS50库
I'm going to go ahead and include, just for convenience, the CS50 library
再次，因为我不想处理scanf。
again, because I don't want to deal with scanf.
我将继续将其保存为phonebook.c。
I'm going to go ahead and save this, incidentally, as phonebook.c.
我将继续前进，不仅包括CS50库，还包括标准io。
I'm going to go ahead and include, not just the CS50 library, but standard io.
而且，我将抢先一步，并包括string.h。
And preemptively, I'm going to go ahead and include string.h as well.
我将继续执行我的主要职能。
And I'm going to go ahead in my main function.
我将使用一些新功能，在这里我们将仅简要介绍这些功能。
And I'm going to use a few new functions that we'll see only briefly here.
但是在下一个问题集中，您将更详细地探讨这些问题。
But in the next problem set, will you explore these in more detail.
我要给自己一个指向文件的指针。
I'm going to give myself a pointer to a file.
奇怪的是，在所有大写字母中，FILE，
It turns out, weirdly, that in all caps, FILE,
这是C附带的代表文件的新数据类型。
this is a new data type that does come with C that represents a file.
所以我要继续给自己一个指向文件的指针，
So I'm going to go ahead and give myself a pointer to a file,
文件的地址。
the address of a file.
我将调用变量文件。
And I'm going to call the variable file.
我可以称它为x。
I could call it f I could call it x.
为了清楚起见，我将其称为小写文件。
I'm going to call it lowercase file, just to be clear.
我将使用一个称为f open的新函数，这意味着文件打开。
And I'm going to use a new function called f open, which means file open.
和文件打开有两个参数。
And file open takes two arguments.
它采用第一个参数，即您要打开的文件的名称。
It takes the first argument, which is the name of a file you want to open.
我将打开一个名为phonebook.csv的文件。
I'm going to open a file called phonebook.csv.
然后，我将继续打开它，特别是在附加模式下打开它。
And then I'm going to go ahead and open it, specifically, in append mode.
长话短说，您可以用不同的方式打开文件，
Long story short, you can open files in different ways,
读它们，就是看它们的内容，写它们，
to read them, that is just look at their contents, to write them,
就是要完全改变他们的内容，
which is to change their contents entirely,
或附加到它们的后面，即表示逐行添加到它们，
or to append to them, a, which means to add row by row to them,
以便继续向他们提供更多信息。
so to keep tacking on more information to them.
我要继续前进，为了安全起见，
I'm going to go ahead and, just to be safe,
我要说的是，如果file equals等于nul，
I'm going to say if file equals equals nul,
因为记得nul表示出了点问题，
because recall that nul signifies something went wrong,
让我们现在就回来。
let's just return now.
也许我输错了文件名。
Maybe I mistyped the name of the file.
也许它不存在。
Maybe it doesn't exist.
可能出了点问题。
Something went wrong, potentially.
我要说的是，如果file equals等于nul，
I'm going to check for that by saying, if file equals equals nul, just
现在退出该程序。
quit out of the program now.
但是在那之后，我将继续进行操作。
But after that, I'm going to go ahead and get a string.
但是我们现在可以将其称为char star，称为name。
But we can call that char star now, called name.
我要问用户一个名字。
And I'm going to ask the user for a name.
我们之前已经做到了。
And we've done this before.
我要去问他们一个电话号码。
I'm going to go ahead and ask them for a number, phone number.
我们之前已经做到了。
And we've done this before.
现在，唯一的区别是，我称字符串char star。
The only difference, now, is I'm calling string char star.
现在，这是最酷的部分。
And now, here's the cool part.
原来，如果我要保存此姓名和电话号码
It turns out, if I want to save this name and number
以CSV格式永久保存到该文件中，
to that file permanently in a CSV--
如果不熟悉，则在咨询界，分析界流行。
if unfamiliar, popular in the consulting world, the analytics world.
这只是一个电子表格，以逗号分隔的值
It's just a spreadsheet, a comma-separated value
您可以在Excel或数字或Google电子表格中打开的文件。
file that you can open in Excel or numbers or Google spreadsheet.
我要继续，而不是printf，而是fprintf到该文件，
I'm going to go ahead and, not printf, but fprintf to that file,
一个字符串，后跟一个逗号，然后是一个字符串，然后是一个新行，
a string followed by a comma, followed by a string, followed by a new line,
插入姓名和电话号码。
plugging in the name and the number.
然后在这里，我将关闭文件。
And then down here, I'm going to close the file.
所以这是新的。 fprintf不是printf，它将打印到您的屏幕上。
So this is new. fprintf is not printf, which prints to your screen.
fprintf打印到文件。
fprintf prints to a file.
因此，您必须再传递一个参数，第一个，
So you have to pass in one more argument, the first one, which
是指向您要将这些新字符串发送到的文件的指针。
is the pointer to the file that you want to send these new strings to.
然后，您仍然提供一个格式字符串，它说，嘿，fprintf，
Then you still provide a format string, which says, hey fprintf,
这是我要打印到文件中的数据。
this is the kind of data I want to print to the file.
然后插入变量，就像我们对printf所做的一样。
And then you plug in the variables, just like we've always done with printf.
最后，我们关闭文件。
And then lastly, we close the file.
简而言之，该程序似乎会提示人们输入姓名和电话号码。
So in short, this program would seem to prompt a human for a name and number.
然后继续写那些名字
And then it's going to go ahead and write those names
和文件编号。
and numbers to the file.
因此，让我继续制作电话簿。
So let me go ahead and make phonebook.
好的，到目前为止，没有问题，点斜线电话簿，David，949-468-2750。
OK, no mistake so far, dot slash phonebook, David, 949-468-2750.
好的，尽管似乎什么都没发生，但让我再次运行它。
OK, let me run it once more, even though nothing seems to have happened.
布赖恩，请问617-495-1000，输入。
Brian, how about 617-495-1000, Enter.
让我在这里检查我的文件浏览器。
Let me check my file browser here.
请注意，我们今天创建的所有文件，包括如果我放大的文件，
Notice, all of the files we've created today, including, if I zoom in,
不只是phonebook.c，还有phonebook.csv。
not just phonebook.c, but phonebook.csv.
如果我双击该按钮，请注意其中的内容。
And if I double click that, notice what's inside of this.
Voila，David的名字，Brian的名字以及我们每个电话号码。
Voila, David's name, Brian's name, and each of our numbers.
甚至比这更酷，让我继续并关闭它。
And even cooler than that, let me go ahead and close this.
让我继续并使用IDE下载此文件。
Let me go ahead and download this file using the IDE.
并将其放入我的“下载”文件夹中。
And that's going to put it into my Downloads folder.
让我继续并单击它。
Let me go ahead and click on it.
然后将打开Excel或Numbers或其他
And it's going to open Excel or Numbers or whatever
您恰好在Mac或PC上。
you happen to have on your Mac or PC.
我将继续进行。
I'm going to go ahead and just proceed.
瞧，这种格式看起来有点愚蠢。
And voila, looks a little stupid in this formatting here.
但是我打开了我自己生成的电子表格
But I've opened up a spreadsheet that I, myself, generated
使用fopen，fprintf和fclose。
using fopen, fprintf, and fclose.
因此，既然已经有了我们可以使用的指针，
So already, now that we have pointers at our disposal,
我们可以实际操作诸如文件之类的东西吗，这很酷。
can we actually manipulate things like files, which is quite cool.
但是我们本周要这样做，而不是
But we're going to do that this week, not
带有文本，但带有实际特定类型的文件。
with text, but with actual specific types of files.
的确，在这里回想一下这种想法。
And indeed, recall this kind of thinking here.
如果您看一眼，这可能很神秘。
If you glance at this, it's probably pretty cryptic.
它看起来像机器代码，但事实并非如此。
It looks like machine code, but it's not.
这也许是最简单的表示
This is, perhaps, the simplest representation
文件里面的笑脸的轮廓。
of a smiley face inside of a file.
如果您有位图文件，位图，位网格，这些位，
If you have a bitmap file, a map of bits, a grid of bits, those bits,
很简单，实际上可以是0和1。
quite simply, could literally be 0's and 1's.
如果您将黑色分配为0，将白色分配为1，
And if you assign the color black to 0 and the color white to 1,
您实际上可以将0和1的相同网格表示为
you could actually think of this same grid of 0's and 1's as representing,
的确，一张笑脸。
indeed, a smiley face.
换句话说，这是一些像素。
In other words, here are some pixels.
我们谈到了零周的像素。
We talked about pixels in week zero.
像素只是组成计算机上图形文件的点。
Pixels are just the dots that compose a graphic file on your computer.
像素无处不在。
And pixels are everywhere.
现在，我们所有人都可以通过Zoom或YouTube等实时进行调整，
All of us, now, tuning in live via Zoom or YouTube or the like,
我们正在观看像素流，这些像素流由多个图像和多个
we're watching streams of pixels, which compose multiple images and multiple
图像组成的视频似乎正在以20或30左右的速度移动
images compose video that appears to be moving at, like, 20 something or 30
每秒帧数，每秒图像数。
frames per second, images per second.
当然，现在这些图像的保真度很高。
Now, of course, there's only so much fidelity in these kinds of images.
这在电视和电影中非常普遍，
And it's quite common in the case on TV and in movies,
如果有一些坏人通过监视被发现
if there's some bad guy that's been picked up with some surveillance
镜头或类似内容，总是涉及法律与秩序等方面的人
footage or the like, invariably, the folks on Law &amp; Order and the like
可以改善视频并放大并查看
can just kind of enhance the video and zoom in and see
恰恰是人眼中的一闪一闪，显示出谁犯了罪。
exactly the glint in the person's eye that reveals who committed some crime.
好吧，那真是胡说八道。
Well, that's all kind of nonsense.
它源自我们在第零周引入的一些原语。
And it derives from some of the primitives we introduced in week zero.
实际上，只是为了取笑，让我继续
In fact, just to poke fun at this, let me go ahead
并在美国这里播放此电视节目的几秒钟
and play on a few seconds of this TV show here in the US
称为CSI，只是让您了解这种逻辑有多么普遍
called CSI, just to give you a sense of just how commonplace this kind of logic
是。
is.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
- 我们知道。
- We know.
-在9:15，雷·桑托亚（Ray Santoya）在自动取款机上。
- That at 9:15, Ray Santoya was at the ATM.
-问题是，他在9:16做什么？
- So the question is, what was he doing at 9:16?
-向某物射击9毫米。
- Shooting the 9 millimeter at something.
也许他看到了狙击手。
Maybe he saw the sniper.
-或者正在和他一起工作。
- Or was working with him.
-等一下，回去。
- Wait, go back one.
- 你看到了什么？
- What do you see?
[哭声]
[CLICKING]
-全屏显示他的脸。
- Bring his face up, full screen.
-他的眼镜。
- His glasses.
-有一个反思。
- There's a reflection.
[打字]
[TYPING]
-那是Neuvitas棒球队。
- That's Neuvitas baseball team.
那是他们的标志。
That's their logo.
-他在跟穿那件夹克的人说话。
- And he's talking to whoever's wearing that jacket.
-我们可能有证人。
- We may have a witness.
-两次射击。
- To both shootings.
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很遗憾，今天宁愿毁掉许多电视和电影
DAVID MALAN: So unfortunately, today will rather ruin a lot of TV and movie
对你来说，因为你不能无限放大
for you, because you can't just zoom in infinitely
并查看更多信息（如果该信息不存在）。
and see more information if that information is not there.
在一天结束时，只有有限的位数。
At the end of the day, there's only a finite number of bits.
举例来说，这是布莱恩（Brian）的照片。
And case in point, here's a photograph of Brian.
而且您可能会看到，哦，他的眼中闪着光芒。
And you might see that, oh, there's a glint in his eye.
让我们看看他的眼睛在那反映了什么。
Let's see what was being reflected in his eye there.
因此，如果我们在此处放大Brian的这张图片，
And so if we Zoom in on this image here of Brian,
也许我们再放大一点，那就是实际的全部。
and maybe we zoom in a little further, that's all that's actually there.
您不仅可以点击增强按钮来查看更多信息，
You can't just click the enhance button and see more,
因为归根结底，这些只是像素。
because at the end of the day, these are just pixels.
每周为零的像素只有0和1，而且有限地很多。
And pixels, per week zero, are just 0's and 1's, and finitely, many so.
因此，所见即所得。
So what you see is what you get.
现在，话虽如此-实际上，我们也可以在这里对此取笑。
Now, with that said-- and actually, we can poke fun of this, too, here.
我来播放Futurama的另一个短片
Let me just play one other short clip from Futurama,
哪种锤子也可以说明这一点，但是更有趣。
which kind of hammers home this point as well, but more playfully so.
[视频回放]
[VIDEO PLAYBACK]
-放大死亡速度。
- Magnify that death speed.
为什么仍然模糊？
Why is it still blurry?
-这就是我们的所有决议。
- That's all the resolution we have.
加大它并不能使它更清晰。
Making it bigger doesn't make it clearer.
-确实在CSI：迈阿密。
- It does on CSI: Miami.
-[SIGH]
- [SIGH]
[结束播放]
[END PLAYBACK]
戴维·马兰（DAVID MALAN）：因此，在这里，我们有两个剪辑互相交谈。
DAVID MALAN: So there, we have two clips talking, rather, to one another.
但我必须为2020年更新内容。
But I have to update things for 2020.
这些天，你真的无法上网，或者杂志，
You can't really pick up the internet these days or magazine these days,
如果您愿意的话，也不会提及
if you even would, that doesn't somehow mention
机器学习和人工智能
machine learning and artificial intelligence
和花哨的算法，通过它们您可以执行操作
and fancy algorithms via which you can do things
以前不太可能。
that previously weren't quite possible.
这实际上是一种情况。
And that's actually kinda sorta the case.
您可能记得从零周开始，我们发现了这种美丽的水彩画
You might recall from week zero, that we found this beautiful watercolor
哈佛档案馆里的这幅画只有大约11英寸高。
painting in the Harvard archives that's only about 11 inches tall total.
但是不知何故，它在我身后高13英尺。
And yet somehow, it's 13 feet tall here behind me.
现在，通常，如果您只是要增强这幅水彩画，
Now, normally, if you were to just enhance this watercolor painting,
它很快就会开始看起来很愚蠢
it would start to look pretty stupid pretty quickly
像素很多，即使您
with lots and lots of pixelation, even if you
像档案馆一样，使用了非常精美的相机，
used a very fancy camera, as the archives do,
捕获原始图像。
to capture the original image.
但是我们想把它炸到13英尺高
But we wanted to blow it up to 13 feet tall
这样一来，它就可以始终以高品质站在我们身后。
so that it would stand at high quality behind us this whole time.
从某种意义上讲，我们实际上确实使用过增强功能。
And there, we actually did use enhance, in some sense.
因此，使用长话短说，比上周更好的算法，
So using, long story short, fancier algorithms than those last week,
您可以使用人工智能，机器学习，
you can use artificial intelligence, machine learning,
实际分析数据并找到没有的模式-
to actually analyze data and find patterns where there weren't--
不一定是人眼可见的。
that aren't necessarily visible to the human eye.
因此，例如，如果我们将原始图像放在这里并开始放大，
So for instance, if we take the original here and start to zoom in,
在这个分辨率上看起来还不错。
it looks pretty good at this resolution.
但这很顺利。
But it's pretty smooth.
您并没有真正看到这是在实际画布上绘制的事实。
You don't really see the fact that this was paint on an actual canvas.
因此，这只是放大Photoshop。
So this was just zooming in on Photoshop.
但是当您实际运行这样的图像时
But when you actually run an image like this
通过基于花式机器学习的软件，人工智能，
through fancy machine learning-based software, artificial intelligence,
您可以开始对其进行改进，然后实际看到，
you can begin to improve it and actually see,
不只是一栋建筑物顶部的窗户，
not just this window from the top of one of the buildings, which
在Photoshop中非常漂亮
is pretty glossed over here in Photoshop,
您可以开始查看更多详细信息。
you can start to see more detail.
因此，这实际上是以前的事情，只是放大Photoshop。
So this is literally the before, just zooming in Photoshop.
这是在实际应用花哨的人工智能算法之后
This is after, actually applying fancy artificial intelligence algorithms
通知，等一下，那里有一点变色。
that notice, wait a minute, there's a little discoloration there.
等一下，那里有些变色。
Wait, there's a little discoloration there.
如今，增强变得越来越重要。
And nowadays, enhance is increasingly becoming a thing.
它仍在推断。
It's still inferring.
并不是要复现必须存在的信息。
It's not resurrecting information that was necessarily there.
确实是算法上的最佳猜测
It's doing its best guess, really, algorithmically,
重建图像实际是什么。
to reconstruct what the image actually was.
如果我们进一步放大，也许可以
And if we zoom in further, you can, perhaps,
看到如果只是使用Photoshop，这真的开始变得模糊了
see that this is really starting to get blurry if you just use Photoshop
并继续放大。
and keep zooming in.
但是，如果您通过足够好的算法来运行它
But if you run it through fancy enough algorithms
并开始注意到轻微的变色
and start to notice slight discolorations that
不是人眼所能看到的，我们可以进一步增强它。
aren't super visible to the human eye, we can enhance that even further.
而且您不能无限地这样做。
And you can't do it infinitely so.
从某种意义上说，我们正在创造信息
And in some sense, we're creating information
那里不一定有该信息。
where there isn't necessarily that information there.
因此，这类事情是否在法庭上成立是另一个问题。
So whether or not these kinds of things hold up in court is another question.
但是，这样可以提高图像的保真度。
But it can improve the fidelity of images like this.
确实，它使我们能够从11英寸放大到13英尺。
And indeed, it allowed us to zoom in from 11 inches to 13 feet instead.
因此，当涉及到图像处理时，我们最终
So when it comes to manipulating images, ultimately, we
确实具有一些编程功能，包括此文件指针，
do have some programmatic capabilities, including this file pointer,
就像我们刚刚看到的一样，还有其他一些功能。
like we just saw, and also, a few other functions as well.
我们这里的最终示例将奠定基础
And our final examples, here, will lay the foundation
对于下周您将要做的事情，
for what you'll do this coming week, which
以新发现的方式操作您自己的图形文件
is manipulate your very own graphical files with a newfound understanding
指针和地址，现在是文件以及输入和输出。
of pointers and addresses and now files and input and output.
例如，我要继续在这里打开一个程序-
For instance, I'm going to go ahead and open up a program here called--
给我一秒钟。
give me just one second.
我将在这里打开一个名为jpeg.c的程序。
I'm going to open up a program here called jpeg.c.
我事先写的这个程序jpeg.c，
And this program, jpeg.c, which I wrote in advance,
该课程的网站上的内容，请执行以下操作。
which is on the course's website, does the following.
它首先声明一个称为字节的类型。
It first declares a type called byte.
事实证明，在C语言中，关于字节是什么没有通用定义。
It turns out, in C, there's no common definition of what a byte is.
正如我们所知，咬一口就好了。
A bite, as we know it, is a bit.
事实证明，最简单的创建方法
And it turns out, the simplest way to create
字节是定义我们自己的字节，就像我们定义了字符串一样，
a byte is to define our own, just like we've defined a string,
就像我们也定义了其他类型一样，例如学生，
just like we've defined other types too, like a student, in order--
一个人，而是为了给我们一个字节。
a person, rather, in order to give us a byte.
所以第一行代码只是声明了一个数据类型
So this first line of code just declares a data type
称为字节，使用另一种更神秘的数据类型，称为u int下划线t。
called byte, using another, more arcane data type called u int a underscore t.
但是，有关问题的更多信息。
But more on that in the problem set.
这样做确实发明了一种叫做字节的东西。
That this just did invent something called byte.
注意，在这个程序中，我正在重提这个想法
Notice, in this program, I'm resurrecting the idea
从命令行参数的第二周开始，我们可以从用户那里获取输入。
from week two of command line arguments, where we can take input from the user.
注意，我正在检查用户是否输入了两个参数。
Notice that I'm checking if the user typed in two arguments.
如果没有，我将立即返回一个以表示错误。
And if not, I'm returning one immediately to signify error.
在第17行中，我正在使用新技术。
In line 17, I'm using my new technique.
我正在使用文件名打开文件
I'm opening a file using the name of the file
该人员在命令行中键入的内容。
that the human typed at the command line.
这次，我将其打开以使用引号unquote而不是a来阅读它。
And this time, I'm opening it to read it with quote unquote, r instead of a.
但是如果没有文件，
But if there's not a file--
因此，如果是爆炸文件（即感叹号文件），
so if bang file, that is, if exclamation point file,
或者，如果file equals等于NULL，则它们表示同一件事。
or if file equals equals NULL, those mean the same thing.
我可以继续并返回一个，表示错误。
I can go ahead and return one, signifying an error.
在这里，我正在做一些聪明的事情。
Down here, I'm doing something a little clever.
事实证明，很有可能，
It turns out that with very high probability,
您可以通过仅查看前三个文件来确定任何文件是否为jpeg。
you can determine if any file is a jpeg by looking only at its first three
个字节。
bytes.
许多文件格式都有所谓的幻数
A lot of file formats have what are called magic numbers
在文件的开头。
at the beginning of their files.
这些是行业标准编号，其中1或2或3或更多，
And these are industry standard numbers, 1 or 2 or 3 or more of them,
通常只希望它位于文件的开头，
that is just commonly expected to be at the beginning of a file,
以便程序可以快速检查，这是jpeg吗？
so that a program can quickly check, is this a jpeg?
这是gif吗？
Is this a gif?
这是Word文档吗？
Is this a Word document?
这是Excel文件吗？
Is this an Excel file?
他们往往在开始时就有这些数字。
They tend to have these numbers at the beginning of them.
jpeg具有一系列我们将要看到的字节。
And jpegs have a sequence of bytes that we're about to see.
您将在下一个问题集中看到此处的这行代码24，
This line of code 24 here, as you'll see in the next problem set,
您可能会如何为自己提供字节缓冲区，特别是
is how you might give yourself a buffer of bytes, specifically
三个字节的数组。
an array of three bytes.
您将在下周看到的下一行代码称为fread。
This next line of code, as you'll see this coming week, is called fread.
顾名思义，fread从文件读取。
fread, as the name suggests, reads from a file.
也就是说，它从文件中获取字节。
That is, it grabs bytes from a file.
使用起来有点花哨，但您会更舒适
And it's a little fancy to use, but you'll get more comfortable
随着时间的流逝。
with this over time.
它将读取该缓冲区的第一个参数，该数据类型的大小，
It reads into this buffer, its first argument, the size of this data type,
一个字节的大小。
the size of a byte.
并且它从该文件中读取许多这样的数据类型。
And it reads in this many of those data types from this file.
同样，它是用于参数的，与我们所看到的相比，这是很多的。
So again, it's for arguments, which is kind of a lot from what we've seen.
但是它从这个文件中读取了三个字节到这个数组中，
But it reads from this file, three bytes into this array,
aka缓冲区，称为字节。
a.k.a. buffer, called bytes.
因此，这就是您编写不会将数据存储在文件中的代码的方式，
So this is just how you write code that doesn't put data in a file,
但请从中阅读。
but read it from it.
然后在这里，注意我们的十六进制。
And then here, notice our hexadecimal.
因此，我们走了一个完整的圈子。
So we've come full circle.
如果字节括号0等于0xff，则字节等于
If bytes bracket 0 equals equals 0xff and bytes
括号1等于0xd8，字节括号2等于0xff，
bracket 1 equals 0xd8 and bytes bracket 2 equals 0xff,
对您来说，这绝对是个秘密。
this definitely looks cryptic to you.
但这仅仅是因为我在手册中查找了jpeg，
But that's just because I looked up in the manual for jpegs,
事实证明，几乎所有jpeg都可以，
and it turns out that almost any jpeg, rather,
必须以0xff，0xd8、0xff开头。
must start with 0xff, 0xd8, 0xff.
这些是Mac，PC上jpeg的前三个字节，
Those are the first three bytes of any jpeg on your Mac, your PC,
在网上。
on the internet.
总是有这三个字节。
There are always those three bytes.
事实证明，第四个字节进一步决定是否
It turns out, the fourth byte further decides whether or not
文件实际上是jpeg。
a file is actually a jpeg.
但是，这样做的算法比较简单，因此我保持了简单性。
But the algorithm for that's a little fancier, so I kept it simple.
如果文件的前三个字节是这些字节，则可能是jpeg。
If the first three bytes of a file are those, maybe you have a jpeg.
但是如果您没有这三个字节，
But if you don't have exactly those three bytes,
您绝对没有jpeg。
you definitely don't have a jpeg.
因此，我在这里可以做的如下。
And so what I can do, here, is as follows.
在今天的代码中-让我继续获取另外两个文件
In today's code-- let me go ahead and grab two other files
我带来的
that I brought with me.
碰巧又是一张照片。
And one happens to be a photograph again.
给我一秒钟。
Give me one second.
我带来了一些文件，其中一个叫做brian.jpeg，
I brought with me a few files, one of which is called brian.jpeg,
这是布莱恩的照片。
which is the same photo of Brian.
然后我有一个gif，当然不是
And then I have a gif, which of course, is not
jpeg，就是这只猫在这里打字。
a jpeg, that is this cat typing here.
而我现在所拥有的实际上是我面前的东西
And what I, effectively, have in front of me now
是一个程序，如果我制作jpeg，因为这个文件是jpeg.c，
is a program that if I do make jpeg, because this file is jpeg.c,
然后运行点斜线jpeg，我可以输入cat.gif之类的内容
and I run dot slash jpeg, I can type in something like cat.gif
在命令行中将其作为参数，按Enter键，我应该看不到。
at the command line as an argument, hit Enter, and I should see no.
相比之下，如果我在命令行中将Brian的jpeg作为参数传递，
By contrast, if I pass in Brian's jpeg at the command line as an argument,
我知道了。
I see maybe.
再说一次，也许只是因为算法
And again, maybe only because the algorithm
实际判断某物是否为jpeg
for actually adjudicating whether something is a jpeg
比这复杂一点。
is a little more complicated than that.
但是确实，我现在可以访问各个字节，因此也可以访问像素，
But indeed, I can now access the individual bytes, and therefore pixels,
似乎是图像文件。
it would seem, of an image file.
实际上，我们甚至可以做到这一点。
And in fact, we can even do this.
让我继续向您展示最后一个程序
Let me go ahead and show you one last program
我们特意事先写的，只是为了让您了解一下
that we wrote deliberately in advance, just to give you a taste of what's
伴随着下一个问题集。
coming with the next problem set.
该程序是您可能已经重新实现的程序
This program is a reimplementation of the program you've probably
使用了一次或多次称为CP。
used one or more times called CP.
回想一下CP是IDE和Linux中的一个程序，
Recall that CP is a program in the IDE and in Linux,
更一般而言，它允许您复制文件。
more generally, that allows you to copy a file.
您执行CP，空格，文件名，空格，新文件名。
You do CP, space, the filename, space, the new filename.
这是如何运作的？
How does this work?
现在，我拥有了用于自己复制文件的所有构建块。
I now have all of the building blocks with which to copy files myself.
再说一次，我在这里定义一个字节。
So again, I'm defining a byte up here.
我在这里将main定义为接受命令行参数。
I'm defining main as taking command line arguments here.
并注意一项更改。
And notice one change.
我没有使用CS50库。
I'm not using the CS50 library.
因此，即使以前在第二周中使用的字符串现在也变成了char star。
So even what was previously string in week two is now char star.
即使在这里使用argv，我也要确保人类类型
Even here for argv, I'm making sure that the human types
用三个词，程序的名称，源文件和目标
in three words, the program's name and the source file and the destination
文件。
file.
我再次使用fopen。
I'm using fopen again.
我在这里从argv1打开源文件。
I'm opening the source file here from argv1.
我确定它不是nul。
I'm making sure it's not nul.
然后我退出了。
And then I'm quitting if it is.
我是-这是新东西，也在这里打开目标文件
I'm then-- here's something new, opening the destination file here, also
与fopen。
with fopen.
但是我使用的是引号unquote，“ w”。
But I'm using quote unquote, "w."
我要用r打开一个文件，用w打开一个文件，因为我想从其中一个读取
I'm opening one file with r, one file for w, because I want to read from one
并写给其他人。
and write to the other.
然后在这里，这个循环是一个聪明的方法
And then down here, this loop is a clever way
将一个文件复制到另一个文件。
of copying one file to another.
我给自己一个字节的缓冲区，所以只是一个临时变量，
I'm giving myself a buffer of one byte, so just a temporary variable, just
像布莱恩的临时工或空杯子。
like Brian's temp or empty glass.
我正在使用此功能，fread。
And I'm using this function, fread.
我正在通过其地址，一个字节的大小读入该缓冲区，
I'm reading into that buffer via its address, the size of a byte,
特别是源文件中的一个字节。
specifically one byte from the source file.
然后，在同一个循环中，我从那个缓冲区写一个字节的大小，
And then, in that same loop, I'm writing from that buffer, the size of a byte,
到目的地的一个字节。
specifically one byte, to the destination.
所以从字面上看，您可能已经看到我使用过的CP程序
So literally, the CP program you might have seen me use
或者您自己曾经用来复制文件，实际上就是这样做。
or you yourself have used to copy files, is literally doing this.
它正在打开一个文件，遍历其所有字节，
It's opening one file, iterating over all of its bytes,
并将它们从源复制到目标。
and copying them from source to destination.
最后，它正在关闭文件。
And then lastly, it's closing the file.
最后两个例子刻意快速，
And these last two examples deliberately fast,
因为这整整一周将用于深入研究文件I / O和映像
because this whole week will be spent diving into file I/O and images
其。
thereof.
但是我们要做的就是使用这些fread，fopen，fwrite和f close，
But all that we've done is use these fread, fopen, and fwrite and f close,
操纵那些文件。
to manipulate those very files.
例如，如果现在执行此操作，请让我执行cp。
So for instance, if I now do this, let me do make cp.
OK，似乎可以编译了，点斜线cp，brian.jpeg。
OK, seems to compile, dot slash cp, brian.jpeg.
brian2.jpeg怎么样？
How about brian2.jpeg?
然后按Enter。
And hit Enter.
似乎什么都没发生。
Nothing seems to happen.
但是如果我进入这里并双击brian2，
But if I go in here and double click on brian2,
我们看到我们有了Brian实际文件的第二份副本。
we see that we have a second copy of Brian's actual file.
因此，在下周，您将尝试使用多种文件格式的图像。
So this coming week, you'll experiment with multiple file formats for images.
首先是jpegs。
The first is jpegs.
我们将为您提供所谓的取证图像
And we will give you a so-called forensic image
数码存储卡中的一大堆照片。
of a whole bunch of photographs from a digital memory card.
实际上，在执法部门，这几天确实很常见，
In fact, it's very common these days, certainly in law enforcement,
取取硬盘驱动器，媒体棒的取证副本，
to take forensic copies of hard drives, of media sticks,
手机和其他设备，然后对其进行分析
of phones and other devices, and then analyze them
用于丢失，损坏或删除的数据。
for data that's been lost or corrupted or deleted.
我们将严格执行此操作，从而您将编写一个可以恢复的程序
We'll do exactly that, whereby, you'll write a program that recovers
从数码存储卡中意外删除的jpeg。
jpegs that have been accidentally deleted from a digital memory card.
我们会给您该存储卡的所有副本
And we'll give you all copies of that memory card
通过制作取证图像，即复制所有0和1
by making a forensic image of it, that is copying all of the 0's and 1's
从相机中并将其以文件形式提供给您
from a camera and giving them to you in a file
您可以读取然后从中写入。
that you can fread and then fwrite from.
我们还将向您介绍位图文件，
We'll also introduce you to bitmap files,
BMP，由Windows操作系统普及
BMP's, popularized by the Windows operating
墙纸之类的系统。
system for wallpaper's and the like.
但是我们将使用它们来实现使用指针和文件I / O的功能，
But we'll use them to implement using pointers and using file I/O,
您自己的类似Instagram的过滤器。
your very own Instagram-like filter.
因此，我们将在此处拍摄Weeks行人天桥的这张照片
So we'll take this picture, here, of the Weeks footbridge
哈佛大学在马萨诸塞州剑桥市。
here in Cambridge, Massachusetts by Harvard.
我们将为您实现许多过滤器，
And we'll have you implement a number of filters,
以这个原始图像为例，
taking this original image, for instance,
然后去饱和，使其变成黑色和白色，
and desaturating it, making it black and white,
通过遍历从上到下，从左到右的所有像素，
by iterating over all of the pixels top to bottom, left to right,
并识别出任何颜色，例如红色，绿色或蓝色或介于两者之间的任何颜色，
and recognizing any colors, like red or green or blue or anything in between,
然后将它们更改为灰色阴影，进行棕褐色过滤，
and changing them to some shade of gray, doing a sepia filter,
使事物看起来像是老派，就像这张照片一样
making things look old school, like this photo was taken
许多年前，通过类似地应用启发式方法来改变所有物体的颜色
many years ago, by similarly applying a heuristic that alters the colors of all
图片中的像素数。
of the pixels in this picture.
我们将其翻转，因此您必须将这个像素放在此处
We'll have you flip it around so you have to put this pixel over here
还有那个像素
and this pixel over there.
而且您会确切地了解文件的实现方式
And you'll appreciate exactly how files are implemented
在您自己的硬盘驱动器和手机中。
within your own hard drive and phone.
而且您甚至将实现一个模糊过滤器，这绝非偶然，
And you'll even implement, for instance, a blur filter, which no accident,
使得查看这里发生的事情变得更加困难，
makes it harder to see what's going on here,
因为您现在开始将附近的像素平均在一起
because you're starting to, now, average together pixels that are nearby
互相故意把东西弄光
each other to kind of gloss things over and deliberately
使得在这里很难看到。
make it harder to see here.
因此，即使您选择，我们也将拥有
And so we'll even, if you so choose, have
您实施边缘检测，如果感觉更舒适，
you implement edge detection, if feeling more comfortable,
在这些图片中找到所有物理对象的边缘的地方，
where you find the edges of all of the physical objects in these pictures,
为了在代码中实际检测到它们并像这样创建视觉艺术。
in order to actually detect them in code and create visual art like this.
现在，很多。
Now, this was a lot.
而且我知道通常会考虑使用指针
And I know pointers are generally considered
成为C更具挑战性的功能之一，
to be among the more challenging features of C,
当然，一般来说，编程也是如此。
and certainly, programming in general.
因此，如果您感觉已经有很多事情了，那就是。
So if you're feeling like it's been quite a bit, it was.
但是你现在确实有能力，无论是今天
But you do now have the ability, either today
或在不久的将来，甚至可以理解这样的XKCD漫画
or in the very near term, to understand even XKCD comics like this that most
那里的任何计算机科学家都已经看到过。
any computer scientist out there has seen.
因此，今天我们对您的最终期待是在这里开玩笑。
So our final look for you, today, is on this joke here.
即使我不一定能从远方听到你的声音，
And even though I can't necessarily hear you from afar,
我只是假设，在今天的最后时刻，
I'll just assume, in our final moments today,
每个人都大笑起来。
that everyone is breaking out into a very geeky laughter.
我至少看到一些微笑，这令人放心。
And I see some smiles, at least, which is reassuring.
这就是CS50。
This was, then, CS50.
下次见。
We'll see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]